okay
hello
and welcome back to our playthrough of disco elysium
we just finished kind of like the first little chunk of the game
kind of starting our character
and yeah just figuring out who he is
in this wild disgusting world
and how wild and disgusting are we going to be to
kind of meet the world where it's at
so I've sort of decided that the character profile
we're going with is like
ex or failed therapist turned dirty cop
kind of the idea like
I tried to be a therapist
but I found it was too easy to manipulate people
or the more I learned about people
the more I could not help the urge to exploit that stuff
so I became a cop instead
where I can hide behind a moral or duty justification
for getting information from people
and I can sort of code that as
this is a good thing for me and them
I'm actually protecting them by figuring out their dark secrets
so that's kind of where we're at
let's continue
keep working on this crime here
literally just came back at the perfect time hell yeah
let's fucking go
okay let's check out the crime scene a little bit more here
get some cash lying around
never gonna let that go to waste
some more magnesium
I'm thinking we're gonna need to stock up on magnesium
this winch mechanism has been oxidating for some years
the kids ladder is climbable
okay not too much interesting going on around here
let's check out the body
...with bulging white eyes
the face around them does not look human
it's swollen and ready to burst
his lips are fish like
and his tongue like a bull gag in his mouth
pretty gruesome
you seem to be holding your breath
a cargo belt twists his neck at an unnatural angle
the body below appears stiff
it's letting out an ungodly rot
the smell seeps in even through your clenched nostrils
legendary let go of your nose without throwing up
that 17 percent
has not steered me wrong yet
oh it looks like my camera is frozen okay
so all of this has just been cut out of the recording
but my other camera is having some issues
so I've gone back to the old camera
it is what it is
if there's a noticeable drop an image quality that's why
let's continue
I'm gonna go for the
I'm gonna go for the low percentage roll
I've gotten pretty lucky with it so far
and see what happens
as you breathe in the odour comes over you
it's a spell of the mind telling you to run
and your stomach to wring itself empty
with your hands at your sides and your eyes squinting you stand in it
my dude is
is the luckiest motherfucker
I swear turn off the cheats there are no cheats I swear
you guys saw me boot this up
as you breathe in the odour comes in over you
it's a spell of the mind telling you to run
all I really achieved was that I didn't throw up
it's highly skilled individual
let's get closer since we can withstand it
the man before you is naked
but for a pair of underpants and enameled boots
his skin is greenish
marbled with decaying veins and blotched by lividity
a fading web of tattoos covers his chest and shoulders
the cargo belt used to fasten him to the branch above
appears industrial in strength
I'm sitting in front of my window which has these blinds
and I keep them closed but
the cats like to hit them and so I get sun in my eyes
all right
let's get a look at that belt
the hangman's knot is pulled tight
by the weight of the corpse below
yellow hard edged polyester cuts into his neck
above a sliding buckle ties the belt to the branch
oh my there's something on the belt
a familiar word that speaks to the thirst within you
yeah no black Marvel what you're gonna see is exactly that
like that's the kind of luck I tend to have
where the really like easy shit
all the stuff I spec my builds out for
I fail every time
VERMILLON
in yellow letters along the length of the twisting cargo belt
only a deep longing for Vermillion golden spirits
lets you decipher the fading logo of the local brewery
I knew it it's the fucking bartender
no you should not get a drink
you should perform an initial inspection of the victim's corpse
we are on the rope part
industrial strength the kind used for tying cargo to lorries
hey pockeysucker thanks
so much for the sub my friend
for five months appreciate you always
good to see you around
enjoy that （？） emote
like in a circus
when the circus leaves town
and they tie a black spotted giraffe to the wall of a carry-pen
let's go with that
no more like in harbor like the one just east of here
I get to sense they used whatever was on hand
without paying much attention to not incriminating themselves
I'm losing Kim's respects by every time I open my mouth
that doesn't necessarily mean that dock workers did it though
my brain's ability to connect cosmic coincidences
that's like the inland empire one
is starting to steer me wrong a little bit
yeah sensitive archetype
the brief suggested as much
politically motivated by the ongoing strike
did you not get a briefing
of course I got a briefing Kim
I just probably didn't read it or forgot that I read it
my past has got undergone total annihilation nothing remains
my mother the love of my life certainly not a briefing
（选项：没有 他们可能忘记告诉我了）
let's blame it on someone else
then you should ask me the first moment we get
why not blame the dock workers
I guess that's a fair argument
you should ask me the first moment I get okay
（选项：他们是怎么把他弄上去的？）
a noose is one of those things that's easier to use one way around
I think they lassoed the branch
then pulled on the belt buckle closes
it's what I would do seems easier than climbing out there
it's not merely polyester it's steel reinforced
see these lines this is where the wires run
I see rabbets for more than 20 strands
this makes getting him down much more problematic than I had assumed
kim's worldly experience is really affording him some insight here
we've got to catch up to him
do you think it's because he's sober
the cadaver hangs from a cargo belt
limbs limp and torso covered in tattoos
hmm let's go look at those tattoos
an intricate web of blue line stretches across the torso
from the right shoulder to the solar plexus
each time they intersect a small white star is formed in their crossing
hundreds of fading asterisks riddle his skin
the concentration is highest around his heart
his corpse is marked by stars
what will mine be marked by
alcohol and heartbreak
your fist clenches suddenly
it'll be riddled with disco hell yeah
decay is creeping on the tattoo
already most of the canvas that's holding it has darkened
now it disintegrates slowly letting out a stink
is this a map of the night sky
national pattern a microelectronic system
probably a national pattern this looks like a
a crime to demonstrate something
of no nation that I know of
if anything it reminds me of religious illumination
last or penultimate century
men who live harsh lives often turn to innocentic worship
but which one I see no trace of a humanoid figure
Kim is on to it
the pattern does not stir patriotic or religious sentiment in you
what it does is speak to the wounded limping animal the male in particular
unable to communicate in anything more than grunts
it's impossible to tell if its advice is right or wrong
so am I
why did you do that
he takes a thin piece of milld aluminium from his coat pocket and pulls it open
sounds like a sword being unsheathed
a small lens appears some sort of camera
let the lieutenant work we trust we trust him
shit Cuno what the fuck is that
an instant color camera
he produces two metal-capped ampoules
and clicks them into place on the side of the apparatus
a thin slot shines
this is the first time he openly acknowledges the kid's existence
I have only two ampoules
so nobody move I don't want to waste one
...points the camera at the corpse peering into it the lens needs adjusting then
a sound a shrill flash
followed by the breaking of a small ampoule of glass
you see streams of colour pour
onto the thick glossy piece of paper rolling out
in case we need it
the style of this game is so
confident and unique
to me when I think about playing games and especially narrative games
the word that comes to mind is friction like
how much friction is between me and the narrative
for example when you're playing like
I don't know an open world game like
the narrative is often telling me
you need to go to this specific place
but the game is telling me like no go wherever you want
and so there's friction just meaning in the sense
that like the more that's applied
the more I feel like I want to slow down
whereas like when there's no friction
it feels like what i'm doing in the game
and what the narrative is asking of me are just like
they're the same thread that's being pulled on
here this is great
it's ugly but in an artistic way
ludo narrative dissonance yeah
译注："ludonarrative    dissonance" 是游戏设计 领域的术语，用以描述玩法 ludology和叙事narrative 之间的矛盾。相应的设计挑 战为，如何在游戏的玩法和 叙事之间保持一致性，以提 供更加深入的游戏体验。
this is a bigger brain way to say it
I just like the word for friction
which I also use in psychology sometimes
so friction is actually a psychological term in that sense
译注：心理摩擦力-friction 可类比物理概念来理解，即 让一个行为不能顺畅发生的 因素叫作摩擦力。该概念常 用于行为塑造、习惯培养。 （如，将爆米花放到房间远 处可显著减少摄入量）
that like in the trying to change a behavior
how much friction is introduced
how much friction do you introduce to your own behavior
for example if I'm trying to quit smoking
or in the context of this game start
right now there's a lot of friction between me and starting that behavior
number one I can't find any cigarettes
number two I don't think anyone would give me one
and so I'm supposed to rely on my critical faculties
to find a unattended cigarette
to scour pennies
so that I can afford my own cigarettes
or to beat someone up and take their cigarettes
it's getting my decision making gets impaired
because there's too much friction between me and what I want
and so I start looking for shortcuts
that's genuinely where you make a lot of bad decisions
cool machine
yes it is pretty cool isn't it
oh Kim actually does have a personality
it contains inside to the victim
I'm sorry that was mean I didn't mean that Kim
I'd say this was a man of physical violence
the story he wanted his body to tell was important to him
it is his letter to us someone should decipher it
we need to show it around
your personality is honesty and earnestness
and that's enough for me
can I have it
I should look at it later without the corpse smell
I think Kim should hang on to it
he's a little more responsible
here a souvenir don't lose it
it's no longer than a pack of cigarettes okay
kiddie
this is the time of day it's the hardest to stream at
because the sun is right outside my window
and if these blinds move at all I can't see shit
the glassy-eyed corpse looks by
his mouth mute
and his skin as colorful as the chemical rainbow on the photo paper
teeming with opportunistic organisms
you've acquired an interactable item
investigate this item further by going to the interact tab in your inventory
（选项：调查靴子）
the material appears to be ceramic
its clean white stands in stark
contrast to the decaying flesh above the knee
the man wore thick polymer socks probably for padding
a fine array of interlocking plates covers them
delicate and fragile
they feel alien to the world around you out of place somehow
（选项：这是什么样的靴子？）
they're armour not boots
technically speaking these are sabatons
sabatons
（选项：什么样的盔甲？）
pceramic plate zirconium dioxide most likely
this is where the make would be under the heel
Fairweather Fairweather model T-500/VE
I'm guessing that's vitrius enamel
this is advanced stuff
yeah where the fuck did these things come from
（选项：其余部分哪去了？）
the locals probably scavenged it
it would be odd if he had more on after seven days
we should keep a look up for these pieces
the armor could yield information
maybe he'll know something
if you wear those pieces
it will help me protect your mortal coil
maybe he was just wearing those boots and
there is no rest of the armor no probably not
the sabatons dangle off the man's decaying form
ageless and synthetic
let's take him off
this feels dangerous
are you sure
okay even my fucking reptilian brain is telling me not to
so I'm not gonna try
the sabatons dangle off the man's decaying form
I love how it gave me a second chance at making not a shit decision
how about I don't touch it
（选项：这种材质看上去有些突兀）
maybe I don't touch the crime scene let's make an observation instead
金：确实 它很贵
we've requested similar material for our tactical units for years now
the constabulary's deemed it too costly
in that time we've lost six men to semi-automatics
how much we talking here
for a full set about four years of wages
okay my instinct is telling me to take the sabatons to get the money
but my relationship with Kim is evolving and very important to me right now
all right and the inland empires were my imagination than reptilian brain well
it's steering me well so far
（选项：我猜那是一大笔钱？）
as a wage it's regrettably small
but for a piece of hardware yes that's a lot
that's for us to find out
my initial report on the area suggests
he was a security guard for the harbor company
but that just hearsay
（选项：这对安保人员来说有点过于先进了）
I agree these equipment is way beyond what a guard can afford
cadaver slowly twists on the cargo belt
his torso covered in tattoos and extremities blotched pink and blue
don't be afraid to be weird you know what cyber
your encouragement has me wanting to
I at least want to knock on it
a small bell like sound fills the air
like tapping on the side of a porcelain cup
the pry bar in your hand is itching for some action
what the fuck it knows i have the pry bar in my hand
I mean that's fate right i have to smack it
let's let's hit it
the metal connects with the same ding
the sound does not appear to get louder
did you hear that a click
cybercat cyberspace cat
you're steering this investigation now
this is a kinetic redistributor
it spreads the incoming energy horizontally from plate to plate
when the plates connect there's a click
that's the sound you heard
see these lanes
the fuck did this guy go to school Kim where have you been all my life
and can you explain things to me
in that sort of like dull but intellectual voice all the time
you need to have the items equipped for the game to acknowledge them
that's brilliant
faint organic lines cover the plates where they separate into smaller ones
these plates then divide into smaller plates
until there are hundreds of them altogether
I'm so glad I just was carrying this fucking thing around
I don't know why I decided to do that
I just thought it would be cool
like the scales of some ancient white monster
cracked and pearly
let's pull the boot off
this feels dangerous
do it
the stench fills your nostrils
as you push downward
an ominous creaking sound comes from above
stop
pig's gonna pull his head off
brutal
look Kim is telling me to stop
I'm gonna stop
but I kind of want to push him a little bit
what's how is our trust going to evolve
unless I know his limits okay
you're about to put his head off
do it homo
well whoa this kid Cuno
I have to push back against that right
yes that's what I say
you'll compromise the coroner's case if you do
so please don't
what are you trying to achieve anyway
why are you hanging on to that boot
there may be clues in the boot
Kim there could be clues in there
maybe we should concentrate on what's outside the boot
and leave what's inside to the boys at processing
just these once besides
ah you're right you're right umcar
I could impress Kim or the kids
you need to push your friendship a little bit
okay how do I know where he stands
is he gonna stand by me even when I make bad decisions
because guess what buddy
I'm gonna make a lot of those throughout this playthrough
Cuno s（cunoesse） oh there's two Cunos okay
there's no way you are getting them off
all the organic matter in his body has been flowing down into the boots
they are fused to his feet now
why do you think the locals haven't scavenged them yet
all right Kim don't
embarrass me like this in front of Cuno all right
i appreciate like when you clarify things and
when you give me essential information
but you you don't need to attack my character and
like he already called me a homo right
which is not an insult by itself
but the way he said it made me feel pretty upset
so just don't don't contradict me in front of a crowd ever again
how about that
sure there's a way to peel them off
but first the body needs to be down
and second it would probably be better if the lieutenant wasn't around
okay so maybe we gotta get rid of Kim
the anticipation makes you crack your fingers feels nice
nice and cracky
we'll just respectfully agree
processing will take care of them
with the situation in the morgue
it will yield nothing
but we must pick our fight
should we continue
the cadaver slowly twists on the cargo belt
his eyes are milky white and blind to the world
protruding comically from their sockets
there is no one home just sub-aquatic terrors there
sub aquatic terrors this is this a writing is so good
dark brown hair grows on his head
his face is ready to explode from the organic processes inside
the death's head grim has passed
what remains is an unrecognisable mess
underneath the curdled meat there is an expression
not carried on his features but below inside
an expression of pleasure
this man was experiencing joy at the moment of his death
let's connect to him this is a pretty high chance
watch just watch okay I have not done any tomfoolery
with the chances of this game
so far I've gotten extremely lucky
I'm gonna click on this and I guarantee it's gonna fail
（吊人：“我已经离开了”）
oh okay
I got lucky again
where have you gone
you stinking your boring
why are you feeling pleasure when you died
maybe I was getting my rocks off
eighty three percent is the exact opposite of seventeens good point
do I look like an erotic auto-asphyxiation type to you
um
maybe
yes
captain coppdromo
I fear we are drifting away fixating on sexuality again
let's go with a simpler question
I'm a joke look at me
who were you alive
a killer a mother fucker and a killer
takes one to no one
go ahead into the wild pale yonder
god that voice just makes my reptilian sprains like skin crawl
in the past way out in the west
（选项：发生什么了）
what do you mean
（选项：我在跟你说话）
it's the power of your
black frothy liquid starts bubbling out of his lips
IMAGINATION
go ahead ask me more questions
you fucking love questions
yes I do
because you're a copparooni
look at all of them gone
do you want more questions
ah yeah give me a comical amount of questions
comin' right up coppprppni Roonie
this is getting up beat now
why do I feel like I forgotten something terrible
beacuse you have
who killed you
love did me in brother coppo it was love all alone
can you ask me...
sure lobo I can ask you a question
why are you doing this
looking at my face motionless
looking into my eyes standing here
why are you investigating my murder
I can blame it on Kim
could deny my own agency
something about me is cynically hopeful though
in a contradictory sort of way
i'm gonna say that it's leading me somewhere
or maybe i just want your fucking boots
something is on its way something hidden
it's coming
a miracle from the north west and it's almost here
you can feel it in the air on your hands
the cold spring air smoothing them over
（选项：我的名字叫罗尼吗？）
fuck no you're no Roonie
the name is Raphael Ambrosius Costeau
listen to yourself
you're not a Raphael anything
you'll probably just harry or something that's right
harry
no no
I'm definitely Rafael
good for you
I hate you
I remind you of someone
a deep sea creature
not quite be fair now
a baby
you sure wriggled out of that one coppolini
come back later coppo
amuse yourself with my frank manners
and my memento mori features
if possible also see me in your dreams
oh my god
of course
you have questions don't you
come back later cop
are you sure we finish the preliminary examination of the cadaver
we might miss some of these things once he's done
the cadaver slowly twists on the cargo belt...
the steel-reinforced belt presents a unique challenge
I brought chain cutters
but I don't see a good angle of approach to the belt
I'm pretty sure I got those chain cutters buddy
the cadaver is a good 1.2 metres up
neither one of us can reach the belt without assistance
and even if we do there's the question of cutting it
saw the branch let's not do it
could shoot him down
maybe we can ask for help from the harbor
ah maybe we could saw the branch
climb up there and saw the branch
I don't trust that ladder the assailants didn't use it
it's rotten and less sturdy than it looks
那他妈是怎么把他弄上去的
and I don't see another good way up there
honestly I prefer a non-acrobatic solution to these
clown cops climb tree fall down
enraged cop assaults children after falling from tree
cretin cop they like that word saws the branch he's sitting on literally
你可太懂了
local children report corpse mutilation
fuck yeah climb that shit monkeys
fuck you
C you're only making them do those things less
those kids bully us into not doing our work okay
yes we should us acrobatics as the very last option
after we've tried everything normal
these have got to be the most fucking boring mulkkupaat I've ever seen
oh fuck off
can someone else do it
someone else you mean like the police
sadly yes the whole RCM is out there right now
doing the exact same thing we are
I know it's hard but I assure you
the others won't come to help us
and we have a growing sanitary concern here
we need to get him down fast
as you narrow your eyes
the monster before you
only the lower extremities are pink with a dash of blue
his fatted hands thighs and his neck just above the noose
（回chat）我没有枪！没枪怎么射！
the rest of the corpse appears dark green in the cold spring air
（选项：我们重新谈谈怎么把他搞下来）
yes we do
yeah bang bang time pig shoot his head off
how
to shoot the belt
yeah
yeah shoot the belt
it absolutely will not officer that's not how physics work
it will maybe cut one thread loose
yeah now we're talkin' entertain the Cuno with some shit
they'll miss the pigs will miss Cuno
the lieutenant is undecided
on one hand he wants to shoot some gun
on the other it's an awfully stupid idea
let's get kim's
let's get his anxiety up
let me try alright Kim
let me give this a shot
lieutenant's brow is furrowed
he appears too deep in concentration
take the shot lieutenant
I blow his head off
take it take the shot
take it
take the shot Cuno wants some of that shit
silence with his elbow sharp the lieutenant unzips his jacket
fucking shoot that fucking guy down
and produces a lightweight firearm
he drops a paper cartridge in the barrel
separates the scouring stick and gives the cartridge five tucks
fucking do it kim let's go
he then steps back
and assumes the Falostesse position  taking aim
the corner of his eye twitches his finger is on the trigger
（选项：把那个狗娘养的射下来）
he's gonna fucking mi
the kick voice is drowned in a shrill blast
that echoes off the walls of the surrounding tenements
a cloud of smoke slowly parts in the air
as the lieutenant steps back and says to himself
god damn it
oh come on Kim
he feels bad about it
about his eyes mostly just having bad eyesight properly from a young age
whatever you do do not console him
fucking idiot
fuck
these fucking kids
Cuno could have hit it easy
but then Cuno is not fucking handicapped is he
well give the fucking gun to the kid then
it said don't console him
maybe I need to push Kim a little bit more okay
here's the thing
Kim feels like he's been in charge this whole time
he's like walking around like he has to baby me all right
like he knows I'm not all there all the time
and I think he's a little afraid to make his own decisions
I think I have to I
don't insult him
okay
we'll back it up
I have to say it's beginning to look unlikely
we can get him down without assistance
okay
I was really hoping we wouldn't
the union appear to be suspect in this case
it seems like a dangerous route to go down
what then what the fuck are we supposed to do
okay they do have the tools and the men
and since it looks like they put him there
but what are the options
the corpse twists on the belt like chicken on a skewer
maybe I should try with the gun
I think you should give me the gun
it's bad as it is  us shooting firearms like punks
go ahead i'm not stopping you
just don't lose it
yes give me the gun
they only have one gun
this is the sorriest pair of pigs Cunos ever seen
will you kids fucking scram
don't you have school
where's the school in this fucking game
yeah take it you fucking banaanipoika
take it and shoot yourself in the mouth
fucking these fucking kids
feel the weight first
the cold piece of bakelite and gunmetal is surprisingly light
先熟悉熟悉这个东西
your fingers fit right through the guard
instinctively resting on the trigger
I like the sound of that
what the fuck are you waiting for Cuno
tell him to shoot himself in the mouth
Cuno is silent
aggression gathers in the air
the trigger feels delicate and ready to break under your finger
我要让这些小鬼看着
我要让小孩们见识
the trigger feels delicate and ready to break under your finger
I'll show Kim
I'll show the cadaver
I'll show everyone
the buckle comes into focus in your sights
等着 看我是怎么做到的
you stand with your feet planted firmly in the ground
and your left hand supporting your gun
my guy is probably basically sober by now
he's pointing it directly at his head
it's gonna blow his head off isn't it
why don't you just shoot yourself in your mouth
at least you won't miss
I do want the kids I want to tell the kid to shut up
I'm gonna do that but
do I close point the gun
I can point the gun at the kid
I'm not gonna shoot the kid
I gonna tell him to shut up though
or what you're gonna fuck me
you want to fuck me pig is that what this is about
what the fuck
and fuck it
boom got him
the buckle explodes into tiny pieces coming loose with a whirr
what the fuck
with your hand numb from the recoil
you look have the body slump down
for a moment the man appears to kneel in front of you
luckiest cop in the world
I don't know what's happening
looking straight at you
helpless trapped within itself
who killed you
communism
it takes a millisecond for the association to flash within your cortex
you have no idea where it's coming from
then the rigor in his muscles gives up
and he smashes sideways into the spring mud
你被执法了
letting out a horrid stench
who's laughing at you little shit yeah
let's get those fucking kids back
fuck you kyrpale
you've been policed
（金：高击掌！）
yeah
take that one Kim
this is
I gotta I gotta give him a high five
fucking boom
the lieutenant takes a little hop to perform the customary salutation
your palm hurts from the slap
it's precise and down to the point
I knew these guys were f****ts
i just can't ignore it
we will perform a field autopsy and determine the cause of death
but before excuse me
the stanch is getting bad
I'm sorry to interrupt the jubilations here
I need a little breather before we do the autopsy
what field autopsy
yes the four phases of a murder scene
one investigation of the scene
I can't say I'm satisfied with that part yet
I still want to know what's in that trash container
well we gotta check out the trash
two initial examination of the victim
we were pretty good in our efforts
and the autopsy will provide another chance
i mean i basically did everything here so
three field autopsy
this will not be pleasant or easy
and it will have to be performed on the scene
what the fuck are they on about
are these fucking kids gonna watch us do that and comment on it as well
cops are gonna cut his shit up next
four and final transport of the coroner's case to the district morgue
I'll do that
god these things
don't we have a doctor
you and I are detectives
the honorary rank of detective signifies our ability
to handle the entire incident chain
from crime scene to autopsy to clean-up
we do it all
yeah I feel like a detective
your station would not have assigned you the case otherwise
this case is important
alright you know what kim
can you hold the mean for now
we should try to interview Evrart Claier the leader of the union
harbor property was clearly used in the hanging
the harbor just east of here getting in might prove a challenge though
or we could ask around for the representative of the logistics company
my initial information say the wild pines
have sent some sort of strike negotiator
to wrangle control back from Evrart
yes and those were the interviewiees let's go
sensible decision okay
we've weaseled our way out of another crisis here
make sure we save here check out that body now
the rotting man lies on his side
with his eyes looking straight through you
lieutenant adjusts his glasses and takes a deep breath
we will come back to that
fuck does Cuno care
who is Cuno
Cuno's Cuno pig
Cuno primal violent
I'm gonna do some verbal combat with this fucking kid
bat with this fucking kid
that went about as good as it could
I don't know we're getting extremely lucky here
yeah think about it think about that rabid Cuno shit
he seems glad someone understood what he was going for
but right as he's getting distracted
you hear a malevolent hiss from behind the fence
watch out Cuno
he's trying to fiddle you
he's gonna put his hands on you
oh my god
help pigs got Cuno help rape
help he's got the Cuno help
I don't think anyone in this world would ever
no bystander is going to go out of their way
to help someone in this disgusting environment
just answer the question
help he digging his dick out
escalate Cuno his dick is out you are afraid
pigs are hurting Cuno  somebody please
shut him down
wait does this mean
does this mean hit him
I mean I have a forty two percent chance of succeeding
should I give Cuno a smack I mean
what can I say give him hell yeah
after all this
okay I fail at that one
I succeeded and running away from the bartender
你没能让他闭嘴
your fat fist didn't meet its target
instead it pulled you down with it
I succeed at shooting the fucking guy down
at scoping out the entire crime scene
like I did all this intellectual shit
but my guy is too fucked in his own body to like give a kid a slap
I mean checks out
it's actually pretty consistent with my character
try to hold it together
pig's trying not to cry Cuno can't believe this shit
can no one stop the Cuno
I can't stop the Cuno
that's the title of this video I can't stop the Cuno
pig Cuno thought you had this
what happened Cuno can do anything now
the whole charade was about to establishing dominance over you
it's safe to say he has succeeded
I've been dominated by the Cuno
fuck your shoulder
fuck your knee
fuck your fat body up
ah
Kim get let's get Kim involved
金：不。
why what you're not gonna help me
why did I give you the gun back
Kim you're supposed to be irresponsible for me here
the creature behind the fence makes it a point to laugh even harder
Cuno made you his fuck gimp
my morale is just declining oh my god
the lieutenant isn't laughing at all
well then fucking help me up
just get back to it
unbelievable
Cuno beat the shit out of the popo
you didn't do anything
（坤诺：打断你的腿！）
I brought this all on myself
I told you not to tempt such forces
now how about we go and do something worth the public's time
oh yeah you're gonna take the moral high ground
Kim okay well
let's leave these fucking kids to themselves
fuck out of here
let's check out that dumpster first
this trash container is locked
我已经受够了自取其辱
the sliding lid has a padlock that says whirling in rags
there's something in there not necessarily connected to the case but still
the body is downwind from here
maybe you prefer the smell of garbage to the smell of death
trash food waste from the cafeteria
they lock these containers to keep the derelict from flocking in
could be evidence too
I feel like there's some evidence
I mean we gotta get into that trash
what do you mean feel
it's just a hunch kim
we could try using a pry bar
the one you took from my motor carriage or
or
or we could ask for a key from the manager of the whirling in rags
he probably has one
this is a white check you may retry it
my body is not very good
it's 17 percent I don't want to tempt it
I just failed a 42 percenter
let's look we'll try to get the key
so you said something about a white check
how do I do those
how do I retry them or whatever
what do I need to do here
god damn we have a lot of quests there are tasks
check the map
so what do I do
like these ones
oh I can try it again
so meaning I should just try this anyways right
force time isn't happening
you've jammed the pry bar under the lid
but it just isn't bending
what is this
your triceps ache for the metal to bend but it resists
this calls for a potent curse help break it's resistance
utter the POWER WORDS
the FUCK kind of metal is this this is fucking SHIT
I could complain I could kick it or
I could try harder that doesn't seem like
I think complaining is more inspirator
金：金属的质量没有问题
from what I see it's sturdy enough
he's enjoying your little failure he finds it amusing
he's reveling in the sweaty rage on your face
god damn it god damn it
now what I've done is I've lost all of kim's respect
after I did that fucking sick thing where I shot the guy down
and I scoped out the entire crime scene
now I can't do simple shit like
like like
hit a stupid kid or open a trash can
my character is a failure at the most important things
let's ask the manager for the key
oh fuck this
the letter r is crown
let's get the fuck out of here
I don't care about owning that kid anyways
so meaning I could probably try and go get my thing back
a broken window
could probably try to get my
my tie
okay what are the things I'm really failing at here
threaten people
do I want to be threatening no I don't think so
I think my body just needs some kind of attention
pick locks and pockets that's pretty cool
sneak under their noses
see hear and smell everything
I feel like failing at physical stuff yeah
my physique is like not even that bad
it's my motor that's pretty bad
I feel like reaction speed is probably pretty important
physical instrument
what is this
lie
see the art
enables you to take what others don't notice
the little wad of bills hid away in the sugar bowl
takes in the final detail of the physical world
that's what i really want is
to be very perceptive of people in the environment
but a failure to actually do anything about it
like observation skills
like that's the failed therapist in him like
he's trained to spot people and detect everything
but he can't exert his agency on anything
because he's just a failure of a human
shivers what is shivers
tune into the city
shivers comes when the temperature drops
and you become more keenly aware of your surroundings
enables you to hear the city itself
to truly belong to the streets
it's a supernatural ability
old wrongs play out in present time
scenes across the city happened in front of you
but who is speaking to you
at high level shivers may make you seem mad to the outside world
seldom hear the city
speaking to you it does seem pretty cool
and it does go alongside inland empire
as like a magical intuition
street wise
but I kind of want to be a
I'll probably speck into shivers as well
got zero in this
it urges you to be better than you are
that's probably nothing
you can drop one in shivers
if you enjoy good writing
let's do it drop one shivers
okay we've got a lot of stuff  we can do here
find smokes and smoke them that's that's a priority
track down my badge
track down my gun
I kind of do feel like having my gun would be a good idea
what was that other one
ah yeah
I should get briefed by Kim on the case
yes
tell me about the case
what do you want to know
literally anything I can't remember a single thing
ah yes okay the case brief you missed now I remember
three days ago the RCM Emergencies Desk received a report
about a security guard who was found hanged in Martinaise
an anonymous caller said
there was a dead body behind the whirling in rag's hostle cafeteria
the cadaver had been there for four days
no one had come to investigate
during that time
the victim had been stripped of his belongings
the caller did not identify him but used the word lynching
there is an ongoing labor dispute
between the local dockworkers and the logistics company Wilde Pines
I was told we should approach the death as part of this dispute
they didn't identify themselves in any way
the tone was muffled using a device of some sort
the desk could identify neither the caller's age nor sex
there's a strong prejudice against involving the RCM
in what's seen as the union matters
the dockworkers union is the de facto police in Martinaise
now it appears they've started executing too
we cannot allow that
and the RCM is
that's us the Revachol Citizens Militia
we're the police in this city
we're here to find the killer
why are we on the same place
you and I are pawns in a pissing competition
yeah tell me who's really pulling the strings here
his disdain is clear
this man would not use such an expression otherwise
金：你不知道？
go deeper
I assumed you were in on it
I don't remember being in on anything
you know what I'm in on retrograde amnesia
that's for me not for Kim
what's there to say
it's just stupidity
keep it going
our precincts can't decide if Martinaise is
part of Jamrock or the Industrial Harbor
yours or mine
as if we somehow own parts of the city
typical street gang mentality
so we've let the union make a mockery of law enforcement here
and now it's come to its natural conclusion
well sort of
it's less a matter of who gets to police Martinaise than who has to
it's an orphan district in other words
I think the dispatch desk just told both our stations about the hanging
there was quite the brouhaha at 57th I can tell you that
time to settle it they said Cop Off
but I assure you I am not their finest or toughest
with 102 cases solved
what I am is least interested in a pissing competition
so he volunteered to represent the 57th
but not out of competitiveness
on the contrary
good reaction speed there
so you volunteered to spoil it
we've got a motivation here
I'm an unrepentant spoilsport
I'm the finest case solving machine
sent to outperform you in every way imaginable
hmm
I feel like I have a lot of ground to make up with with Kim
because I really sufficiently embarrassed myself
with that trash can and losing to Cuno so
I don't want to also come off as a
close minded are uninsightful
I probably have an unbelievable kill count
an apocalyptic omen sent by my people
I'm gonna leave why I was sent unspecified
the silence carries
Martinez nothing
it's just a pedal at the end of some drain pipe
no one cares about this place they care about spots
most of our colleagues don't even know how to get here
north of the interchange doesn't exist
a tremble comes over you
哦 天人感应来了
another after-effect of ethanol poisoning perhaps
feels like leaves do when they rustle in the breeze
somewhere far away below the turbine
the 41st and the 57th
the lieutenant was right
it's not about who gets what's north
it's about who doesn't
okay shivers is fucking good
yes it's a wholly pointless matter
forget I ever mentioned it
what I like about that is it yeah
it's like an intuitive sort of like
grasp on the bigger picture
like who benefits
who doesn't benefit
he's actually glad it's addressed now
three percent chance
uh let's go for it
because you're the best qualified
那肯定不是
no that doesn't seem right
I'm exceedingly well
why can't you remember why you were sent
anyway don't keep the lieutenant waiting
okay
we'll find out more about Kim as we go along
ask this lady what's up
the RCM in matinez what can I help you with
shivers as cool as it is implied to be a paranormal intuition
上面另有条chat个人很喜欢，说天人感应是Outland Empire
but you can sign it away as
译注：反常扭曲-parataxic distortion，心理学概念， 指个体将过去的人际关系和 情感模式投射到当前情境中 ，对他人和事件产生不切实 的感知和反应。
just being literally the definition of a parataxic distortion
it seems like
not too many things you discover through shivers
may matter of decisions
but it definitely gives you a lot of like worldly context
or maybe that's wrong
can raise your chances if you explore other dialogue options
the check is locked because you didn't
oh okay
so I should have talked with him about some other things first
of course
what can I help you with
can I borrow your gloves
I'm doing an autopsy
that's a little direct
of course where to
wild pines you mean the company woman
yes a representative of the Harbor
she should have set up operations nearby
oh
that must be the woman on the giant boat
there's one docked on the pier
it arrived a couple of weeks ago
it's very hard to miss
okay
where am I
just tell me where we are
we are in Martinaise sir
this intersection is called roundabout north I think
there's the pier
（选项：北边有什么？）
the capeside apartment buildings
some more tenements not a lot really
（选项：东边有什么？）
the hobbergates some kind of commotion I think
I don't follow the local politics
（选项：南边有什么？）
some shops and the bridge
the Canal bridge leads to the coast
but it's broken I think
some kind of accident probably
（选项：运河的另一边有什么？）
just coast
there's a little fishing village there
and a fish market
but that got closed down ages ago
rows of stalls under a broad roof
where silvery fish were heaped on newspapers
water water everywhere pouring from the heavens
in the shadow of the old church
there is just like good writing hidden in that skill isn't there
what kind of fish market
it's just water no
actually I think they call it the Martinaise inlet
there are some islands in the bay but they're hard to reach
all right
let's ask her for our gloves
wow sure keep them i have another pair
okay I'll take him
（选项：你到底是谁？）
me I am just a gardener
（选项：那你在这里做什么？）
I am working
（选项：做什么工作？）
I have a greenhouse in the yard there
I've been trying to get some work done
there's discomfort she stops mid sentence
well as you probably know
there's a corpse hanging from a tree there
it smells pretty bad so I have to take breaks
don't worry miss we are here to clean it up
you can get to work soon
thank you
down do you mean the body is finally gone
oh
we just left it on the ground
can you tell me when you've taken him away then
no do not report back to this random civilian about anything
yeah exactly
why would I do that
this is why I became a cop god damn it
so I don't have to answer to anyone but myself
see you around officer
thanks for the gloves miss
I'll put them to good work let's put those on
all right we got another skill point here
drama this is about lying to people
treat the world as a stage
lie concoct the most elaborate and wonderful stories
render you an insufferable thespian
I can't lie or discern when others lie
that's pretty good I don't know if I want to do a lot of lying
but I need to know if other people are lying
authority makes itself seem very reasonable you've got a good point
where is authority
assert and reassert your dominance over those around you
become William Shakespeare
demands respect
hey what's up kraith
I kind of want to take a point in drama
if they lie you'll know immediately
I want to be able to call people out on their shit
definitely a Respect Junkie yeah so far
译注："Respect Junkie" （未想出恰当中译）指的是 一种极度渴望他人尊重的人 。特征：过度追求认可、低 自尊、表现欲强、敏感脆弱 ，甚至可能做出一些夸张或 极端的行为来引起注意和获 得他人的肯定。
both can sus out lies okay well
then maybe I expect more into empathy
it was volition
to be a good guy well
that's probably not what I'm going for
how's the gaming going it's going
it's good there's some ups and downs
my guy is exceptionally good at certain things
and really bad at much simpler things
halflight is your fight or flight response
sense the ways situations are about to turn
ultra attuned to the world around you
the Cuno happened yeah
I got beat up by a kid
I tried to hit up the kid and I fell on the ground
and not only did the kid laugh at me
but I lost kim's respect as well
then I tried to open a trash can and my guy was too weak
but I made a pinpoint laser shot to knock the body down
with a fucking pistol
have a zero in this
I don't have a zero in anything else
at low levels you'll be bumbling freckless cop unable to catch a pair of keys
see this is what I'm missing
I can't be bumbling way way through the world like this
I got to put a point into this right
I do count this as a win
let's put something in that
I can't just like go around like
I'm traumatized by like losing that battle to Cuno
I think this would have probably made a big difference
I want to be persuasive
but I also want to be cool
okay so it sounded like where you're to go north
to the pier
welcome to Revachol
he doesn't even talk to me
（选项：你为什么要那样针对我的搭档）
don't you welcome to Revachol me
my grandfather came here from a 3000 year old racist isolationist culture
while your ancestors came to this island a mere 300 years ago
every school of thought and government has failed in this city
but I love it nonetheless
it belongs to me as much as it belongs to you
jeez Kim is getting deep here
it's men like you who keep Revachol divided
making it that much harder for everyone
to climb out of this post war limbo
oh come on man I just said welcome to Revachol
it's a lorry driver thing
racist lorry driver
I know exactly what you meant
you think my kind doesn't belong here
that I should watch myself and behave
but you see I'm an officer of the RCM
it's actually my job to make sure you behave
silence the air between them become tense
maybe I should give the fucking crowbar over to Kim
your partner needs backup now's your moment to shine
fucking yeah I've got your back
I've got your back Kim
he Kim is really the muscle of our little duo here
you do make a cute couple you know that
the lieutenant exhales and resumes his regular calmness
把他关起来 金
whatever you say officer
等会 我们等会儿再对付这个傻大个
you could ask him to show you the soles of his boots
he definitely looks like someone capable of a lynching
maybe he was present
yeah that's a good point authority
got a smoke
nope
he's got a smoke right there in his fucking hand
snatch that shit out of his fat fingers
need after listening to his garbage
you're smoking one right now
it's my last one
you hiding some smoke
could I do that I'm an honest man
look I'm the one with a fucking crowbar all right
give me a smoke
what officer
sorry I couldn't be off any help
what's that argument all about
it's about biological detaminism
natural law the sorting of the races
not the most popular topic nowadays
with the coalition in charge and all
you might want to change the topic
that is bury your head under the sand like come on sheep
change the topic
the way he says it makes it almost sound like a threat
oh so you're just a racist makes sense
yeah a cigarette hoarding racist
I'm not just racist look
I've read books
the science of racial theory has all been proved
even if some people don't want to accept it
hey what's up masters
welcome to the stream
yeah it's been a long time since we've seen you around
it's been pretty interesting so far
people who've studied these things said that
you and me are superior by desire
so naturally
we Occidentals should be in charge
obviously you can see the merits in that
well man what's blowing my mind is like
every character that I've stumbled across
which has been like four or five of them
has like so much to say and so much to react to
and just really deepens the environment that I'm in
I haven't walked more than a couple meters in any direction in this game
and I feel like I've been sucked into like this whole infinite possible world
it's crazy
even some fucking fat fingered cigarette hoarding
racist has a lot of interesting things to say
open your eyes
haven't you noticed something different lately
an unfortunate downturn maybe
when members of the superior race cease to
believe in their innate superiority
they stop competing for resources
okay and
this concerns you policeman so you better be vigilant
the damn kipts are showing up good lately
same with the mesquitos and the other introduced species too
they're on the precipice of cultural victory
（选项：这个文化胜利是什么意思？）
it's what the kipts of boogie street are going for
right under our noses
and the others too
on the radio heard any chanson lately
heard any mottettos or lieder no
dominating culture is how they plan to win
they say so themselves
it's who
also you need to realize the dangers of mixing races
who knows what might happen
if people don't stay in their birth place
you might end up with a new sub race with the new characteristics
leading to extra competition
that's why you've got to control the offspring
yeah I think I can get down with racism
fuck
yeah I'm not down with this
why don't you go fuck yourself there we go
don't push your luck runt
let that be where it is
let's check out that trash can though
probably need to drink some of that magnesium
gotta I gotta heal up
can I go in here
wanted to be a dirty cop I do not a racist cop
you see several packaged raincoats fill a low shelf
beneath a display of croissants and juice bottles
the raincoats are transparent except for the big FRITTTE slogan on the back
what is that is what
uhm it's a raincoat
why is she so snippy she's snippy already
if you want to buy one then it's only 4 Real
I don't have that I don't have shit
I got less than one Real
the tear machine stands in the corner
a sign says one bottle equals ten cents
hmm oh that's the tare machine
（选项：是啊 但到底是*做什么*的）
it's a machine for tare
you know you find tare outside like bottles or whatever
and put it in the machine then it gives you money
you need a bag I guess
we used to have some but we gave them all out so
feel free to use it if you find a bag though
I'm sure there are some out there
somewhere
okay so I need to get a bag
so that I can pick up some bottles in the trash
so I can turn them into this thing
and then I can buy some sigs that's what I gotta do
that's what I gotta do right now
what's all this then
okay bunch of rioting bullshit
not my focus I my guy
look I've been putting my brain behind...
oh this guy's got a cigarette it's got a sig
I am a gander and a hunter and a gatherer
feel like a traveller
what's going on here
it's the jam my man
it's a traffic jam for the ages
harbour gates up the street are shut tight
no explanation given
workers on strike scabs agitatin' and all around clusterfuck
meanwhile we're all stuck here in long haul limbo
for days upon days upon days
limbo huh
so how long you've been here
feels like forever
like I was born on this here roundabout
just me and the metal and the tires
the oil and the fumes of mazut
can you say it again only a little less plodding
I look I like this guy I don't want to put him off
I'm still trying to get that cigarette right out of his hand
I'm just gonna praise him
yeah imagine it's been a whole week already
behind the laugh however
a touch of sorrow
is that empathy coming out
so tell me what do you need
how about a cigarette
nope don't smoke
he's smoking
some of the other drivers do though
他明明正在抽烟！！！
there's still a few around waiting for the jam to disperse
or waiting for the sweet release of death
he's literally smoking a cigarette
yup nothing wrong with that statement
your senses have nothing to add
you'll have to ask around elsewhere
was actually born and spent his whole virtual life in this roundabout true
you could also check the kiosk down the street
Frittte with three t-s
Revachol is weird
see anything about the dead guy
....I know that all accounted for
otherwise I haven't really asked about that
been wastin' time right here keepin' busy
the reason he didn't give me a cigarette
is because I could
technically I couldn't perceive the one in his fucking hand
analyzing the fundamental structural and psychological conditions
of being stranded in the midst of a sea of motor lorries
and their sad despondent chauffeurs
a sense of surprise there ain't more bodies hanging from more trees
I mean he's got a certain way of looking at the world
it's like whatever's going on over at the docks
workers got a blockade set up
making demands
no way in or out
（选项：所以他们有什么要求？）
some pretty wild stuff I hear
like a giant new power crane in half the company
forget what exactly
I've heard talk there's a company rep in town too
like a strike negotiator type
they know what's up
precise demands and so on
ah yes from the wild pines we'll meet her soon enough I'm sure
they want to keep that money flowing in my man ka-ching
it's all about money
I mean at the end of the day you gotta ask yourself
who benefits who's collecting on this tragedy
anything else
us lorry drivers camionneurs
a few still hang around here waiting for this mess to end
most have scurried off somewhere to get drunk or high
or laid
not that I blame 'em really
not my thing
chasing transient pleasures is a drag these days
I prefer the examined life now
thinkin' reflectin' observin'
he's just living his life experiencing everything around him
what's better than chasing transient pleasures
the more transient the better
when one's ended you can get onto the next one
oh high grade narcotics illegal firearms stuff like that
time to arrest him
oh I can just arrest him like that
nah Tommy wouldn't do that
Tommy wouldn't corrupt the world like that
ha no I'm joking my man
FALN runs a nice clean business
this haul of cargo is mostly sporting goods
you know tracksuits and that kind of thing
usually gets shipped to Graad and the Occident
不准调戏我的争强好胜！
though we've been making headway in the iilmaraan market lately
我差点把他逮起来
I was gonna lock Tommy up for life
can I get one of those track suits
we're pals and all
but I can't just freely hand out the merchandise
the bosses won't be happy
（选项：所以 没有什么违禁物品咯？）
not unless they've legalized sports equipment
while I was on the road this rocking beauty
（选项：背后那个是你的車吗？）
this rockin' beauty sure is
like a rash you can't get rid of
you interested in heavy duty cargo machinery
yeah it must be
your job is to know all these little things isn't it
well my job is to deliver tracksuit trousers
汤米是个纯朴的人
there it is again a little touch of sadness beneath his cool
he thinks he's spent too long in this lorry
I mean his name is literally Tommy the man
yeah Tommy the man
loom loom
the man taps his fingers rhythmically against his arm
he's just a dude
（检定-通情达理：你从他的眼睛里看到了什么?）
oh fuck yeah
an empathy response
let's get a little bit deeper in with Tommy
let's see what he's really made of
in his eyes a half-familiar longing
flecks of brown and gold
（选项：怎么个熟悉法?）
it's hard to say
his gaze wonders southwest down the street
that goes beyond the horizon
what are you looking at Tommy
what missed life are you thinking of
that you never got to live
do you really want to sell tracksuits
do you really think standing out here
in the cold miserable environment
with all these trash cans and racists around
is where he wanted to be no
Tommy had bigger dreams a bigger life imagined for himself
hopefully one day we can get him there
the road continues for miles
flowing together with other roads
turning into causeways or bridges
and in suddenly in dead ends
or ramping up or down highways
it forms a crisscross pattern across the land
where it lead
above the Jamrock Quarter in the form of a raised motorway
and then the never ending sprawl of Faubourg
high above buildings new and old
the air filled with the rumble of motor engines
go further
to the old old south
我好爱天人感应
to the farthest outskirts of Revachol
感谢刚才的加点建议
through the chequered fields of farmland
upstream to the River Esperance
past Monte-Martin the border approaches
（选项：边界上方是什么?）
you cannot see it's out of the city up ahead the mist blocks all sight
a gale blows across your cheeks it is cold
before you stands a tall lorry driver with sad eyes
（选项：西南方有什么?）
excuse me
I'm I fucking
译注（到底在注些什么）： "I can fix you”是个网络 迷因，通常用于嘲讽或自嘲 人自认为可以改变或拯救他 人（尤其是在情感或心理上 有问题的个体）的天真想法 。
I can fix you Tommy
I can fix you
man
I don't know what to say
not much anyone can do
there's no helping an absence you know
I miss my family
they're all I have
my wife a second kid on the way
waiting all the way in Deora
and here I am stuck in this shit
so far from home
oh this is my character's
latent failed therapist opportunity coming out
what's it like to miss someone Tommy
not just what it's like to miss someone as a human
but what is it like for Tommy to miss someone
what's it like good and bad
an ache that brings you joy
I think of them a lot
I dream up these silly scenarios in great detail
of living with them
it comforts me
an ache that brings you joy
let's drop all this crime investigation shit
and just follow Tommy around
what about you copman
you missing someone
is that what it is this feeling
no it's scary than that
you're pursued by a hunter
smelling of apricots and sorrow and the past
I love this I love that there's two parts of me that are like
not in agreement with what it is I'm feeling
I miss my gun that's true
I'm a fine man I don't miss anyone
I miss someone but I don't know who it is
that feels honest
no I feel hunted that does also feel quite honest
I'm gonna get real with Tommy
I feel for you my friend it's bad enough to know who you miss
missing like that doesn't feel like it has much of an upside
but thanks for this
it's nice to talk to someone
and I know it wasn't easy to ask
I hope you find your way through your own troubles
there's a therapy session on the cold streets for you
we just made tommy's day a little bit brighter
helped him clarify that that joyful aching is
actually something that gives meaning and value to
the mission that he's on and the people that he misses
fuck man that was deep
don't be a stranger
still fucked up he didn't give me a cigarette though
okay I'm pretty sure we're supposed to go north
getting fucking sidetracked by
all this interesting stuff that's happening around me
hello sir
step right in the door is open
I am the law I just go around and saying that to people
are you interested in a new and exciting book
no does this kid have any cigarettes on her
okay sir
I'll try to answer any questions you have
I hope they're about books
what's your name
her name is Annette sir
my mum her name is Plaisance she owns the store
she's inside minding the register or organizing the stock
this girl is extremely suspicious to me
I mean she's well dressed she's standing here unsupervised
and she's got a really positive like disposition about her
like none of that stuff fits with the rest of her environment
free to step in and Brasall was
I'm gonna guess that she was involved in the crime
this is the one who had the fucking light feet in the crime scene
just standing here looking all inconspicuous
it's gotta be her I gotta arrest her
I'm signalling that the story's open
otherwise people might not know
they'd miss out on the crime romance ambography's a famous people
a sudden gush of wind turns the pages of the books on the counters
she covers her face smiling
but she's cold
such a good trooper you are no
I could brutally dismantle in the free market
you're cold can I help in some way
kind of you to officer
what could you do to help her anyway
I could throw her in shackles
thank you sir
I'm happy to help mom out with the store
here we go
this is the question for me where is your school
why aren't you in school
I'm doing my studies at home at the moment
I have to help mom keep this place running
what is school anyway
let's get Annette's opinion on that
school well mine is a big yellow building on Boogie street
and the people there run it
they say it's a charity
the gale wind blows in from the coast
a wind of needles
it wraps itself around a building of brick and mortar
somewhere a clamour rings through the honeycomb of classrooms
I like this writing stings me
it stings me with how good it is
a honeycomb of classrooms
（选项：这是什么感觉?）
remorse
the parquet of assembly halls
the rows of stall bars are growing cold
the corridors stand empty
a girl's voice somehow finds its way through this strange feeling
you haven't heard a word of what she's been saying these past few moments
you only hear
mom says it's necessary to do both because it builds character
mom says a proper worker is dutiful
that's how you get ahead in life you succeed
mom says it's peachy
she was a little afraid at first
there's talk about this house being curved
behind her the window has been boarded up
you sense the boards creaking
twisting for a second
and some kind of doubt in her tense shoulders
cursed in the way that makes them say
that no business has ever really thrived here sir
that they all go
bankrupt
exactly but we've been doing fine so far
I don't think curses are real
should probably look into this
we can go into the bookstore and ask about the case
but I don't seem much more to look into here
yeah well you've been fucking quiet this whole time kim
yes please do also look at our wares inside
the postcards and board games are there sir
maybe I should show you about some of our books instead
okay you're distracting me child
unless you have a cancer stick for me to suckle on
I need I have things to do
there's so many things to interact with though
it's overwhelming
let's take a look at what do you find here
this coin operated viewer is facing south
the instruction manual says to insert 25 centims
and pull the handle while looking inside
then use the focus knob to zoom in if necessary
well I don't have very much money
I feel like my guys crafty enough to get a cigarette without paying for it
so I'm gonna drop some coinage and
your money disappears into the coin slot
a clunk the ring of metal
the curtains on the display open
you lean in to catch the view
it's blurry different blues and greens
in the middle of the shimmer stands a drab grey shape like a ghost
the lenses shift the ghost sharpens into a islet in the bay
in the ruins a man made structure is visible
a half sunken sea fort
its concrete almost reconquered by nature
it looks as if it was abandoned quite some time ago
nothing but a rotten tooth remains of the anti aircraft tower
a lonely birch tree grows out of it
its leaves ripped from it by the winter wind
damn 25 cents for all that fucking good world building
really I don't have the eyesight to make it out
yeah we know that Kim you couldn't even shoot down the fucking corpse
the little brave birch tree seems to wave back in the wind
Tibbs has windows what do we got here
some signage
yeah we need to get to the pier
Kim getting bullied look Kim
me and Kim got work to do
I'm not sure exactly what his role is in this little duopoly we have
because he ain't actually doing much
except causing me grief and embarrassing me in front of fucking Cuno
ugh something in the trash
a navy coat
it's gonna ruin my half light though
hey up here
piggo
who the fuck is that
who just called me a piggo
the streets will flow red once more
a great torrent rushing down Rue d'Esperance
you wait and see
yeah he does have a gun only because I gave it back to him
the streets will not flow red with anything who are you
I'm Cindy the fucking skull
这个地方的死小孩都是怎么回事啊
what else do you want to know
blood type the last time I was tested for hep C
do you know cuno
these fucking kids they all go to the same school
where is your school
why aren't you in it
why are you hanging around
given everybody who passes by fucking grief and existential dread
I'm the law
just answer some fucking questions okay
ask away pigman but I don't promise to answer
you don't promise to answer
why were you cat calling me a moment ago
what are you doing up there do anything about the murder
I ain't no snitch pigstein
go forth and forage in someone else's shit
no shortage of squealers in these parts
it's like all these fucking people
and their vulgar tone towards adults and really people of authority okay
whatever's happening in that school
they're not teaching them about how to respect cops
actually there is a shortage of people
who talk to us in a normal calm informative manner
where are all the how the fuck did Kim turn out like this in this cruel world
we weren't put on this earth to make your life pleasant
fuck-o
fucking hate these kids
arrest the kid exactly
（选项：你一直往旁边看 你在看什么）
lieutenant is desperately searching for a handkerchief
she turns her head and face the coast
hatred disgust
it's difficult to tell which of the two is more present in her girlish features
the woman on the boat does not notice her staring
that Ozonne whore someone's got to keep an eye on her
（选项：野松公司的代表？）
yes we should go talk to her
she is a professional negotiator of though
I have the feeling she will be very cooperative while telling us nothing
you should take the lead ask her unexpected questions
you know do your thing
don't be afraid to get a bit wacky
throwing her off is our best bet
okay Kim yeah
so maybe the slow and steady approach
that you've been fucking using
isn't actually the best one for this
（辛迪：好主意 猪猡）
run along now fuck her shit uo good
别再侮辱我了行吗！！我已经...
impound that boat while you're at it
I'd like to watch her swim back to Ozonne
I'm already feeling soft and bruised
by my my failed encounter with Cuno okay
I've already had my ego and my actual body bruised
every time I get insulted by another one of these kids
I just want to fucking lock them up
just lock them up
（选项：你对这面墙做了什么？）
can't you tell
I'm painting a beautiful mural an aero-graffitio visible from low orbit
I haven't really started it yet
I'm waiting for the right words
yeah okay you can't do shit so you don't know what to write
why are you so committed to do defacing the building
I have an opinion on this want to hear it
yeah
it's hooliganism yeah
fucking lock her up
be realistic what are you going to do climb up there
well I don't know Kim
yes
you heard your partner piggy
give me the gun back how about that
辛迪：没有人能够阻挡我
cuno put you on the end of the pecking order
you could barely keep above Kim
you know what
just because you're right doesn't make me happy about it
I don't condone the idea of using physical force on her
she's a girl
yeah girl first child second let's lock her up
watch your back ungulate
you've got eyes on you
an ungulate
who are you to deface the law that way
and fucking over it with these kids
okay
let's go investigate this fucking
this game is making
it's bringing out these fucking things in me these
these traits
my authority and my ego
it's weakening my ego making me vulgar
that's I need some more magnesium always
all right let's talk to this lady
the striking woman leans against the cabin top of her sailing boat
smiling as you approach
her green raincoat glistens with droplets
a silk scarf is tied around her throat
crime scene super cop Brady child listen here you little shit
yeah exactly with a child I'm like I lose all composure
good afternoon offices
I'm Joyce
不跟她握手...
Joyce L Messier
I represent the board of wild pines the owners of the harbor
you gentlemen must be finally an adult
终于来了个成年人
you know what
because everyone else has come at me so fucking sideways
I don't trust her earnestness alright
there's only one person's hand I'm shaking in this whole playthrough
and it's kims
don't shake her hand
I'm glad to see you here
not shaking anyone's hand
she is unfazed by your rudeness
probably chocking it up to local custom
yeah tell you the certain dominance
I was dispatched to handle a strike not a lynching
anything I can do to assist the RCM in this matter I will
what about Tommy
I think I don't know would I shake Tommy's hand
I'm still a little bruised up by the fact that he didn't give me a sig
I might give him like a solemn one of those
like that but I don't know if I would do
I want to know if I would go all the way to a handshake with Tommy
we need to get a little closer a little more acquainted first
that is good to hear madam
my colleague will take the lead on this interview
I should let you know that he is recovering from an
unusual medical episode
very unusual
but I can assure you of his ultimate competency
kids were rude to you now you're rude to her a cycle
a circle of rudeness exactly
I'm just giving out the same thing that I'm getting here
that's all what's happening
how interesting
I wish you a swift recovery
in the meanwhile you have my full cooperation
and the full cooperation of the wild pines group
it's hard to get a read on her precise disposition
but she appears helpful
she appears suspicious what does she know about the crime
I don't want to go so direct with the question yet
first I want to see where she's coming at
how much is she willing to divulge before I start pushing on her
（选项：说说野松公司 你们是做什么的）
what we do
I'm afraid I don't speak for wild pines as a whole
it is a giant undertaking
isn't that exactly what you do
you're the rep
（选项：所以 *他们*是做什么的）
the pines core competency is logistics
container shipping freight that sort of thing
see those air ships there blinking
those are the shipping side of things
and that is the terminal another subdivision deals with energy
oil and gas exploration offshore platforms
how much money you guys handled
I'm not at liberty to discuss the company balance sheet
but I can tell you that
last year the company booked more than 20 billion Real in revenue
you're right Tommy not giving me a sig was the failure on my part that's true
I've sort of neglected that point of it
because my perception was so bad that
despite him literally holding a cigarette
he was able to convince me that he doesn't smoke
a billion
it's a number officer a big one
it's a lot of smoke money why I failed punching Cuno
no that was not my fault
it's made of one thousand millions
a million is made of a thousand thousands
twenty billion is a large number
but the conglomerate employs 72000 people
they all need to be paid
then there are capital improvements interest payments
a conglomerate the size of the wild pines is like a shark
if it stops moving it will die
then what becomes of those 72000 families it's a tremendous responsibility
so where do you get all those buildings
they started as an exploration and cargo fleet
conducting trade between the Samaran and Insulindian isolas
250 years ago
when Pine's ships explored the south Semenese and charted Lo Manthang
on behalf of the suzarain
centuriea of care deliberation and madness have gone into this endeavour
足够了女士
坦白说吧 我对你讲的这些都不感兴趣
centuriea of care deliberation and madness have gone into this endeavour
vessels pass through the Great Unrest to re-emerge with apricots in tow
the logic of the system is totalizing
it's taken everything from its employees to build it
so what the fuck are you doing here
you mean aside from being the terminal's legal owners
who are responsible for moving eight percent of the world's cargo
eight percent of all cargo in the world
you don't keep it moving the workers do
yeah let's now that she's getting a little annoyed
that I asked her to explain to me what is a billion
and then what do you do with that money
let's let's keep going
we built this district
all the best parts of it
Rue de Saint-Ghislaine with its bastions
the plaza's Meteoran mosaic
even some of the old street lamps have been put back
thanks to the investments from the WP
before Martinez was swallowed by the Industrial Harbor
even before it was part of Revachol
long before Terminal B was erected here
the pines built it as a resort for its Revacholian employees
a company getaway for a weekend or a summer holiday
then came the revolution but that's another matter
I'm here to make sure the pines can fulfill their responsibilities
to the place they built
with your help hopefully
says her warm tone
let's just make a clear observation here
why yes I am
not a lot of people on boats are there
of course there are
we're on an archipelago
how else are you supposed to get around
what do you mean archipelago
I mean we are on Le Caillou are we not
we are and the city of Revachol is on the island of Le Caillou
still I haven't seen anyone else sail about around here
I haven't seen anyone else drive a souped-up
Coupris Kineema motor carriage either
actually that motor carriage has been specially issued
to serve as a patrol and pursued vehicle
it's for crossing long distances in the greater Revachol Industrial Harbor
金 金 金
it's not a toy
what are you doing
I thought you said I got this
neither is this
a toy I mean
it's a machine for crossing long distances in the bay of Revachol
between the city and the Islands
she's having a good time arguing against the law
too good perhaps
太超过了
authority you're starting to like really speak to my core here
do you have a license for this boat
officer I assure you
I'm a highly qualified pleasure craft operator
the crowns of her teeth are porcelain white as the boats howl as she smiles
qualified pleasure craft operator so charming
yeah where's their license give me the fucking proof
...safety inspection last month offices it is completely seaworthy
in fact it's taken part in not one but two insulindic regarters
even finished once
that's not enough I need to see
it really you don't
Kim
what are you doing
you said I got this you said be wacky
why is he getting in the way of this now
who benefits okay
where does Kim get his money
does he get it from wild pines
I police
this is a little known fact among those who police
that the Wayfarer Act specifically denies the RCM
the authority to demand anyone's operator license
Kim's only job at this point is to fucking
embarrass me in front of people
don't tell me that in private afterwards okay
don't ever ever discount my authority like that
in front of someone who I am interrogating okay
this is all part of the ploy
that's weak
unless it's their passport no
do you want to ask for the ladies
you need to save face if you want her respect
DEMAND that passport
I demand it give me the passport
the woman is silent smiling
while the waves lap against the hull
in your hand under the plastic
a light blue passport saying Republic of Vesper
the coat of arms has a lion and an ostrich sejant
he can he's completely undermining me okay
first he says take the lead
say whatever you want all you gotta do is get her talking
and then the second
I try to go down that path he's like actually
I'm gonna expose you for being ruthlessly stupid and unqualified to do this
the woman born in the year 3 in the commune of Revachol
smiles at you
face adorned with frown lines and crow's feet
the photo is recent
he's broken my trust
Rejoyce Layton-Messier
but I don't know what the law is look that doesn't matter okay
that doesn't matter cybercat
so you're from Vesper
my husband is
I have dual citizenship
a Vespertine is handier when traveling
I fucking hate this woman
你的名字叫雷乔伊斯？
yes but please don't call me that
Joyce is much more efficient
and yes if i dig into my own character psychology
the reason I hate her is because she makes me feel inadequate
she doesn't like it
probably a bad memory mean girls at school or some ancient lover
yeah we're gonna press on that later
she nods and returns the plastic bag to her coat
but it actually fits into my roleplay character
because the whole idea was
I'm not really someone who respects the law
I'm a failed therapist to became a cop
so that I could wield authority to people and get information out of them
and pretend to myself that I have a moral right to do it
so yes I don't need to know the law
I think I have a better opinion that the law demands I validate
it's just who I wish I could be yeah fucking
smoked out drugged up and very unapproachable
the boat no
it is called Cor-de-Leite 19 because that's the type of sloop it is
oh it's a sloop
it's a word it feels strange
such a beautiful boat deserves a proper name
a breeze ripples through the sails
对 快用天人感应甩我
and tugs at your hair
below the sleek fish like shape of the hull parts the water
beneath that a resounding darkness
you're reminded of something or someone
cool but your boat really needs a name
okay how about Cor-de-Leite 19 why
好无聊
because it was manufactured in Revachol east
by a company called Cor-de-Leite
and its hull is 19 paces long
how about the sleek fish
how about Dolores
why Dolores
well it means nothing to me
I think I'll stick with a factory name but thank you for the suggestion
it's a pleasure craft a 19 pacer
（选项：这是什么*类型*的船呢？）
it also happens to be rated for category 1 racing
though these days I may use it for business
my sloop I like it a lot
it's the eel's hips baby
I'm enjoying this part of the interview
it has so little to do with the murder we're investigating
Kim
can I fire Kim
this is a part of the investigation
okay I'm learning about
the person I'm canvassing the scene Kim
I'm scoping out fucking details that
you and your logic adult brain could never perceive okay
my brain is on like inland empire and shiver shit all right
it's pulling together like cosmic psychological archetypal information
from like everywhere around me
and you're just like why aren't you asking her if she knows about the crime
you fucking idiot
I'll teach him I'll teach him how to investigate
I really do the lieutenant thinks
is she thrown off yet
he's looking at the woman assessing her
good
all right
quite a few things follow
follow your lead Kim
just try punching Kim I should go for it
the information I'm to share with you
includes sensitive trade secrets
for the sake of my employer
I have to ask for your names and page numbers
so are you fucking kidding me
I can't scope a peep at her license
but I have to show her my badge
I don't have my badge
of course ma'am we should have introduced ourselves
I am lieutenant kitsuragi from precinct 57
and this is my colleague from precinct 41
I'm afraid he doesn't have his badge at the moment
I hope mine will suffice
Kim agrees with your method he's just playing good cop well look
I wouldn't have really really poor perception
if I didn't pick up on that
how does it benefit me to contradict me and embarrass me
in front of fucking Cuno and this
weird dame
how curious
why is that detective
我不接受提问
awkwardness washes over the conversation
the woman doesn't like this turn of events
I see so are you saying you
lost your badge during the course of this episode
I swear to god if she laughs at me
I am gonna ask for that gun back
let's go with the absurdist idea
乔伊斯：哦 *天啦*
I suppose this does explain some of the
more curious turns in our conversation
as I said ma'am his technique may be very inconventional
but he is an officer of RCM
of course I sympathize
but I'm afraid I simply can't share anything more
until I see that badge
see that technique that I just used right there is disarming her
see now she thinks I'm a bumbling idiot
who can't string together a coherent line of questioning
and that I am so hungover that I lost my badge
despite both of those things being true
she maybe will more
more vulnerable to my other techniques
look those two things can be true
and I can still use them to my advantage
hang on she's a professional negotiator
she should be open to some sort of mutually beneficial arrangement
（检定-循循善诱 ：我该如何通过谈判来解决这个问题？）
72 percent let's go easy
what the fuck
what did I tell you
every single time
17 percent yeah I'll pass that every time
anything higher than 50 you can guarantee I'm gonna fail it
I assure you it is no small matter for me either
we all share the responsibility for disarming this situation
I hope you have a badge for me as soon as possible
are you serious
I actually need to go get my badge
you have so much else
I only have this spread my hands
this is the entirety of my existence
that's quite the agents of change scene
or stop immediately doing checks
look I get excited
I saw the 72 percenter and I was like that's easy
（选项：我什么也没有 只剩下这个案子了）
officer
come on
I'm losing ground here
you know I don't mean to sound cold
but if you want something
you have to give something back more than just guilt
you're doing it
despite your own best efforts you're still getting in
I'll be frank with you
if I'm going to break protocol
I need to be able to justify it to my superiors
they're going to want to see something tangible
the union is conducting drug trade out of the Harbor
it's an open secret in Martinaise
surely it must not come as a complete surprise to the RCM either
perhaps it's time to look into it
or you can find your badge
which honestly seems like a lost cause
detective a word in private before we continue
okay what is it Kim
what do you got for me
honestly I was expecting you
to use your unorthodox technique to keep her off balance
and you know not putting tears to be her henchman
I thought it was going well
someone is running circles around us
she might have known about your misplaced badge all along
or she's simply an adept improviser
either way we've played straight into her hand
he doesn't let it show
but there is a limit to how much the consequences
of your unprofessional behavior can cost the investigation
look all I know is that things worked out very well when I had the gun
if you just give it back to me now
I think that we will be in much better circumstances
yeah I have to pay more attention to the red checks
I'll throw it back on Kim what do you
you think we shouldn't investigate drug trafficking
no if there is reasonable suspicion we must investigate
otherwise she could claim we are siding with the union
or that we are on their take
we'd never hear the end of it
she's really put us in a bind
what I propose is we ask her then we investigate briefly
but do not share the outcome of this investigation with her
we tell her it's done and demand for her information on the lynching
oh that would be fantastic
but do we have the time
the world is large and your badge is 8 by 6 centimeters
this logic that Kim is wielding against me
it's frustrating because he's right and I hate that
you could request a new one from your station
but that would literally take months
it would not hurt if you tried more in the future
okay Kim
now you're actually just trying to hurt my feelings
you're back good what can I help you with
乔伊斯：事情其实挺简单的
that's fucking investigate the drugs
someone is using Terminal B to smuggle raw ingredients
from the Samaran isola into Revachol with the union's blessing
wild pines has suspected it for years
what's amazing is how well this game is responding in every single circumstance
to my attempts to like subvert it and also to role play
like I can't believe how well it's responding to everything
and still keeping the narrative like consistent
like I can see that there's multiple branching paths
but the way this is being told to me feels like
this is the only one like it feels unique enough
which is crazy
ingredients for what
meth and dextroamphetamin
GBL and various synthetic psychedelics
honestly it might be quick to say what you can't make from the stuff
yes after they clear the terminal we lose track
the actual production is taking place
at various sites in and around Jamrock quarter
north of here
wildpine seems to be well apprised of the local direct trade ma'am
do you mean to see the union also produces the product
says drugs I mean
we're in logistics
it's our business to know
and no as far as the company knows the union does not produce it
they transport the ingredients for a cut
yeah that's what's crazy is like
I can imagine going a different route and
just a whole complete other turn of events taking place
yes but you won't get anything out of Evrart in the dockworkers union
still every chain has its weak link
mmm the bolt cutters
（乔伊斯：那些货車）
someone needs to move the ingredients from the harbor into the city
once they reach Jamrock
they're distributed to a network of local manufacturers
well beyond our grasp
but in transit they are vulnerable
perhaps you've noticed that a number of lorries are tangled
in a traffic jam at the roundabout just now
interview the drivers who are still hanging about
one of them might be waiting for a crucial shipment
她在说汤米？可能是汤米
I'll be explicit
if you find this driver
I will share company secrets with you
you'll be indebted to her in a way
but one step ahead of the union in another
it's a good point authority
no we asked East Motor Tract to raise the drawbridge
the road company is a partner of one of our subsidiaries
however this is a limited time opportunity
once the complaint has been processed by the trade committee
they'll have no choice but to lower the drawbridge
and the operation will continue
thousands of litres of raw ingredients will pour onto the streets of Revachol
not the east across the river
but the west the vulnerable the weary
cold breath rushes in from the bay
making its way down the alleyways and potholed streets
from Martinaise to Jamrock
in the traffic you hear the clinking of glass vials
concealed beneath tarpaulin
or is it just your teeth chattering in the cold
fucking misery
a lot of it it comes in from large Samaran factories
in south Safre Siigay and Hsin-Yao
the literage they must get from this terminal alone must be oceanic
well at least this solves one mystery
what is that lieutenant
why I had to call east moto tract and beg them to open a drawbridge for me
I had wonder since I first drove in on my motocarriage
I am sorry for the inconvenience lieutenant Kitsuragi
but we need them trapped here
this is a unique opportunity
I'm sure you understand
we are suspicious about a driver being present
that must be the racist guy
...might even be connected
or not though if you have evidence to the contrary
I'm eager to hear it
as eager as I am to share it
lieutenant once the job is done
excellent according to my reports
there are at least three lorry drivers lingering near the roundabout
hopefully one of them will know something
it may come to nothing or it may just blow the case wide open
I can keep the drawbridge up for a few more days at least
you should have the time you need
in the meantime let me know
if there's any other way I may be of assistance
that's the man who was killed
I'm afraid this is a discussion for once we've cleared the lynching question
乔伊斯：最好不要本末倒置
so you do know something
I hope there is something else I can help you with
she wants to answer the question
protocol keeps her from it
（选项：关于罢工你可以告诉我什么？）
everything right up to but not including trade secrets
first you'd have to repeal the Emergencies Act of Trade and Aliments
that gives me the right to silence it's quite the octopus
I am glad you see it that way
to repeal the act would mean repealing the coalition government
the one that leases you the right to police west Revachol
I don't like how it's much more capable of
speaking intellectually she is than my character
but I am derailing us
you wanted to know about the strike
she makes me feel incredibly inferior
I believe the official title is senior labor negotiator
in practice I'm a grocery clerk
I relay the union's demands to wild pines
and return with wild pine's counter-offer
and how are the talks going
they're not that's the problem
the union stopped all negotiations a week ago
after that awful lynching took place
now they won't even let me into the harbor
there's a 2.20m racist behemoth blocking the gates
yeah I know about that guy
what can I say
the union employs a giant covered in tattoos a racist giant
I guess that's part of their big tent organization now
let's say I was not making the kind of progress I'd hope for
when I first arrived
what's truly at fault is the system that gives her the right to silence exactly
maybe I could just take that crowbar and really pry the information out of it
and when did you first arrive
I arrived three weeks ago
yes in the middle of February
the bay was still partially frozen then
I prefer to do these things on site like the RCM
but the strike began in December
I wasn't the original negotiator here
I took over after Mr. Gaumont hit a wall with Mr. Clare the union boss
Mr. Clare refused to speak with Gaumont
despite concessions he granted the union in prior negotiations
this isn't the first time the union has gone on strike
heavens no there have been two prior strikes
both times the union won significant concessions
including overtime pay and a medical plan
this time their demands are more I guess you could say aggressive
tell me about the union boss
Evrart is a man of the utmost integrity
if you can say one thing about him
it's that he always puts the interests of the work
（选项：真的吗？）
of course not Evrart is fantastically corrupt
I imagine he has a thick viscous goo where you and I have blood
he is the most corrupt individual I have ever seen
and I deal with men like him for a living
if there is anyone more venal more irredeemably nepotistic
then it's his twin brother Edgar
yes Edgar looks exactly like his brother except for that lazy eye
he also talks exactly like Evrart does
and when one's term as foreman is up the other takes over
it's how they circumvent the term limits you see
with a funny little switcharoo
while in office they've embezzled god knows how much of their workers dues
what about the union itself
the union was once a perfectly normal institution
20 years ago anyway
it must not have been easy to establish under the emergency act
but they did it I can respect that
organized labour at its best as they say
then something happened in the local chapter elections
the brothers Claire came and transformed it into a
how do you say
a mob the Debardeurs are a crime syndicate
sad as it may be I suspect we'll be forced to cooperate with them
refreshingly honest officer
the company has tried appeasing in the past
but I'm afraid our concessions have only emboldened Evrart and his brother
well of course she's all like praiseworthy to Kim
and your opinion detective if I may ask
I'm a curious and talkative person you see
would you say the Debardeurs union is
I gonna be honest all of this stuff has gone way over my head so
I'm gonna remain neutral
of course officer
I just don't have an opinion
你说选举期间*发生过什么事情？
I'm glad you asked
there was a woman the previous forewoman of the union
she disappeared
disappeard
yes on the last day of the local chapter elections
her daughter phoned in and said she wasn't running anymore
or coming to work ever end of story
remain neutral
that is suspicious most likely extortion
indeed the company suspects foul play
but there's nothing they could do
it was a union matter
the point of the presentation is
these kinds of things happen around the Claiers
watch out when you're dealing with him
thank you for your concern ma'am we'll be just fine
there are leaflets everywhere and banners what did they say again
oh yes
every worker a member of the board
over aggressive commie posturing
seems like they have no idea
...another said demand democracy
pretty tame stuff compared to every worker a member of the board
fortunately they explained it
every time the wild pines group makes a decision about anything
it needs the signature of each of the 2200 workers in its Martinaise Terminal
just so you understand this is
but 1 of 22 terminals owned by wild pines
essentially not only are they kings of the company
they are also kings of the 72000 employees of wild pines group
I'm not sure
naturally I assume that was just their opening position
a hard nosed tactic with a side of mockery
but there's been no follow up
just the same nonsensical slogan repeated over and over again
and now people are getting lynched I hear
behind the whirling in rags
a disastrous situation if there ever was one
so my characters position on this is
at the end of the day he's a very self centered individual
and all this other shit is like all right well
this comes down to what I need
from this is how to move forward with my thing
so who do I get a squeeze
that's all I gotta know
excuse me from whom did you hear about is lynching
I first heard it from the boia at the gate
the one his very name advertises his aversion to work
I think he said it was call me Manana
this checks out
Mr. Claier told him to how did he put it fuck off midget
Gaumont is short of stature you see
yes keep in mind this is a negotiator Mr. Claier has worked with before
and who was more than fair with him and the union
sounds like usual aggressive posture
乔伊斯：当然 我能提供什么帮助
let's change the subject
of course detective
all right that was a lot of talking with her
I feel like she talks circles around me
let's get kim's impression on that
do I have a level up to do or something
no I don't okay
I did pick up some clothes though I wanted to see
yes now that's a fresh look
with the gloves and the crowbar
yes
what do you want to know
just wondering if he had anything to say about this exchange okay
so we're at another good stopping point for now
I found myself very sorely shown to be inadequate
in the one thing that my guy is supposed to be good at
which is like being persuasive and detecting things
and this posh lady just like talk circles around me
all right I found a thought in the thought cabinet
what is the thought cabinet
what is this
plus one empathy towards Kim kitsuragi
okay we'll investigate that next time
this game is a mountain of dialogue easy to get lost in
the dialogue is so good and every character is so well written
I think that part of the design is probably
like she hides her intentions behind her
intense knowledge of everything that's going on
and she's also an authority figure in a person of power as well
concealing character personalities within it as well yeah
and what I understand your character is desperate for authority and respect
in order to deflect from his inability to look at himself in the mirror yes
that's perfect
that's literally perfect because I didn't look in the mirror
his whole thing is like
what I am getting out of my character here is that
inland empire and shivers and this like perception rhetoric
he's able to collect knowledge about things like some supernatural
some very intuitive about people and his environment
but then he can't really do anything effectively with them
that's like my idea is that as a failed therapist
he didn't have enough empathy to know how to like help people
but  he was really good at detecting like
people's intentions and their personalities and things
he just didn't know how to like do anything with it and
so he thought maybe it's better to be a cop you know
maybe I can hide behind that like moral disposition
he's good observer
but not good at processing it I think
he's just not good at delivering on it
like he has all of this internal knowledge
that he can't seem to share with anyone
because people either don't get it or he doesn't know how to like use it to his advantage
and it just comes off like
bing a bit of bumbling and confusing
empathy is useful if you want to know the character
behind the mountain of dialogue yeah
can't even deliver a punch I know it's so pathetic
oh my god
he really is pathetic
okay
I think we'll pause it there for for disco elysium yeah
super excited to continue this playthrough
next time we'll investigate this union and
kind of see where things lead us there
bye thank you for watching
and I will see you next time with more disco