okay
hello
and welcome back to our uh
therapist plays Disco Elysium let's play series
if you are new here then hello welcome
my name is Brady I'm a therapist
and we are doing like kind of a long form
psychoanalysis of the main character
and his companions and all the people
that we meet on our journey through Revachol
so in today's episode
we're going to talk a lot about
like our main characters reflections on his own self identity
as we sort of start to unpack and discover
things that he is remembering about his past and
psychologically what does it mean to
integrate a past version of yourself who you may not
have a lot of positive feelings about
into the identity that you're building today
and also we're gonna see if we could take
another shot this whole thing with Cuno
so
let's dive in
now one thing that is a kind of a hanging thread is
I want to return to my bedroom while I'm here
we're playing the game like reading some
psychological class material
yeah if you're new to the eurobrady experience
this is one part entertainment
one part Masters level psychology lecture
one part my own
self therapy life
for your enjoyment
read the problem part let's do that
let's rewind let's trace your drunken steps back home
jump across the raised channel bridge southwest of here
fall over get up
get off the asphalt in 20 minutes
shuffle your feet through courtyards
scaring little children
that checks out
go under the great raised motor tract the 8/81
until you reach Le Domaine Aminol in north Jamrock
the streets are frozen this time of year caked with ice
walk down Main to Perdition
there's a side alley there
and your footprints in the mud
okay
there's something there
there is a past for me
okay
this
Kim also tries not to look at the pile of tape viscera on the carpet
or the weird suitcase on the hat rack
or the pottic plant dying in the corner
but it's all just too morbid to ignore
oh that's true
this is the first time I've brought Kim into the environment
maybe in a subconscious way I'm trying to understand again
how much can I destroy my own image to him
before I come to the conclusion that he's not going to abandon me
maybe if I show him
something intimate and disgusting about myself
maybe he will finally abandon me
he nods
nod stoically that sounds
he takes a step toward the door
like he'd like to leave
oh he's ashamed to be with me
I'm not finding a lot of security in him
I'm gonna be honest guys
I know Kim is a hype character
people have been really upset about how like
I'm not like taken to him so quickly but
psychologically speaking like everything that he does
is showing me that he does not like trust me
and that the only reason he's sticking with me
is because he needs something for me
the bed is cold and not particularly inviting
but it's yours
the sheets(look awful)
the option to go to sleep becomes available
every night after 9 PM
okay
okay let's see if I can get my tie down and
wait
was there
there's something I could do to like
try this again right
yeah the ceiling fan
sevoir fair that's what I need
I'm still not very good at this
this fan has two chain pull switches
one ends in a tiny fan the other in a light bulb
a truly horrific neck tire somehow attached itself to one of the blades
or has it been consigned there as punishment
okay we saw this(before)
you feel as though this creature is your friend
and wants to reattach itself to your neck
so that you may continue your adventures together in this strange world
okay last time we tried to just get the tie and it did not work
let's try
turning the fan off
(The blades)come squeaking into a holt
it should be easier to reach the tie now
okay 72 percent
there's no way I can fail this right
you swoop up and catch the tie snap
it's released from the blade
the luck continues
warning warning
the necktie is no longer contained
what you have in your hand is a fantastically colorful tie
with four or five different patterns
(The)knot reminds you of a noose
okay we've got a tie
it is
it's there it's on
let's go scope on that
that tie there
no I want to keep I want to keep the crowbar
where's the tie
oh there it is
the necktie is adorned with a garnish a garish pattern
it's disturbingly vivid
somehow you feel as if it will be wrong to ever take it off
it's your friend now
you will betray it if you change it for some boring scarf
okay
and I guess I guess I could look in the mirror
I'll tell you what
narratively speaking
if I'm just going by role play
after my interaction with Lana
the sweet grandma in the wheelchair
I'm suddenly feeling like I can humanize myself a little bit more
than I could at the beginning of this playthrough
and I finally feel secure enough to look at my own countenance
lets do that now
a mirror hangs on the wall covered in steam
you cannot see yourself
just the outlines of a man
you have no memory of the face that awaits you there
underneath the soft vapor
well and we are trying to figure out now who we are
as you slowly reach your hand towards the surface of the mirror
abort you clearly have not thought this through
you won't like what you see there
and you will never unbecome it
okay Inland Empire again
another competing mental state that is coming in to tell me
there is a concern that I am not ready for this
right now what my character is wanting
is a way to connect his past self
but this would invite me to reflect on my present self
who I have not decided if I like very much yet
this is a big risky move
maybe I should touch it first
make sure there's nothing wrong with my face
yeah there is definitely something wrong with it
maybe it's okay to continue living in denial for now
where to even begin
there is the bloatedness
then the swollenness
it's like there's an upholstery of alcohol underneath your skin
I'm scared I want to stop doing this
I'm sorry at least my tongue is okay
there's a lot of anxiety
bet you are
your nose feels like a small balloon in the middle of your face
it hurts when you honk it
it doesn't appear to be a particularly tiny nose either
not with all the drinks it's absorbed for you
at least my tongue is okay
it's not
(It's)swollen and snail like wriggling between your fingers
don't be scared
it's only your face
it's not like anyone's going to see it
okay everything about this is telling me that
I do not feel comfortable doing this yet
from a character perspective I'm not doing it
there's something this like
there's something that tells me not to right now
my character is not ready yet
he's
I already came back for the tie all right
that's a big step for me to start retracing my steps
and like showing interest
some discomfort is good absolutely
but
I feel like that would be too much of a confrontation to myself
yeah I gotta go through a character arc first
I hope you guys understand like
I intend to role play this the entire way through
someone is working let's check this out
we got in the sink
tomato
that's not good
a thin man is smoking below an exhaust hood
occasionally sipping from his mug
this must be the Whirlings cook
he's got a cigarette
okay
this is my moment all right
I have failed at every opportunity to stimulate myself
maybe if I had a cig I'd be okay looking at myself in the mirror
maybe this is the time
all right all right
I gotta prepare myself
this is this I cannot fail this one
as you step in
he nods toward the table
and says something in a completely foreign language
the only words you can make out are 'goracy' and 'kubek'
okay there is a language barrier
but there is a universal understanding
of the sweet nicotine release
that that a man who is too tired for his own life
would get from a sweet drug
it must be his name Goracy
Goracy Kubek
sounds representative
my logic side is so stupid
okay do I want to establish a power dynamic right
my character is very much like
authority oriented everything is about a power dynamic
so
I already feel inferior by not understanding his language
that reminds me of how insecure I am
about where I have ended up in the world
and why I don't remember things
so it makes sense for me to want to establish power over him
by saying you know I have an authority role
the man puts his cup down and replies something
his left hand drawing arcs in the air
you've got some impressive pots there
he smiles and bangs his ladle against each of his pots in turn
what
no I I do need something
no I
the man ponders his cooking utensils and
fuck
acknowledging your presence
I can't
he smiles and
I can't ask him for a cig
God damn it he doesn't understand me
steel door with
you immediately feel drawn to the color
blue is for mystery
oh I wonder where this door leads
you do
it's a door in the back of the kitchen
why do you care where it leads
I'm drawn to its cobalt blue Kim
you would know that if you
had any interest in understanding me
it is quite pretty
I suppose we could look into it as a side investigation
yes a mini side-investigation
I'm trying to see how much you're willing to put up
(Garte)the person to ask this the cafeteria manager
I want to touch the door
the cobalt blue surface feels rough to touch
the stainless steel door is flush with its frame on every side
I want to push the door
door does not budge
I have to leave the door for now
let's see what Garte has to say about it
can I help you
another thing great
I oh yes that door sure
there's nothing mysterious about it
it's just a door
do you know what's behind it
no I don't have a key
I don't know how to get there
and I don't care either
it's not like I've been wondering about it for 10 years
it's just a Frittte warehouse probably
or some boring storage space with a bunch of old junk and dust
junk and dust
he's attempting to maintain an air of indifference
it's absolutely not convincing
I think he I I
let him get to pretend it's indifferent okay
power dynamics it's all about staying composed
he looks at the dust on his finger and wipes it off
okay we'll leave it for now
I do not trust him
all right let's blow this joint wait who's this gentleman
that sugary black rum stain on the counter
makes you teary eyed with joy
it's almost touched in how syrupy and sticky it is
how long have you been up already
it's drink o'clock
my character is probably
probably hounding for something here
atta boy it's coming back to him
you had your mesolympic reward pathway worried there
not thinking about drinking all that time
it was like you weren't yourself
yep
there's a competing mental state here
this one is so powerful
that it's able to wrench me from my construction of identity
actually I should be thinking about this
drinking hasn't turned out too well from me
I want to say this
but I don't know if my character has that insight yet
I do need a rum in lemonade
I love fregart to serve me up a beverage
he did say the drinks were on him let's see what
or don't forget about it
you should totally try to get a drink there too
but first
I can do both
lick that stain off the counter
yeah man let's get wild lick it
let's go halfway there
calmly the lieutenant looks out of the window
then to you
licking the tasty rum state off the counter but only a little
then out of the window again
what are you doing
investigating
we should move
a real drink would go well
with those cigarettes you're looking for
that's a great combination
it knows it knows what I'm looking for
it's all about money you know who benefits
okay let's uh let's get out of here
I don't think I can get a drink right now
don't give in
okay what were we doing
I spent a long time in there
sort of reflecting on my entire world view and sense of self
and whether or not I feel comfortable with this person
I've been traveling with and
what are his motivations for being with me
we've gotten very introspective in the whirling in rags
there's a nostalgic sense I'll always feel towards this place
now having gone through that mental adventure in there
it only took us like 10 hours to get to that point
yeah welcome to welcome to the year of Brady experience
oh my God so many things to do
I'm never gonna complete this game
open the trash container let's start with this
there's a lock trash container behind the whirling in(rags)
I need clear directions
let's go check out the trash okay
I'm a little scared to see Cuno again
but I'm hoping that like
now that I have this pretty cool tie on
maybe he either won't recognize me or he'll think I'm cool
let's check out the trash can
let's go scope on that
this trash container is locked
the sliding lid has a padlock that says whirling-in-rags
with a well oiled crack the lock pops open
it should now be possible to simply raise the lid
and see this is a point
where I in the process of therapy with my character
would find it very important to highlight what he just did right
through elements of deduction
through elements of empathy
through basically an apology to the person that
he slipped out on before
he managed to get a key
and this has pushed forward his investigation
this should absolutely reinforce his self esteem
excuse me
his  self esteem
but I would find it very common
for the character to not see it that way
the narrative that he's going to be telling himself is rather that
every achievement I have is based on luck
but every bad thing that happens to me is a character defect
that's a very common framework for someone who
is either depressed or critically lacking self esteem right
and so I would want to make a very special notice of
like this is a win
this is an achievement that you've gotten to
based on your skill set and
your ability to read and understand people right
it's not for me to interpret that for him
I would have to engage him with questions
like what was it like for you to finally open the trash can
well I you know I I was
I was pissed off because I couldn't open it before
okay so he's getting in touch with the anger
instead of the sense of gratitude towards himself
we're not quite there
right I might need to ask a different way of this
so when you got the key from Garte right
what did that tell you about him as a person
right I'm trying to get him closer to
more of an apathetic response right
those are the kinds of questions that I might start
engaging with him
because it's not my role as a therapist
to interpret positive narratives for people
that's like not the goal
the goal is to help you develop a not always positive
but realistic framework about yourself right
I would much rather you feel
like conflicted but realistic
about what's happening around you
than wholly positive
because then we're just being delusional
telling ourselves that everything is great and
we're a fucking great cop and great person
like that's not what that's not real either right
I don't want I don't want to replace reality with just positivity
I want to find a healthy middle ground
don't maybe you shouldn't
didn't I just have a premonition that
there's something in there
there is but you won't like it
sweat forms on your brow
your hand is still on the lid
I'm gonna open it
the smell of rotten food rises to greet you
you see soggy cartons dirty rags
and organic waste
okay
we're just in time
this hasn't been emptied for over a week
let's check out the cartons first
milk and egg rest with one broken egg in it
some pasta wrapper
picking up the soggy packages somehow feels familiar
a box falls into pieces in your hands
Batise Soleil cereal
there are plastic pasta packages below
and turbo noodles
nothing of note however
okay let's check out those rags
maybe there's something interesting there
among the threadbare kitchen towels
something catches your eye
a pair of denim trousers
get 'em
as the legs of the slime covered jeans begin to unspool from the garbage
a rank corpse smell fills the air
the victim's clothes
cadaverine odour is faint
if this belonged to the deceased
they were removed when he was still in the early stages of decay
drop them in here officer
let's bag those trousers
guitar mark blue jeans
pockets empty or emptied
he wore them with a belt too
a wide belt
the loops appear stretched but
the belt is missing
that's it
do you see anything else in there
I have another bag here
something slimy catches your eye
a drab long sleeved shirt olive coloured
appears from the food waste dripping with pus
this is a military type over-garment
no label or serial number
this is the kind of rib-knit shirt that's worn over light armour
to conceal it in an urban scenario
the rest of the rags are just kitchen variety waste
a yellow old mug that catches your eye
but other than that
all right we should go to Garte again
and ask if he knows who put your clothes in the trash
it could be as simple as someone from the hostel cleaning the yard
or that one
I'd advise against confronting that force
another encounter with Cuno
we need to ask the kids who put them here
I'm not satisfied by the last time
I encountered him
oh yeah thank god I have the garden gloves
I don't even think of that
I'm stumbling my way through success again
the fuck's he on about kids
you hear that Cuno
he thinks you're an infant or something
see
not really
all we know is the victim's clothes are in the trash
the lid was locked and this establishment had the key
it's just a small loose thread
the lieutenant nods
then looks back into the trash container
let's check out that food waste
it's just organic waste cold and slimy on your hands
apple and potato peels mostly
unidentified sludge
and the occasional chicken bow thrown in for good measure
but hey
nothing it's nothing
nothing more to see here
what's this
oh what is it
a blue piece of plastic sticks out from the apple peels
it's shiny
looks like the corner of something
something larger
a clipboard
a blue plastic clipboard
with moist papers hanging from it
they look badly damaged
but you can still make out forms and notes
written in a man's handwriting
okay that's clue
officer is that your paperwork
oh shit
it is look
the plastic has the RCM street grid on it
you've even got an autopsy form in there
wait a second fucking
the Inland Empire is supposed to be my boy
it's supposed to have never steered me wrong
what is Inland Empire
why is it trying to keep me from my own identity
does it have a motive of keeping me
as a blank slate
because in its cosmic desires
it can imprint upon me any sort of personality it desires
and that if I were to regain my own memories
it would have no place to influence my decisions
because I would have characteristics of my own
who benefits
if you don't mind my asking
how could you have let your paperwork end up in the trash
why was I in the trash that's a question
think I didn't want to be a cop anymore maybe
well
his eyes express a rare condolence
then he picks it up
maybe Kim does not want to be a cop either
maybe this is the only way he knows how to
apply himself as well is by being a cop
if you put Kim in a different position
would he have the same level of conviction
or the authority to act on those convictions
probably not
does Kim work as a cop because he wants to help people
or because it gives him a purpose
is it out of self interest
or is it out of
a desire to right the wrongs of the world
I guess we'll find out
lucky we found it
you should take stock of what remains
just to be sure some has not made it
into the hands of the RCM's adversaries
organized crime and the like
there might have been police secrets in your notes
okay I'll do that
it would also not hurt to start taking notes on the case
now tell me what your eagle eyes see
or are we finished
I got the eagle eyes
some items such as the ledger you found are interactable
go to your inventory
and select the Interact tab to read your paperwork
okay
you pick out a broken mug
with an oddly racist depiction of the yellow man frolicking in saffron
only in its social sensibility
the container sounds of muffled gong
okay well that was insightful
that's one thing of the least
I think we got it all
okay
so we've done we've accomplished one thing so far
let's check out that mug
it's just a racist mug
what's there to read here
not much
let's look at all that content I mean
oh boy
here we go
what are you going to say about
a broken tossed away mug that you dug out of the garbage
this mug is an example of prejudice
I'm going to use it as an example of what not to do
push this into the face of every merchant I find
and tell them this is your inane ideology
by denouncing it I can earn political capital
to mask my badass hustling
the mug didn't belong in the trash
it's just a funny mug
yes I think
I think I will use this as a
as a sign of gaining influence over others
if you want to earn some change by guilting people
go for it
but if you want to earn real dough
finish the case and start getting paid again
fuck okay fine
let's check this out
it's the ledger you found in the trash
a pitiful cabbage of white and yellow papers hanging from plastic board
barely held together by a metal clip
this sad display is made complete by the faint smell of urinal cleaner
there is a piece of toilet paper
or is it cleaning tissue
no it's toilet paper
desperately stick into the back of the blue plastic clipboard
it's a metaphor for you
below the pathetics terror
do not look into its blue heart
okay the Inland Empire is starting to get suspicious to me
why doesn't it want me to figure out who I was
let's check out that toilet paper
it's just toilet paper
stick it to the back of the plastic clipboard
you can take it off if you want
maybe it's kitchen tissue
if you want it to be kitchen tissue
it can be kitchen tissue
it's not though it's toilet paper
okay let's take it off
leave it there it's cool
I'll take it
still wet the toilet paper I mean kitchen tissue sorry
peels off the plastic easily
leave it
all you have to do is shake it off your finger and
voila the legend now looks marginally better
okay let's take a look at that clip
an aluminium block runs the width of the board
biting down on the paperwork
its crocodile teeth are the only thing keeping the papers together
a regular pencil the tip worn down to nothing
has been attached to the clip
the surface is interrupted by a silvery sticker
it's rectangular sparkling with iridescence
you don't know how you didn't notice it before
what's this
that thing it's a halogen watermark
we use it for adding information to RCM property
what kind of information
it depends aside from an anti-counterfeiting stamp
mine has my station number and address
the information varies by date of issue
how many years you've been on the force he's thinking
it'll have that
how can I be
any capable light with the right wavelength will do
okay
all RCM vehicles have had lights designed to
reveal illusion watermarks mine too
so maybe I could actually find out what my address is
if this has some of that information on it
this means you can read the watermarks
if you just turn the lights on
okay
while a bunch of sodden papers sag from the clipboard in your hand
it's a sorry sight
let's look at the clipboard
it's made of dark blue plastic
hard enough to beat someone to submission with
the edges are rounded however
the U4 size board feels thick and heavy in your hand
light shimmers on its wet surface
on the back you see the embossed letters RCM
hmm let's shake it
something rattles inside
ever so lightly
peek inside
the plastic shimmers like lapis lazuli
but it is not see through
you cannot see to its center
blue
something about the color blue is important
don't look into it
I'm gonna look into it
I'm not trusting Inland Empire anymore
with your hands
U4 sized pages hang from the clip screwed to the top of the board
oh boy okay
I should try
I should probably do more dialogue first right
every time I see one of these I just want to go right into it
they're not exactly white
they're yellowed in patches by sunlight and alcohol
and covered in dense blue handwriting
ink escapes into watercolor patterns
reaching its tendrils across entire pages
the paper itself is chequered
with faint red lines forming short paragraphs
once in a while there's a red stamp
that exclaims case files commit to paper
the case files themselves are plenty
you count more than 100 sodden crumpled up earmarked pages
falling apart in your hands
they appear to be sufficiently organized
and extremely dense
if mostly illegible
let's check them out
work strife poverty the Jamrock Quarter
these are handwritten logs of investigations
dating back to January 51
this year
the exact number is hard to estimate due to missing pages
and an odd nameing convention
but there are at least 20
maybe 30 cases
undertaken not completed mind you
okay this is actually really interesting for like
again I'm imagining I'm the therapist of my character
let's imagine the content of our session is
he brings in this clip board
it's got all these things on it
it's got artifacts of who he was on it and
we might be able to investigate
and say like
not what can we figure out from it because like
the goal of therapy is not to be
it's not always to
necessarily intellectually understand something
it's to process reactions to things
so the question I might have for him is like
what did you feel when you were looking at this right
and I could imagine him saying well it was confusing
right
what was it like to see
that the way you organized yourself was very
disruptive even before you lost your memory because
there are missing pages
there's odd naming conventions
there's all these undertaken quests that aren't complete
just like the play through we're doing right now
like I would
I would be less invested in trying to get him to puzzle out what happened
and more presently what is your reaction to seeing this right
because to me it seems like the person he was is not
too dissimilar to who he is
meaning that losing his memory did not erase
his personality or his way of organizing the world
it's this is exactly like how our current character is
like look at this shit
look at all these fucking things
look at all these like tasks we've undertaken
and done nothing on them
yes it appears you employer
shall we say robust yet literary system
each investigation has its case number written on the margins
yet still more tellingly most accompanied by a name
and for a lot of that practice
what I'm trying to do is get the character
or the client to empathize with themselves
I might ask him what do you think about the person who wrote this
well he seems like a mess
what does it mean to be a mess
well it's someone I don't have a lot of respect for
how can they live their life like that
it's also someone I can relate to right
what I'm looking for is a way to empathize with the self
because the self relationship is the core of why
this character feels detached and
it's all the reasons why every time Lena was praising him he like
minimized that praise and was like yeah
oh I look like shit
no I'm not a real cop
this world isn't even structured around having cops
the political system isn't even equipped for it
like he found all these ways to minimize
the way she praised him
because he doesn't care enough about himself right
so that would be one of my goals as the therapist
is like
this would be a great opportunity to start working on that
is how do we empathize with the person who wrote this
this stuff and like you know threw it away
yes all caps
one is called THE NEXT WORLD MURAL
another THE SQUARE BULLET HOLE MUDERS
another yet THE UNSOLVEABLE CASE
others appear more light hearted
THE GUYS ON A COUCH IN AN UNEXPECTED LOCATION
and TEH MURDER AT THE HOOKAH PARLOUR
even the rare article free COLLAPSING TENEMENT
murder features prominently throughout
it's time to take an effort to piece these case files together
but it can be done
once you're done inspecting them up close
Kim my cases appear to employ some kind of naming convention
let's get Kim involved
you mean the alfanimeric
officer precinct time of arrival at the scene
a non numeric one with titles
oh you mean the titular
yes well so do I
in our defense almost everyone in the RCM does
it's a holdover from the early days of the RCM
right after the revolution
when the organization had little idea how to do things
it persists in an unofficial capacity
officers use these titles to refer to their work among themselves
I seem to have named a case the Square Bullet Hole Murderers
again in your defense
I seem to have named one
the man with the hole in his head
that was a real person
his death was real
still I named it that
to amuse myself
to amuse yourself
once again Kim's personality sneaking through
I pray his loved ones never find out
rails spike through the head
he died it was a workplace accident
I have to open an official case is there room
there is for precisely one more
15 pages near the end remain untouched by the damage
the checkered grid forms a structure of passages
breaking the case into sub-tasks to accomplish
commit to paper
the tasks you've completed
flow out of the pen in a brash free hand
similar to the rest of the letters
the wording comes easily
it's almost robotically simple
a language developed for mental rigor and simplicity
inspect the victim's body
get the body down
interview the cafeteria manager
we done all that
a satisfying slash sounds across the paper
you're done it seems to say
and you
fucking yes we are we are reinforcing accomplishments
in a satisfying way
this is good for us
things to be done and things already done
the composition of reality
this is an extremely useful tool for a detective of the Citizens Militia
now all that remains is to name the case
let's do it
no actually any ideas
the furies are at home in the mirror
that is what the opening line of this game was
the Hanged Man the setting sun shit on a stick
let's see what some of those other names were
let's pick one that's pretty fitting
the guys on a couch in an unexpected location
the murderer the hookah parlor collapsing tenement
feel like this is the most realistic one
for my guy
it's simple it's as simple as like
like the robotic wording here
this is a little too like this would be for me
so let's go with this one
great that's great
that's actually what I was thinking too
the hangman
good strong name
we have a very good name for the case now
wait a second I'm feeling
I'm feeling
strangely comfortable around Kim after this interaction
his admission that he also names things in a weird way
that doesn't always make sense
and that he does so at the expense of
empathy towards the people involved in the case
is something I can relate to
and now that he is telling me
that this is a good pick for it
maybe he's just doing it because he wants me to relate to him
maybe he's just trying to get me to trust him
I don't know I don't know guys
I'm starting to feel like
I want to trust him
I want to believe
that what I'm feeling towards him is true
I'm just not ready yet
I'm scared
I'm going to start calling it the Hanged Man
it's good we sorted this out
I don't know guys
there's something here I feel conflicted
I want to trust you Kim
you don't exactly *close* them
so much as a *distance* yourself from the smelly papers
they're a little further from your nose now
can I read the case files now probably not
can't do that one either
let's uh let's check out those yellow papers
in the back you see thin translucent copy of paper
some neon yellow
some bright red
all covered in boxes like marching armies
these look like official forms waiting to be filled out
Three the topmost are misconduct finds
the middle ones are station calls
and the bottommost are field autopsy forms
each is easy enough to make sense of
all right let's check them out
misconduct fine
a monetary penalization ranging from 20 to 250 real
severe cases allow for 1000 real
but that requires special paperwork
the details of issuing these finds are spread out
over the rest of the fields
wait a misconduct fine
these are quite sinister in tone
they give a date and time for the person to 'appear'
at the specified precinct police station
below the 'call'
are the criminal charges you risk by 'not appearing'
a dozen pages of thin copy paper
bright red in colour
you see the parameters of a deceased human form
waiting to be filled in
age sex condition of internal organs
so these are all like blank pages
waiting to be filled out
okay yeah these are like empty forms
predation marks
condition of sexual organs
"close"
all that remains now
is to fill those forms and *hand* them to people
fines for wrongdoers
oh let's fucking fine all the children
and field autopsies to dead guys
what delicious power hid within this pathetic mess
you feel better
I do feel better
thank you authority
I feel a sense of authority over my own past
and interpretation of how to integrate it with my presence
the rest of the stinking cellulose is much worse for wear
being sandwiched between the board and the rest of the paperwork
must have spared the fragile copier paper
let's give that ledger a smell
the acidic stench of rotting food
has rubbed off on the cellulose
it now forms the *base* of the experience
this base surrounded by a faint air of spoiled meat
the stuff of death itself
and then sprinkled liberally
with the citrus zest of toilet cleaner
you don't exactly close them
so much as it distance yourself from the smelly papers
they're a little further from your nose now
uh 28%
I mean I've got Kim's confidence he explained it to me
I can retry this one
I think I'm gonna go for the logic check
it's proving to be harder than expected
you just don't have the intellectual rigor to patch the quilt
my guy is an idiot
this is a white check as well
open the hidden compartment
let's see if we can pry that boy open
it is *not* what you end up doing
you squeeze the plastic to slide it open
but nothing happens
then you bend it some
then crack it
the goddamn thing is stuck
the Ledger quivers in your hand
as it shakes the pages rustle
this pathetic mess suddenly afraid of you for some reason
no my streamer luck is probably still intact
these are like not super challenging ones
watch me get like a 3 percenter correct
oh I actually have a skill point
what did I need for that interfacing
I don't think I need to open this thing right now though
I'm kind of curious what I should do
kind of feeling like
authority and empathy are my two most interesting
outlets for understanding people
get that authority empathy over inland empire
that's exactly what I'm thinking right
if I'm going with a role play right like again
for those of you who are watching on YouTube as well
my goal is not to play this the most optimal way
I'm gonna miss out on shit
I'm going for comedy value more than anything
and like interesting character interactions
and to me
what resonates with the character I'm playing is
like I said someone who has severe trauma
and sees the world in terms of power dynamics
so I am thinking
I want a level of authority
even if it's not good for me
okay let's
let's ask Cuno what's up
it's been a while
look C it's the fucking war-pig
try not to knock yourself f****t
you belittled yourself before the Cuno
now you must seek his forgiveness
I've just leveled up my authority so
I want to make this right with Cuno make amends
let's try to put ourselves on an even power dynamic
Ame-fucking-what pig
it may not look like it now
but you may have vital information
I was trying I was wrong to try to hit you
I bet no one in his life has ever said that to him
yeah
how are you going to make it up to Cuno pigshit
let's give him let's give him free rein over this
how do you want me to make it up
please don't waste time on nonsense
Kim this is important to me
the lieutenant does not approve of this at all
I don't care
look in a displaced act of anger
I tried to hit Cuno
because I could not deal with my anger at myself of
how unhappy I am with the world
and so I drank myself into oblivion
tried to erase my past
and now I'm desperately trying to figure it out again
and in that confusion I swung at someone
and gave them an emotion that didn't belong to them
I'm trying to make things right Kim
if you want me to be at my best as a detective
I need to do this
don't listen to the blind fuck piggo
you're doing the right thing here
trying to get Cuno to like you again
yes（个鬼啊）
you can pay tribute to Cuno with drugs
or cigarettes or some wheels
Cuno could use some wheels
motorized cabbage shit
okay maybe if I get some cigarettes
I can share one with them
I need to make truce with Cuno offer him something
no you really really don't
that is a 12 year old boy
his opinion of you doesn't matter
ah so maybe there's a schema
which is like a mental blueprint for Kim
that the opinions of children don't matter
I wonder where that comes from
what opinion of yours
did you have as a 12 year old that no one gave any attention to
Mr Kitsuragi
I got your number
you don't fucking matter Book-gimp
I'm gonna mark it down as something I need to do
I'm telling you I look
I know how to spot trauma miles away okay
Kim was a child who
never learned that that his opinion mattered
and so of course he's gonna look a Cuno and say
yeah don't bother with this kid
he sees himself
but but why you're turning this into a huge thing
I'm punching someone always ends up someone's bitch
don't you know anything about male power structures Kim
it's just very hard for me to let things go
I know it doesn't matter but I need to make this right
yes
okay if you absolutely *need* to
I absolutely need to this is part of my healing
if you want me to be my best detective
I need to do this
okay
we we got into the trash can we got some notes
let's uh let's go confront the lorry driver
I'm pretty sure that's what I needed to do next
I need to bust down this union
oh I that's right I didn't talk to the girl
maybe she knows how I can make things right with Cuno
this is the most important thing to me right now
Cuno the pig's getting pretty close to me
come to snuff my shit out I think
looks like it's time for me to go Cuno
pigs come to take me in
I just want to ask you some questions
I'm going away for a long long time Cuno
going away for life
what's going on there
fuck are you trying to pull pig
what are those strange words you use girl
I come from the woods kytta vittu
you don't want to go there with me
you don't want to see what I've seen
don't be traumatizing here
get the fuck out of here
okay
all right
look I can't I want to get on Cunos bad side already
he already beat me up once
I'm trying to make amends with him here
let's go
let's go up north here and see what's going on
look what you can't say about Cuno is that he's not loyal
looking for something runt
come to tell me to fuck off again
I found this mug in the trash yours
oh man
that's great look at that guy go
I haven't seen anything that funny in a while
is it yours
God damn
thanks for that but no
no it's not mine
fuck
let me see the soles of your boots
been admiring the stompers runt for sure
I can *demonstrate* them
on the bottom of the man's boots
you see an intricate tangle of treads
with no immediately discernible pattern
wind howls over the Bay of Revachol
a cascade of cold air flowing through the city streets
those same streets have left their share of scuff marks
on the underside of your green snake's skinned shoes
is that a map of Revachol
it sure is
where did you get boots like that
custom-made cost me a pretty penny
but why
you'll see when the time comes officer
*true* patriots carry Revachol in their very soles
technically
you're stomping on Revachol every step you take
I know you people don't understand *poetry*
what are you hauling in those lorries
not much anymore
I'm here to pick up some cargo
but the workers are on strike so
it's a sit-and-wait-on-your-ass situation
how long has the strike been going on
I'd have been at it for a while
a month two months maybe
but this here is just the last week or so
all right
what kind of cargo he's supposed to be doing
yeah apples I take it you had other questions
he's given you the run-around
let's be honest
you were bested
fuck off
rhetoric I know that
what's your stance on drugs
I don't let anything pollute my body
you know where that she comes from
he's got a cigarette
they take the money from our local junkies here
and then use it to out-compete us
in the manufacturing sector
they know they can't beat us in a fair fight
so they have to get us to weaken ourselves somehow
it's racial sabotage racial *economic* sabotage
he's not gonna just
he's not gonna respond well
if I just confront him let's just
he eyes you warily unsure how to respond
this goes on for about two seconds
I don't know shit
if I did I wouldn't tell you
what are you still hanging around here for
what do you think I can't leave the lorry unguarded
stuff's been getting looted lately
is those little kipts sneaking around at night
if they touch my stuff
the bosses will be on my ass like as cancer
there was a bunch of spilled boxes in the back of a big lorry nearby
I did see one lorry with the trailer doors open on my way here
do you know what happened
I knew that guy
he was an honest driver who loved his country
we were having a good debate about genetics
at the Whirling-in-Rags
when some kipt-boys smashed his lock
and took them near everything
lost his fucking job over it
since he left him I haven't had anyone to talk to
bad for him I guess
I could just ask him who's running drugs what
I know he's not gonna give me a real answer
I just want to see how he reacts
isn't it obvious
fuckin 'Siileng that beady-eyed South-Samaran
his little side business is a scam
I wouldn't be surprised if he was pedding drugs as well
he's the Samaran guy
who likes to pretend he's some kind of businessman
oh it is he's just selling his employer's stuff
stuff he *stole*
after he broke the seals on his Humanox lorry
alright where do I find this guy
just follow the smell
it smells like apricots and *oil* when you're nearby
yes yes where is he
looks like I offended your partner there
too bad Siileng's usually a little bit south of here
near the canal
you can't miss him
just watch yourselves
his tribe are natural liars
it's in their blood
he's your man alright 100%
I wouldn't be so sure about it
not until we've heard what siileng himself has to say
goddamn another thing I have to do
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it consider giving it a like
and letting me know what you thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a little bit earlier
if you support the channel
either through Twitch or Patreon
links to both of those and the community discord are in the description
thanks again and I will see you next time
bye