okay
hello and also welcome
it's great to be back on stream
and continuing our Disco Elysium play through
if you're just joining us
which is a good chance that you are
this is kind of still at the beginning of our little play through here
and what we're doing is we're kind of playing through it like
mix of role play mix of psychoanalysis
I'm Brady I'm a therapist
and I'm going to be doing different kinds of
psychoanalysis on the characters
and kind of linking that to the game design
and like how it represents mental health
this game is just in another league
when it comes to that sort of thing so far like
I already did a video
kind of talking about the skill system and how it represents this like
very fascinating way to perceive like
motivation and psychological priority
so yeah we're like
we're gonna get pretty deep with this
the last two playthroughs or last two streams
I'm sort of just been figuring out the game and
now that I've like had some time to collect some thoughts on it
I'll be talking a little bit more about the
the characters and their dynamics and
like I guess why my character specifically is
showing a lot of avoidance and confrontation and like
is not maybe making some of the best decisions
I'm doing like a mix of my own headcanon role play like
I'm not trying to play the game the best way
honestly I'm just trying to make this fun
a fun play through like just kind of doing wild shit
we're not going to see every single part of the game
or every dialogue tree
and that's okay you know
but it has been great to get some recommendations
for things that like I just straight out missed
because of like
so far my character has just fallen into like
he's just failing upwards basically
like passing some of the early skill checks
some of the comments on the last video were telling me that like
missing or succeeding in some of these early skill checks has like
made me skip over a lot of tutorials
which makes sense
because I kind of feel lost on some of the systems
but that's okay
we're discovering it as we go
and I think that just makes for interesting play through dynamics
what I have been fascinated by is how well
the game has responded to my
weird way of approaching
it's completely fine that I skipped certain things
it's completely fine
that I don't know how to play it very well
it's not like
I've not reached a roadblock
where the game is like hey slow down friend
I need to teach you this before you move on
and it's happy to just let me move on and
try to fail my way through everything which
is kind of life
isn't it
with that said that's kind of where we are
let's get started and continue our playthrough
okay so I'm just gonna recap for myself because
I'm gonna be honest I uh
I was very confronted by my last interaction
with this madam on the boat
what I understand
is that we're trying to do right now is
get the information she has about the hanging
and to do so
she has basically convinced us that
we need to stop drugs from moving into her port
wonderful boat lady yeah
okay let me give you a little bit of insight into
why I'm making certain decisions like this
and what I think about
some of the character dynamics so far
just gonna find my way back to the center here
let's go in here
a nice quiet place to talk
okay
so
some of the dialogue choices that
I've made have come from a place where
I'm trying to get into the mind of my character
who is basically like
what I imagined to be very insecure
about his lack of memory right
he's meeting a lot of strong personalities
he meets Kim very early on who
has these very strong convictions
he meets the girl on the boat who
is like a professional and sticks to her script very well like
we were not able to get her to flex very much
on what she was willing to tell us
we met Cuno and Cunoesse two characters who like
whether we like it or not
are very passionate in their way of
communicating and representing themselves
in my head Canon like my character has
met a lot of strong personalities
and that's something that he
currently doesn't have right
it's sort of like compensation
we're trying to present ourselves as like
the detective that we can hope people assume we are
not the detective that we know we are
we lost our fucking badge we don't have a gun
we look like a fucking goofball
with our coat and our gloves and our crowbar
and and we're just like failing our way through
every successful encounter
and so that's kind of like
where the dialogue is coming from so far
it's kind of hard to tell what you really think in the moment yeah
so
what I want to do is get a look at this thought cabinet
this is something I hadn't actually looked at yet
how do I like this background music
it's very very calming and relaxing
okay so what am I looking at here this is like
there's only one thing in here that I can click on
temporary research bonus plus 1
empathy towards Kim Kitsuraki
here's the thing about me and Kim okay
we're on kind of rocky terms he and I
he ah
he's a complicated character to me because
every single other person who I've met
has been immediately confrontational of me right
they've immediately been like
able to identify that I'm kind of a fraud
but Kim is this person who like immediately gave me his
trust and started giving me responsibilities
which I find very suspicious
as a traumatized addict
Kim's a professional you're a bumbling semi competent druggie
well here's the thing right and
this is human nature
human psychology
and it's something that I experience in my practice
in the addiction space
is that people who have lots of trauma
and who maybe come from
abusive homes or sorts of things like that
they naturally have a lot of trust issues
like someone coming up to them and immediately telling them
I'm here to help you
I'm always gonna have your back
that brings out an immediate sense of distrust
and so what you will find people do kind of subconsciously
is they will naturally push that person away right by
being very vulgar by being very confrontational by
sort of pushing and testing the limits
and what they're essentially doing maybe without knowing
is they're trying to prove to themselves
let's say you know
Kim walks into my life
and he says I always get your back
and I don't trust him
and I push him to his edge and he abandons me
and I can go see
that fits my worldview
that fits the trauma informed worldview that
everyone is always going to abandon me right
like we naturally tend to do that
that's something that I experience all the time
especially when I work with clients who are
maybe court ordered to be in treatment or something
who don't necessarily want to be in therapy
there is a kind of resistance that they express to like
you know
why why do you want to help me
what do you get out of this right
and you kind of just have to push through that
when you actually push through
and show that person
it doesn't matter how vulgar you are
it doesn't matter how much you push me away
doesn't matter how much resistance you give me
it doesn't matter if you tell me every single day
that I'm a piece of shit and
you think I'm exploiting you right
if you stick with that person and continue to show them
what we call unconditional positive regard
they start to see that okay
there is actually a way for me to trust someone
I don't have to be so guarded
because even though I can be a bit of a pain sometimes
this person's not gonna abandon me
and then you've established a kind of rapport with them right
and so that's kind of how I imagine the detective to be
like I don't know his backstory yet
but it seems like he doesn't have a lot of people in his life
it doesn't sound like he's got a very
structured support system right
so like it's natural for him to be
mistrusting suspicious avoidedant and resistant
to new relationships okay
this is actually how real psychology would
position these two characters
it would not be natural for me
to just immediately be like Kim is my best friend
because he says he's got my back
no like it's much more natural for someone traumatized
to actually push that person away
over and over and over again until
that resistance fades away and we establish that kind of rapport
or maybe he is just a really cool dude I mean
could just be that too
clears up a lot how you're interacting with Kim in this playthrough
well exactly right like
that's the way that I am interpreting my interactions with him
you know where I'm like
okay Kim you're gonna tell me
you're gonna tell me that I'm responsible in this
exchange with the lady on the boat right
and then you're going to take away that responsibility
see I knew it no one trusts my capability
that's the psychological mind like that I'm working with here right
it's not natural for me to believe that someone would trust me
yeah it's a bit of role playing
my Esprit de Corps part immediately told me he has my back well
yeah I mean that's that's true right
yeah I mean a real world experience so like
it was one of my first days at a new job once
and and I walk into a a group room you know
I'm about to like do my first round of
group therapy with a bunch of people who
you know maybe come from department of corrections
who have criminal histories
who are struggling with addiction like
they're the kind of person that I'm talking about who
you know they present a hard exterior
but there's a lot of psychological fragility there
and they are naturally going to like push back
against anyone who walks into their life
especially like someone who looks like me
and and like is going to be very distrusting
that I have good intentions or that I'm earnest
or that I even know what the fuck I'm talking about right
and I started telling them a little bit about myself and
was telling them that I studied overseas and that sort of thing
and someone had kind of said to me like
oh do they wear those like
high water pant leggings over there too
because I was wearing pants and like
the leggings were not all the way to my feet
like you could see some of my shin
or not my shin but like my ankle
and I could tell that they were trying to do this
they were like trying to see what my reaction would be
making fun of me in a group setting
and all of the other people in the room laughed
and I have two choices here right
like I can like try to be defensive and
lose my chance at making rapport
or I can sort of like show them that
it doesn't matter how hard you push me
you know I'm still gonna like be here to help you
so I told them no
they don't they don't wear these over there
that's just me I'm still growing into these
and I gotta laugh out of that
and from then on I never once got any of these people
trying to challenge me the same way
they kind of realized
okay this is a safe person to push the boundaries with
and pushing the boundaries is not going to turn them away right
and I haven't gotten that moment yet from Kim
I'm still a little suspicious of him
I'm still a little bit hurt and fragile and
I'm not sure that he's gonna stick with me
in fact there was a line of dialogue
is there a way to like see past dialogue
is there like a dialogue record or something like that
I don't know if there is
but there was a line of dialogue in the last exchange
with the lady on the boat
that said like
there is a limit to the amount
that Kim is willing to let your impulsiveness
like derail this investigation
and I don't remember what part of my psyche my skill system
was informing of me of this
but that is the exact layer of suspicion
that I'm talking about right
where I'm pushing his buttons I'm really testing the waters
with how much I can truly be myself and still be accepted
and there's a part of me that wonders
is he really with me because he trusts me
and he's actually there for me
or am I a means to his own personal ends right
like as Brady the player
I'm not like really that I don't have a personal bias against him
but as the character
I can see that expressed this inner resistance to
people who on the surface seem very trusting
apparently you need to get racist to get a reaction out of him
might have been empathy yeah
but you see where I'm coming from right
this is something that I experience a lot of my work
and I feel like it's coming through with our lead detective here
so let's look at this thing
the thought cabinet
it looks like I only have one thing that I can really do in here
the insulin civiliar war was not the first war
to see the use of aerostatic aircraft on both sides
but it was the longest
for eight years folded
multi rotor aircrafts crisscrossing the air above Revachol
and the Arcade Islands
they made sweepsilver sandy beaches
and shot each other out of the blue sky
then sank as wrecks to the bottom of the sea
the Ace's High was a custom on the revolutionary side
performed by squadron mates after landing
lieutenant kitsuragi likes it why is that
that's the problem
so
what we can do here is I guess internalize
this thought and what does that do
it gives us empathy
ah you spend time thinking on them
okay so this just happens passively I guess
let me get another look at that
why does kitsuragi like this
perhaps this story or this
narrative represents something he identifies with
keep my eyes peeled for that
let's see what she's got to say
hello sweetie
immediately distrusting
I'm immediately distrusting
wait who's sweetie
yeah who the fuck is sweetie you talking to me
why you are officer
I'm no sweetie look at me
see the self deprecation see the immediate lack of trust like
this is as much a lowered self esteem thing as it is like
an inability to integrate positive feedback from other people
because we always think there's a secondary motive
you're a handsome man officer
with your moustache and your chiselled jaw
and that silly dimple on your chin
dimple or not I'm a bitter man
the years have taken their toll
that simple dimple has only brought me suffering
ooh I want to know what the story there is
love can be cruel sweetie
love can be cruel
I don't like that she's interpreting my life story
you mean this grandma on a wheelchair has alteriative motives
absolutely she does I can tell
(you must forgive me I am)getting so scatterbrained
I completely forgot to introduce myself
so I'll let her introduce herself
and then I want to tell you something else about
how like first impressions work psychologically and why
I don't have trust issue
okay maybe I do have a couple trust issues
but I'm speaking from the point of view of the character here
I'm Lena
my husband Murell and I are staying with our friend Gary
just down the street
but I come here for tea when they're away
this Lena is wacky enough for the motley crew
hire her on the spot
okay I like that idea
hey old Winter King thank you so much for the sub my friend
enjoy your early access to these streams and
all other content that comes to the channel
you seem to be in a chair
how'd you like to roll with me
yes dear I'm a paraplegic
what is a paraplegic
I was also informed by many commenters that like
there's no drawback and just continuing to explore dialogues
so I will be doing that
because I guess it raises my
chances of clearing some of these like crazy checks
it means I can't use my legs
I was in an accident some years back
injured in the line of duty as they say
were you a mountaineer
nothing so glamorous dear
so when I was young
I dreamt of planting the Revachol flag on some figurative peak
oh they can hurt my chances too well
we'll just have to figure out how that goes
what did you do that
(I was a)training and development manager
at a rapidly expanding mail order shoe company
you'd think it would be a safe job
but I had to be everywhere
and well once I happened to be under some faulty scaffolding
so it was an accident
I was lucky
this was almost 20 years ago when
I was compensated exceptionally well
one can only dream of such payoffs nowadays
could I become a paraplegic
I hope not although the work you are doing
for all of us is quite dangerous
here's another thing yeah she's admiring me a lot
towering over her in your insignia
you make her feel safe
maybe this paraplegic
uh get up is just a way to disarm me
let's see authority speaks to me okay
as the character it speaks to
it's one of my competing mental states that
most of the time demands like immediate action
it wouldn't be so bad hanging out in a chair playing pinball
I've been trying to avoid my responsibilities with that
I know but that's what I'm saying
it's it's disarming me by making it
making me seem like you know she's not a threat to me
she not a threat to me physically but she could be emotionally
I'm not sure I should be in this line of work
that seems pretty earnest
(you're a man)at the peak of your physical and intellectual powers
you'll find another call in yet I'm certain of it
doesn't that mean authorities not speaking to you
yeah maybe so I don't know
okay thanks for clearing that up for me
there is no bitterness in her voice
she accepted the curiosity her condition inspires a long time ago
okay I have just demonstrated exactly what I
talked about which is
I wasn't sure if I could trust her
and so I pushed her boundaries right
I asked myself is she a safe person
what if I call out something that
I think would make her uncomfortable right
like her condition
and I make some weird remarks about that
and she continues to be honest and admiring me
and my sense of empathy has come out to say okay
you make her feel safe
that was authority and empathy is like
disarming me from perceiving her as a threat
like the game just demonstrated exactly what I was talking about
like basically perfectly
this game is so fucking good like what the fuck
okay now I'm in
let's go
roll with me I want you to be in my wheelchair partner
fight in fighting crime helping people
catching sequence killers
roll that's some cigarettes
phenomenal cohesion between you with the game
that's what's like blowing my mind is like
it seems like every thought I have
the game is giving me like a very prompt reaction
or demonstration of that
I think she could roll us a couple cigs
but I'm gonna now I'm trying to establish
that rapport with her right
the danger in what I talked about
where you push someone's boundary and
like you establish that they are a safe person after all
once you confront them and they stick with you
is now there's a danger of me
having a like overly attached perspective of them
because I'm like
oh well I just found the one person
in my life who has not pushed me away
or abandon me once I pushed on them
now I'm going to attach to myself to them forever
and that's the other side of abandonment and trust issues is
we develop codependency
sequence killers oh my
but I think you already have a partner sweetie
what this this fucking guy
Kim has not shown me yet
that he's going to stick with me
a partner who needs you
to get back to helping the people of Martinaise
see don't like
that's what I'm talking about okay
here I'm trying to make a very important connection Kim
this is like one of the only people who has not like
immediately given me suspicion
even the little girl in front of her little bookstand
with her cursed house
set me on edge okay
she wanted something from me
she asked me to go in the store
she wanted me to buy things right
everyone is out to exploit the detective
except this perfect lady here
who has not given me any reason to doubt
her admiration for me
and here I have Kim
wanting to cut short that reaction
because we've got  bigger things to do
I've got problems with Kim okay
he's getting in the way of me and my healing here
I know I know but there are side mysteries
sequence killers into the paranatural
maybe I should be a little sarcastic
again I'm trying to push Kim
I'm trying to get to that moment
where he shows me that no matter how difficult I am
he stays with me
yes and it seems to me that you do well to stick close to him
he has the look of an upstanding officer of the law
someone you can lean on
and sweetie you are looking unsteady
the way she calls me sweetie
I wish she was my mom
and even if he weren't there
I don't think you'd have much use for me
why 3 heads are better than 2 please come along
Martinaise isn't the most wheelchair accessible place you see
I'd slow you down perhaps another time
see how much I'm opening up to her now that like
I consider her a safe person
I don't know if you've noticed
but I don't know where I am or what I'm doing or anything
like that's one of the most honest things that
my character has come up with to say so far
yes officer you look rather dazed
like a stun fox
but surely things can't be that bad
I'm now being perceived
she won't judge you no matter what she say
this game reads my fucking mind dude
there is a kind of safety comfort and anxiety
in the way that she perceives me
safety because
I can tell that she can see through my rugged exterior that is
desperate to convince you
that I am competent and healthy when I'm not
but also a kind of anxiety which is
someone from the outside is looking in and showing me that
my sense of security of self and health is
a facade even to myself right
and now I trust this woman
and she's like hey you don't look so good
and I'm starting to think maybe she's right
I drank so hard I forgot literally everything
oh my
you know where we are right
we're in Revachol
that's right
in a hostel called the whirling in rags to be precise
honestly I don't know diddly squat about Revachol
I've learned some things about Revachol
but not from the right people so far
what I've learned is that there are no schools in Revachol
and the kids have nothing to do
but hang around and insult adults all day long
and that this place is full of racists
and sad poetry boys like Tommy
I want to know what grandma thinks about this
how would I even begin to tell you
Revachol is the most beautiful city in the world
(We're)fortunate to be here you and I
what a fucking light in the darkness her perspective
I am clinging to it now
do you see how rapidly I'm getting attached to her
now that I've considered her safe
I haven't seen very many other cities personally
but everyone says so
Revachol is a rare jewel
this city used to rule the world
though it has seen better days
it's fascinating that she says this
because every other character has pointed at Revachol as like
a place where things are dying
even the ones who are optimistic like Kim
he sees like a cultural value to this place
but he still feels like it's dying
like it's losing its cultural value because of people
like the racist lorry driver
like everyone sees Revachol in a state of decline
except this woman
speaking of history
you know what year it is yes
it's a bad year in my late 40s or 50s
I don't even know how old I am
let's go with that
there there the year is 51 and spring has only just started
I'm sure there are better days ahead
are you saying the
MC is just overthinking and afraid of negative things
but the lady shows that the negativity is a false alarm
specifically for her
no I think that
my character's perspective is that
I can trust this lady and I trust her optimism but
I can't live in the world that she perceives
right not the way I am
she she has been able to make peace with her trauma
the way that she talked about like
you know I am a paraplegic now and
the fact that she has
endured that experience and remains optimistic
that is something attractive to my character as insight
potentially
there is a way for me to be okay with myself
even though I am extremely flawed
and I'm broken in a way that I will never get better
that's kind of why I imagine he asked like
can I be a paraplegic
it's kind of a comedy line but
there's a little bit of like
can I be like you
like would being a paraplegic make me feel better
because I would find the kind of peace in my trauma
and disability that you have
like this game is so good
like a single line of dialogue like that
tells me so much from a therapeutic point of view
I want to be like her because
she's found a way to make peace with this
and it doesn't matter that she is unfixable
she still feels
okay with who she is
the lieutenant studies you rubbing his chin
yeah what do you see Kim
I'm beginning to suspect that you might
indeed be completely adrift in this reality
thinks the lieutenant
how can it be that bad
never mind we're in this now
see he's sizing me up as well
I imagine that Kim is experiencing a very
similar thing as our detective right
he's wondering like in a similar way
this person is very chaotic
what will happen if I test their limits
will they stick with me right
the lieutenant doesn't seem to have a lot of
people in his life either
outside the melting snow seeps into the cracks in the woods
and the cobblestone streets
all the way down into the sewers
above ground the first May bells blossom
you can feel it
a great cold then the shiver passes
whoever told me to speck into shivers was a genius
I love this perspective
I can tell that this is taxing for you
so I'll just ask one more question
what regime are we living under what mode of government
definitely not a democracy
I'd like to think that it's the dictatorship of the proletaria
but something tells me it's not
fierce warriors
governed by intelligent machines that
perform calculations to determine the freeest market
radios are being used to control people's minds
cop we're living under the cop regime
um let's
let's get her opinion
this is the only one that is not a statement
it's a question
so
maybe if I say it she'll enlighten me
nope sadly not
Ravishal is what's called a zone of control
I knew it under an alliance of foreign powers
called the coalition
we have no government of our own and
what democracy we have is
market driven
there's no government how come there are cops
I don't even know what to say I'm so disappointed hmm
uh let's see
should I go with
oh dear this is troubling
you really ought to know that being one yourself
there aren't any cops in Revachol
not in the traditional sense
the status of law enforcement has been
a complicated matter since the revolution
okay
just giving me good context here
this lady is like informing me of things that
no one else would
and I finally feel safe enough with a person
to let them know that
I am completely ignorant of these things
like I couldn't tell the fucking boat lady that
I don't know why I have a job
but we should stop for today sweetie
you look like you need a break
she sees me
I'm not the best person to explain the big things to anyone
look how honest and humble she is
and she sees me she can tell how fatigued and sad I am
she's scared now
she's realized you really are brain damaged
so how did I do you
didn't do too well dear
it does look like you're having
trouble remembering things
history and places
remembering reality in a word
it's very odd
a sigh
the lieutenant bears his nose in his notebook
see there's another thing that I'm not sure about Kim
the way that she spoke to me just now
she's giving an honest reflection
and she's empathizing with me
whereas Kim is showing me disappointment
and he's showing me mistrust
like maybe I am too brain damage
to be used for to him
but maybe a fresh set of eyes is what the world needs
and while I'm no doctor
such bouts of amnesia are often temporary
so I wouldn't worry too much
solid positive reframing there
Lena
oh my god her name is Lena
I just realized that
wait wait a second this is some Inland Empire shit
of course I am immediately magnetized to the character
named Lena
there's no way
this is eerie
this game is eerily deep in my psyche
you mentioned that three times
I didn't see that comment
for those who have no idea what I'm talking about
my favorite anime of all time is 86
and I am obsessed with the main character Lena
she's one of the most well written characters I've ever seen and
I have spent many many hours talking about
the psychology of her character and
why she's so relatable
and here I find myself gravitating to another Lena
in a completely different medium this is weird
she means this sincerely
worrying won't do you any good
what is this revolution you mentioned
a defeat I'm afraid
the people of this archipelago tried to build
something new something different
the rest of the world didn't like it
so they came and ended it
this was 42 years ago
but I'm a cop whatever it was hasn't stopped me
of course sweetie
I really don't know how to explain it better
I'm just a poor woman she thinks
what do I know of these things and how can I help you
Lena
you have helped me more than you could ever know
and I only wish the game gave me a way
to tell her that
that she's she's someone so far who has
finally given me some secure grounding in this lost world
someone more educated in sweeping matters
maybe you should ask
oh yeah you want me to ask him
no I'm not an encyclopedia
I won't be a guide eater
I'm a detective
okay setting up clear boundaries with me
I can respect that but it doesn't bring us any closer Kim
of course then I don't know
someone rich maybe
well though people are educated
though I don't know where you would find a
wealthy person in Martinaise
I've got to get going now
I'll come back for you Lena of course dear
good luck with your case
I'm gonna cry dude Lena's the best
do you think the MC should worry more
or do you think the MC shouldn't worry too much
like Lena said
I will talk about that later I want to talk about
how my character is experiencing anxiety
like some of the dialogue choices that he is making
not just me as the player but
some of the dialogue choices it presents to me
I sense a lot of anxiety and what he's saying
and I want to talk about how anxiety works
and what the behavioral responses
I kind of rushed out of here earlier
so I kind of want to see
if there's anything else here
real mature man
what exactly were you trying to accomplish
you do understand you still owe me money right
oh shit I hope I haven't consigned myself to paying him
damn your feet thought we got away
oh fuck so I
I got away with it and
now I have stumbled my way back into
just having to pay it anyways
that doesn't seem fair
you demonstrated some serious skills there
slipping away Sam Bo style
yes Sam Bo
by the way Sam Bo or Samaran boxing
is an eloquently violent set of one on one fighting moves
originated from the Samaran Isola
Sam Bo used to incorporate
a wide array of martial disciplines
from archery to mounted combat
but mainly means aesthetically pleasing single combat nowadays
Sam Bo style implies stealth cleverness and cool
I like the sound of that I want to be cool
I want to be very cool
maybe I can lean into the whole I'm brain damaged thing
what are you brain damaged
what the fuck this is so weird
this is so fucking weird
oh my God
how is this happening okay
no I'm just getting my bearing see how my responses
like are different compared to these people
trying to show
confidence here
money is what growing up people use to pay for things
things like this hostel room or
or eight bottles of Potent Blend and nine packs of Royal Extra
we use it for everything really
where can I get money
are you serious
from your work I don't know
you can take bribes I guess
I'm sorry I'm not above bribes cops take bribes
I'm actually not above it take recompense
I don't need to survive
why do I need it
for survival to pay me
unless you want to become a hobo
do you want to become a hobo
there's nowhere else to stay in Martinaise
and it's a cold spring outside
money doesn't make you happy
but it lets you be unhappy for a bit longer
holy shit this guy's got wisdom
if you run out of money you die
it's like that for all of us me too
that's why I need you to pay me
I'm not an asshole
I don't think I have anything
there's a shuffle of nylon
as Lieutenant Kitsuragi looks for something
in the pockets of his orange bummer
that's cop for
I haven't offered to pay
because I don't have any money either
I'm sorry I know it was irresponsible for me to run
you have to understand I was desperate
okay so
having the capacity to apologize
is not an easily adopted trait
I'm gonna have to pursue that one
you know what
the stupid drinks you've had are on the house
you know why because I know you can't pay for them
not because you ran away
can't you see I'm struggling out here
I still have to charge you for three nights
and the broken window
that's 100 square
thank you for your cooperation
so we're cool
not entirely cool
used to owe me 100 Real
if you don't have it by tonight
I can't let you back up there
oh I can't come back
now what the hell did you want
I assume you wanted something to come back here
is the trash container out back yours
oh I wanted to get inside that trash container
mine no it belongs to the whirling and rags
thank you for clearing that up
why do you keep the container locked
why to keep the hobos and drunks out
that's why
and the neighbors too
they put that trash there
and they don't pay for the garbage company
wait why are you guys surprised what
you didn't know you could do what it's so funny
I seem to be making like all of the weirdest decisions
I thought as much
and are you the only party with access to the trash container
well yes us and the garbage disposal company
ah the garbage disposal company
see that's the thing
you gotta ask yourself who benefits
it seems a little callous doesn't it
something stirs in you
I wonder what this feeling is
no it doesn't nothing stirs in me
and it isn't callous  it's common sense
I did stick a point in rhetoric
sort of desperately hoping
it would intrusively give me some insight
so I'm gonna pursue this
prod at him and find out
ah yes
doesn't it seem callous to you
guarding even your leftovers from the poor
callous
what are you Kras Mazov
almost all establishments in Revachol
keep their trash locked
the whirling and rags is not special in that regard
we need those keys
it concerns the case please cooperate
just bring them back once you're done please
look at that look how far an apology goes to
I've seen something here at the Whirling Gart
I think I need to talk about
what thing
the mess hall is reserved for the union
not the whole union thank god
just the nastiest and loudest faction
they come here in the evenings
dumb unruly types
think they are big shit
but they are good customers
they place big orders and always pay on time
he hates the union
but grudgingly recognizes it's power over him
so he is directing his frustration at you instead
retaliate
I love that
authority pops up a lot for my character
which tells me that my guys
way of organizing relationships between people
is all about power dynamics right
in fact we even saw that with
Lena the woman in the wheel chair
which is like
when someone has had some sort of trauma
where their sense of control has been taken away
potentially this is like you know
sexual abuse or maybe
bullying or
abandonment
any of these things that have left the person
feeling like they did not have control over a situation
that's what they tend to organize relationships as later in life
but in a very sort of
unadjusted way
and so every time
I have an interaction with other people
I'm looking for the power dynamic
I'm finding this woman in the wheelchair
and I'm immediately like yes
I have this power over relationship with her because
I can stand and you know she can't
I have a questionable power relationship with Kim
he sometimes gives me a false sense of authority
telling me like it's your case detective
like you need to do the line of questioning
but then he revokes it
and so this is like
I'm not sure where I stand with him
as I look at Garte and the union
that's what my character is latching on to is like
what is the power dynamic here
like he understands why Gart is in this position
because he hates the union but recognizes their power over him
and he's also doing something
called displacement
which is something that I kind of want to talk about
really quick I'll just briefly bring this up
because it's relevant to what this character is saying right now
I want you to look at this line
he hates the union
but begrudgingly recognizes its power over him
so he's directing his frustration at you instead
so
when someone is directing something at you instead
what he's talking about there
is kind of like a
cognitive distortion called displacement
this is what we call it
so displacement is the idea
that we tend to have an emotion
which has a target
like for example
if my boss is telling me I'm not a good worker
and I don't do my job well
and I am easily replaceable
the emotions that I'm having are ones of anger
or frustration or
resentment
but this is not a safe target for this emotion
because there's all kinds of consequences if I act on this anger
if I yell at my boss and I get in a fight with him
I could lose my job
and I could lose my livelihood
there's a lot of
anxiety that interferes here
kind of subconsciously
so this is not a safe target
the anger does not just go away though
what happens is it gets redirected
it gets displaced to a safer target
which is often the people closest to us right
this is the classic like
I got in trouble at work
so I go home and I yell at my partner
or I yell at my kids right
a lot of people who do not know
how to resolve this emotion
when they can't act on it
what they do is they just collect it and they store it
and they deliver it somewhere else
to someone that they are going to have
less consequences dealing with
that's exactly what he's talking about here
when he says
he hates the union
so he's directing his frustration at you instead
I'm the safe target
because he can't retaliate against the union itself
he'll lose his own livelihood
he'll lose his own power and status right
and the way that I have kind of described this to people is
I guess the way I say this is like
how you are supposed to deal with this in the aftermath
like let's say I come home and I yell at my partner
right the way you apologize to this is you tell them
you know I'm sorry
I gave you
and emotion
that didn't belong to you
and that wasn't fair
I collected this anger from
my workplace and from my co workers
and from the people who wouldn't stand up for me
and the fact that I don't have any money right now
and that's a self directed anger
I directing this emotion in all these different places
and none of them are safe targets
but for me today you were the safe target
and it wasn't fair to do that
like I gave you this emotion
and it didn't belong to you
and I just don't know how to deal with this yet
that's exactly what is happening here
that's what authority is telling me
is what's happening here right
he's directing his frustration at you instead
it's asking me to retaliate
and I think the reason it's doing that is
I also have a lot of collected
trauma and anger and frustration
and I feel out of power dynamic balance with lots of people
and so he's the safe target for me right now right
and earlier it was the dock lady and earlier it was Cuno
Cuno happened to be my safe target to
direct this displaced anger at the time
and so I tried to give it to him
and it didn't work out right
I'm walking around with this reservoir
of emotion that I've collected
and when I experience something that makes me mad
and it really deserves
maybe this much anger
but I get in touch with all of the anger that I have
collected and not dealt with
and I
explode with it right
this is like kind of the foundational
way I tend to deal with like anger management
is to understand where that anger comes from
and why so much of it is being expressed
when only this much
really matches this situation that you're in
and so I think
it would be displacement for me to retaliate here
just like it was displacement for
me to retaliate against Kuno
I've always conceptualized as having energy that will come out
so you have to direct it towards something constructive
well that's true
the thing is
is we don't always choose something constructive
we choose something that's self destructive
which you're talking about would be
something called sublimation
which is when you deal with a...
displaced emotion in a socially acceptable way
for example
instead of just handing this out
to whoever makes me angry in the moment
what I do is I take a boxing
and I get involved in an activity where I can start to let some of this out
and it's a socially acceptable task right
that's what we call sublimation
and in some ways I would probably say that
being a detective is a form of sublimation for Raphael
because it's where he gets to
act out in his socially acceptable way
his sense of authority
he's just not very good at it yet
it's the right outlet but it's the wrong approach
can we see his hands
I've covered up his hands
how does this knowledge of this help a person
who experiences it
because you can start to recognize
okay you know
I got in an argument today
and I gave someone a lot of my anger
and I can you know when you come to therapy and
we might engage in that dialogue
like I might ask you who was that emotion for
well it was for the person who cut me off in traffic
right
and it's like okay well
does the emotion of that event match realistically
I would work with them on understanding that
no this is a disproportionate release of emotion for the situation
and then we would start asking
okay who is the real target
a lot of times it's not
my boss who I can't safely target it's
it's my mom who has never been in my life right
like it's a target that's not only maybe not safe
but not available
it could be society right it could be like
I'm really angry at the economic system
but how do I express my anger to the economic system
well it's not like I can directly go punch it in the face
but I might start developing very negative opinions
about bankers and CEOs and people who in a sort of
symbolic way represent that institution that I'm very angry at
so how do you get rid of it
can't punch capitalism yeah
well you need to find something that works for you
in terms of this right here right
we need to first understand that the anger or
sometimes its grief
sometimes its sadness
like it's not just anger but this is a very common one
we need to understand that it is being displaced
why it is being displaced at this person
and then we can start figuring out what the outlet is
because everyone's going to deal with
feelings of anger in a different way like for me
I like to run
when I go to the treadmill or out on a run like
this exertion of energy and like the rush of endorphins
it sort of like tempers the feelings that I have
and
kind of lets me direct them into something productive for myself
it calms me down in a way
talking about it
Sigmund Freud
called the process of talking about something
and the emotional release you get from it
catharsis
he also called it the talking cure
because just telling the narrative of what happened
learning and understanding like why it happened is
something that in a lot of ways releases this reservoir for you
hey Van Zorkin thank you so much for the sub my friend
thank you thank you very much
so yeah displacement right
I think that that's what we're going to see a lot of in this world
because it's very natural
ways to deal with our emotion
and in fact
sorry to keep going back to the game and back to this
but you can imagine like let's say
I'm in an exchange with my boss
and I'm displacing that anger to you know my partner
and my partner
let's say they got in an argument with their friend
and they're displacing that anger towards me right
essentially like
I'm giving her a motion
she's giving me emotion and
neither of us are really the people that this belongs to
but we're the ones in an argument
so often how relationships start to break down is
partners not collaborating on what they're feeling and
bringing displaced emotions home
and not knowing how to deal with them
is something that comes up a lot when I do like couples counseling
I've heard that having an outlet
like boxing to release anger is bad
because it makes you become violet
well you have to know what you're doing and why
to get the benefit of acting it out right
it's about like
knowing you're doing that with the intention of releasing it
and that being violent isn't the outlet it's
learning to control the emotion right
like your perspective matters a lot
you did pet the mailbox displaced affection
yes 100 percent right
good emotions can be displaced as well
we've seen a lot of people angry at things they can't control
yeah totally right that's how I understand Cuno
I talked about this very briefly when I was actually doing the
this discussion about the skill system
my understanding of Cuno is probably that
there's a very good reason why he's the way he is
like he probably has a lot of displaced emotions
and a lot of missing sense of control
and the way he gets that control backed
is by getting a reaction out of people
okay
let's continue because I could talk about this stuff
for a very long time
because we are self aware about our displacement
I'm going to ask myself to let it go
let it go your above gratuitous baiting
oh yeah sorry about that
game is unmuted
we don't we have to wait
they'll show up sooner or later
men get hungry
even striking men
if not today then they'll be here tomorrow
something else I want to ask about
by the way
you should come back to this thing based questionnaire
if you see anything interesting in the whirling later
okay
by the way I'm gonna sing karaoke here
absolutely out of the question
oh it's quiet I can raise the volume
you wait and see cafeteria manager
absolutely in the question
first we find a sad banger
then we sing this place to shit
another thing great yeah
okay I can
increase the volume a little bit
that should do it
let me know if it's too loud
by the way where is home
the address is coming up blank
and this place sure isn't it
do I even have one
but you've been at this hostel cafeteria for only 3 nights
where were you before
you had to be somewhere
I don't know near south maybe
you don't really know do you
does this mean I'm homeless
Nah we must have been somewhere
a vague blackened image
doesn't sound like somewhere you can stay
if you run out of money
that's a good point encyclopedia
I live in a dumpster I don't care
fuck everything hobocop
let's find out
run some addresses in your head when you get the time
maybe a street or an apartment will appear
man this I have so many
lingering like things to do this is crazy
there's a couple other things in the thought cabinet now
I do want to talk about this
but I think I need to be more acquainted with the system
before I give like a real breakdown about
how this represents mental health
because I do have some thoughts on that
but I want to see
what happens after I've internalized something
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it
consider giving it a like and letting me know what you
thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a bit earlier
if you support the channel
either through Twitch or Patreon
links to both of those and the community discord are in the description
thanks again and I'll see you next time