hello
and welcome back to my
therapist plays Disco Elysium Analysis series
in today's episode
we are going to be taking a very thorough look at
how Disco Elysium portrays intrusive thinking
when electrochemistry starts giving us thoughts
and they are very much opposed to the thoughts of volition
and how this actually very accurately represents
some of our very real thinking patterns
so we're gonna be using actual theory to break this down
using the cognitive model
how actual cognitive behavioral therapy works
and how we might apply it to a situation that
our detective finds himself in with his own intrusive thinking
this one's gonna be quite in depth
so I'm excited to get into it
let's dive it
all right
so what we need to do now is figure out
where to go
this door he wants me to bust down
oh there's a end-of-day debrief
Kim can answer any lingering questions
you may have about the case and the RCM
join him in the Whirling-in-Rags' balcony after 10
so what time is it
it's almost 10
so we've got a little bit of time before we can do that
do we have enough money to pay back Mr Garte
do we have enough
do we have it's got a ton of trash
let's go turn in the trash
let's pay a visit to the best character in this entire game
Frittte girl
let's see what she's up to
and let's get some money
yeah we're not accepting that bribe fuck that guy
I don't care I'll
we'll solve our many problems
through rigorous environmentalism
I believe I'm supposed to talk to this gentleman first though
see what he's got to say
so how'd you like our harbor
was nice enough
let's remain neutral
it's but a rest area on the path leading across open plains
all right
you talk to the boss
eye-to-eye like men of the plain
if you have any more questions I'm set to talk
Evrart said you have a key to the door
a key huh
what door is this key supposed to open
he set it belonged to a weasel
I was hoping you could tell me let's just go with that
of course I got you
you don't know anything
he taps the side of his nose with a little
I got that key right here
and let me tell you
it's mighty good of you to help us out during the strike
working class solidarity as they say
see if I can get some information out of him
I'm a hustle grinder
I'm not really doing this for political reasons
that's very in line with me
oh so the none-of-the-above type are you
I get it I get it
I like to keep my distance too
but it doesn't matter
it's a good thing you're doing thanks
what you're looking for is a basement door behind the greenhouse
that's behind the Whirling-in-rags
that's all I know
our organization is what you call compartmentalized
means we keep out of each other's business
okay but where did you get the key from
good question
the janitor gave it to me
nice fella
we talked about life and things that really truly matter
none of this mess we're in this javing and juggling
what's it for
to feed our children I guess
anything else I should know about this task
this weasel person
when he'll be home
I'm more of a philosophical dockworker
I like to talk about the big picture stuff
who I am who you are
what we are fighting for
hey thank you so much for the hydrate immortal
we'll do that now
so he's a he's a deep thinker
who he is and what they're fighting for
this is interesting
why are you striking
we're negotiating our share
your share
aye
how large a share would you like
let's ask him
all of it
however right now
we want all the harbor workers to be on the company's board
so they could take part in the decision making process
let's ask him about Evrart
I think it's best you make up your own mind
now that you've made
in my eyes
he is a capable organizer and a decent businessman
what has bossing the union entails anyway
I guess you kinda get to be the village chief
he oversees the harbor
makes deals with the owners or other relevant parties
watches out for his own
by that you mean corruption
got him
by heavens why would he not be corrupt
we live in a harsh and disorder world see
and in this world
the old man is corrupt for our benefit
and we know it
appreciate it even
he is personally not too lavish
that desk seemed lavish to me
he is reasonably lavish sure
that's his prerogative
it's not like you want a saintly demeanor on a corrupt motherfucker
that would be a manipulative illusion
as someone so careful with your words
you're letting some vulgarity slip through here friend
what's going on
besides
there are no non-corrupt systems in the world anyway
and moralism is the most corruptive them all
what
not you you would like to say
but then there's that weasle door
how is moralism corrupt
I don't really know what moralism entails in this context though
are you a communist
no
I don't think I'm a communist
seeing something of value when saying I want it all to myself
is a much older and simpler notion
no science to it at all
even a weak child can think it
the only things holding someone back are I can't and I shouldn't
moralism is centralism
that does not help me
that I am further from understanding that now actually
you shouldn't take what's not yours
I mean I agree with that
then how can anything ever be mine
but that's okay
we don't have to agree
the prairie is wide enough for all of us
moralism is the international political group that took over the revolution
like Rene talked about
it's the main ideology of the ruling class
it's basically American liberalism
centrism coalition they're the do-nothing party
there's so many things here that I
that are out of my scope
ah yeah well there's a spoiler policy
but sometimes I'm just gonna ask for information because like
I'll be honest like
I'm gonna
I'm inviting this now I know but like
certain kinds of spoilers I really don't care about
like obviously
I don't want people to tell me
what happens in the game
if I am gonna find that out on my own
but like
the things that are the most egregious spoilers to me are like
character things
like I do wish that I would have probably discovered the
the name thing on my own
I don't think it's like the worst thing ever but
like character development as spoilers to me
but telling me what moralism is like
tell me because
so out of my scope
you seem to think you seem to have spent a lot of time
thinking about the political situation
let's ask him that
sure I've had the necessary free time
fortunately there's always time
okay the look in his brown eyes conjures up an understanding
for him having command of his time is the most important thing
the man sits on the railing
his hands reaching far and wide
yet it feels as if he could effortlessly go even wider if need be
an endless torrent of time
hmm okay well
he did say he would tell me more about this murder once I talked to his boss
any idea who killed the hangman
the mercenary aye
who could have killed him that's indeed the question
why even do such a thing
it's a good question
the Harbor is a prime area of suspicion
in your opinion are the dockworkers involved in the killing
what a thought
why would noble workers resort to such a thing
unless they were pushed of course
pushed how
your dead guy
was an enemy combatant
did you kill him no we're not gonna go there
hold up what does that mean
it was an agent of the opposition
attempting to undermine our honorable efforts
did you kill him
I ain't the murderin' type
but that's just me
large organizations like our union
have all sorts of men
with all sorts of skills
this could be a red herring
couldn't have nothing to do with the union at all
he means a more violent faction
could easily take care of such a thing
or the least violent
understood
this has been of limited use
still thank you
no problem I wish the best to you in your search
sure am glad it's not my search
all right gotta run
so
trash money sleep
parasympathetic nervous system
is telling me my body needs to rest
damn that felt good
your heart's pounding nicely
you should tell people to fuck off more often
I should I should do that
no you shouldn't
you're an officer of the law
maybe I shouldn't
I love this
I fucking love this
this portrayal of mental states
that are in competition with one another
is so good so accurate
like I really do actually want to talk about this
a little more in depth
if you don't mind me indulging a little bit in some psychology
so like I talked about that here
the whole competing mental states thing
but let me give you a little bit of like additional context so
like
CBT right cognitive behavioral therapy
it uses something called the cognitive model
which is like essentially
that the chain of events is
we have a thought
we have an emotion
and then we have like a behavior
and most of the time we actually work backwards
when we are detecting these things
because our behaviors are so much more observable right
it's like simple cause and effect
for example I'll do it like this
my behavior is I smoked
my behavior is I confronted someone
my behavior is that I cried
my behavior is that I
you know slouched in the chair
my behavior in Evrart's office was like
fidgeting
right my behavior
when I was talking to Frittte girl is like
right just talking conversing
let's put conversing
some of my other behaviors would be
fighting
cursing right
because we're talking about like telling people to fuck off
and confronting and that sort of thing
resting right that's another behavior
you can see that like
it's very easy to identify our behaviors
these are the things that we do
we're quite good at giving like a historical account of things
and I think that for our character
it's also particularly interesting because he's like
he's asking a lot of questions like what did I do
in terms of like who was I
some of his questions have been like
was I a good cop right
like did I do my job
did I perform well
was I a good person right
here behavior is
the most obvious most avert part of this process
but it's also the most limited in
understanding the source of our anxieties right
because like now we have to take a step back actually
the way it works is we have a thought
that thought gives us an emotion
and based on that emotion we make a behavior
but when we're trying to understand these things
we actually have to work our way backwards right
so if I did something like smoked
the behavior is
you know lighting up a cigarette or something
what is the emotion
what is the emotion that I'm having as I do that right
some of the emotions my character has had are like
anxiety
fear
regret
sadness
grief
loss of personal self
I would actually say that like empathy is
more of a behavior in this sense
like we are empathizing with someone
that's a verb right we empathize
but the emotion attached to empathy is
it's even hard for me to come up with some of these
sometimes right like
it's a kind of like sadness
what did what did Tommy call it
like an aching of the soul or something
right it's painful
some of the emotions that we've had were like happiness right
we were happy when we got like a cigarette when
when we got some money right
compassion yeah that's a great one
feeling compassionate
anger is a big one
loneliness
isolation
it's kind of like one of those
shame yeah great
right
so like it's pretty it's a little bit more difficult
but still we can detect these things right
and we can even say okay well when I'm feeling anxious
I might do all of these things
I might smoke when I'm anxious
I might confront someone
I might start crying
I might slouch in my chair
I might start fidgeting
I might start talking right
I might fight with someone
like anxiety can be a source for all of these things
what could shame make us want to do right
it could make us want to isolate
it could make us fight with people
it could make us cry as well right like
there's multiple routes that this can take
but this is where Disco Elysium comes in with like
the the thoughts that your character is having right
this is brilliant right here
so the game is saying like damn that felt good
that s a thought
right
this is a neutral objective like automatic thought that we're having
and like the emotion that we might have from that
is maybe one over like relief
and so when we have this thought and this emotion
like what is the behavior that it's telling us to do
it's telling us to go confront someone right
it's saying damn that felt good
your heart's pounding nicely
you should tell people to fuck off more often
is this a good way to experience relief though
because I think without the thought
if I took this away
right and I asked you well what do we
what's the when we feel relief what do we do
we might say oh well you know
we we rest we have a good conversation right
we might socialize we might relax
but no right
the emotion is only connected to a behavior
in a very limited sense
we don't get the full context of how emotions work
unless we actually have a thought attached to it
which can totally upset the relationship between
something like relief and a behavior
because
that felt good
is telling me that relief is connected to confrontation
that in fact feeling anxiety like that
kind of like heart pumping tension
is like good for you
like you should get in more fights
you should curse more often right
if you want to feel relief you cannot empathize
half light is disrupting your
what we would say is a healthy relationship between
the emotion of relief and the behaviors that might follow it
but then you have something like volition that comes in
and says like no you shouldn't
you're an officer of the law right
what is this
this is appealing to my own sense of moralism
and the idea that like you should
you shouldn't do that you're an officer of the law
to me what that's getting into is like a sense of shame
over like that's not something that someone
with a strong moral code would do
regret
you should not have made that choice
and fear
for how you will come off to people who are trying to uphold a professional
you know law abiding posture to
and then those
despite shame regret and fear
seeming like very negative emotions
what kinds of behaviors are they going to lead to
they're actually going to lead you to empathy
standing up for someone
to not confronting them but trying to understand right
they're going to lead you to honesty
the behavior of honesty right
they're going to lead you to apology
and so now you have what looked like negative emotions
leading you to very positive coded behaviors right
so the cognitive model is all about how like
when you're missing
this part of it
right like when we do not include this
emotions and behaviors do not tell a full story
we assume that
oh well we avoid anxiety right
when we fear
we're always isolating
no
fear can have a very positive impact on you
but you have to consider where it came from
it's the thought
no you shouldn't officer
right you're an officer of the law
fear is stimulating a very positive set of behaviors here
and I love that the game does this
because it demonstrates this
so much with so much like effectiveness
right because
like I said
it's very easy to look at our behaviors and say yeah
like I ordered junk food yesterday
I canceled my appointments
I bailed on my friend
these are all behaviors what were you feeling
well I guess I was feeling
shame
okay but
what's the thought what did you think of before
you felt shame and before you cancelled on your friend
well my thought was
they don't want to hang out with me anyways
okay now we can actually like do some rewiring here right
what's behind that
why is there a connection between like
I don't think that they want to hang out with me
shame and avoidance
and this is where you actually get into
what's behind this whole thing
this is cognitive behavioral therapy right
is
thoughts where do they come from
they're automatic
meaning that like
not all thoughts are automatic obviously
but like the ones that are intruding
into our character's mind are very automatic
and many of ours are as well
but most of these thoughts they come from our core beliefs
this is like the hidden category that's
way down deep
that is where our thoughts like sort of
we don't always have the ability to get insight into
what our core beliefs are
this is not core values
like I can tell you my core value is like
you know respect the law
live an honest life
treat people with kindness whatever
these are core values
but a core belief something that might
develop into an automatic thought like
they don't want to hang out with me anyways is
you know like
I'm worthless right
or I'm uninteresting
I'm not a good person right
a lot of
we can change these and develop positive core beliefs
but when we're having this
negative translation
thoughts behaviors
thoughts emotions behaviors it's coming from like a
core belief that is
maladaptive core belief right
and it's all on the word here right maladaptive
think of how many words have this prefix
malice
malicious
malfunction
malfeasance
um
malignance
malnourished
right mal- being like a
oh it's a French word it means bad right
so when something is bad and adaptive
like we are adapting to it in a negative way
like our brain our emotions they have learned to develop
like in a negative way a maladaptive way
which results in this unproductive
unhelpful chain of thoughts and motions behaviors
and it completely dictates most of what we're doing all the time
and this game is like perfectly
depicting this whole thing
by suddenly having random thoughts
that come to your mind like this
but that come from different angles
it's fascinating
so we're trying to understand
what sort of behavior our character might have as a result of this
because we're currently lacking the insight to
go all the way into this
you can imagine that especially when you
this is hard to do when you are in possession of all of your
critical faculties and you're completely sober
and you even have let's say a good grounding of mental health
this is hard to do
but this is like why CBT is so effective
because like it is a practice proven method
and it is like so crossculturally validated
like this is it this is how it works right
I do not practice CBT religiously
it's foundational to a lot of the stuff that I do
but I put these more in a narrative context right
a lot of my work is focused in
narrative psychology
which is using similar ideas
but it's asking about them in a very different way
so like
you know that person doesn't want to hang out with me
instead of like going and using the language of CBT
we might ask a question like where did you learn that
how did that storyline start
that they don't want to hang out with you
how did the storyline start
that a good officer of the law
is not someone who confronts people that way
where does that narrative begin right
and how do we start investigating that storyline
so it's just using a different sort of
verbal framework to address things
in a way that's a little less like clinical jargony
this is what's so great about this game
and like I said
imagine you're in full possession of your critical faculties
you're sober you're mentally well person
this is still complicated
but now imagine you're also fiending for a cigarette
imagine you're looking for ways to get a buzz
imagine you are buzzed right
trying to detect and trace these things
and like sort out what you're thinking what you're feeling
how this results in behaviors and patterns of behaviors is
like it's really really hard
so that's why as a substance use
working in substance use
a lot of my work is in helping people to identify these things
and learning to do this without self judgment right
because we can't come into this and say like
oh well I just realized that
I tend to confront people very negatively
because I've associated good feelings with
you know being vulgar and confronting people right
and getting relief from telling people to fuck off
I get a release of my anger that way
wow I must be a bad person
oh
there's another thought right
like you're able to put it back on the board
and look at these things without judgment right
and as you do that you may start to develop that core self empathy
because then you can learn that
look my thoughts I'm not in control of these things
they just they happen automatically a lot of times
and when I do change my core beliefs
I can change my thinking
I can change the way I respond to emotions
my behavior will follow suit
and I will have the language to tell a better story
about what is happening in my life
that's how you do psychology
okay I've been going
I'm going on a rant here for a while
I'm gonna read some of your
some of your comments
Brady is there any chance to work with you
I think I'll learn more with you than any institute here
I'm very humbled by that
well this is what I can offer you at the moment
is just my janky whiteboard scribbles and
semi game playing semi self therapy lesson
but I hope it's helpful to someone
half flight is your fight or flight
volition is your self control and dignity
yeah no I think that
the names that the game gives to these sources
that's why I was so compelled by
this idea right when I at the beginning
because like as I said in my first like little
breakaway analysis I was like yeah
I struggle sometimes to explain to people
that you can have multiple mental states that
compete with each other
for like delivering this thought emotion behavior mechanism
it's like
imagine this was the language we use to say like
what is volition telling you right now
if you're feeling your life dominated by thoughts of electrochemistry
what do you think volition would say against them right
you could like legitimately use that dialog
when I was in therapy
CBT felt like such an unsubstantial practice
because it was never explained like this
well that's part of the problem I think
is just that like CBT works
it does it's not perfect for everything
but as a good foundation for
seeing short term results
like you can see people start to make effective changes very quickly
and CBT's whole goal is teaching the
client to become their own therapist
because when you're equipped with this
knowledge you can start doing this
you can start
literally just start with this chain right thought emotion behavior
and start writing them down
you know
that's why like we're often recommending doing
thought records and things like that
but work your way back herewards look at the behavior
what did you do
when my mom called I let the phone go to the voicemail
what were you feeling
I was feeling fear
what was the thought attached to it
I was afraid that I was in trouble for something
okay
keep doing that
what's the pattern right like you you
you can start doing this it's um
it's really impactful
if we're stopping like this every time electrochemistry tells us to do it
we are here for another half year
yeah I know
I told you I try not to
I could be
I could literally do this like for a very long time
because I enjoy it
so thought cabinet ideas could be more
like those narratives inform how we express ourselves
yeah what I'm thinking about
thought cabinet is basically like
this is kind of like stepping back from the thought
and getting into a core belief
like exploring a core belief
once I have discovered that my core belief
or one of them might be
I'm sorry
right my core belief might be attached to this
the internalization of that is like me starting to examine the evidence
that's a very CBT
framework as well
examining the evidence
it's basically like a Socratic questioning sort of thing
how did you learn that this was true
how did you learn that you are a worthless person
how did you learn that people don't want to spend time with you
what is the evidence that tells you that's true
well I don't go out very much
I don't have a lot of friends
I don't get invited to things
okay well what's the evidence that counters that
well let's look in your phone
how many phone calls do you have
well I have a lot but I didn't pick them up
why
well because I was afraid
oh okay
well then that there's not so much evidence for this right
so examining the evidence
when we're internalizing a thought
that's kind of what we're doing
we're looking for ways to either reinforce or
counteract the idea that this is a core belief
and that's what so brilliant about this
is that you can decide after you internalize this
that you can get rid of the thought like
okay well I've discovered that
through no fault of my own
through a process of maladaptive thinking
I have developed a negative core belief
and I want to change that core belief
I don't want to be a confrontationalist
I want to be an apologist or something
could be like that
I don't know how much you've brought up about CBT in this playthrough
but a narrow CBT focus analysis of discolysium
we wouldn't run out of things
well this is the first time I brought up CBT
probably not only on this game but like
even in this whole channel
like I really don't bring up CBT a lot
because again narrative fits my framework a little better
for stuff like this
but this game is nailing CBT how it works
I just completed my Masters in psychology for a 3 months ago
but they never explained CBT like that
I love that
I suffered from depression for 10 years
went to many mental health specialists
and these analysis are better than psychologists told me
yeah I mean the way I think about medication is
like there are definitely aspects of mental health that
that medical intervention are great for
especially for talking like depression right like
I will often let people know that
look much of the work that we can do in therapy
that can benefit by doing a process like this
let me get rid of some of these circles
the thing is we can critically evaluate a lot of this stuff
and that's great
but it's really hard to do
when you have fundamental parts of your biochemistry that are
currently compromised by depression right
remember what I said about the nervous system
like when you are depressed
and alcohol is a depressant
but we can naturally become depressed without alcohol
we're fatigued we're tired
it takes a lot of mental effort to listen to things like volition
which tell us to make our bed
and get up in the morning and go have a social encounter
and like do all these things that are objectively good for you
but they take a lot of energy
and so medication can for example like
just clear out some of that fog and
it's not gonna cure depression
but what it can do is it can prime you to
actually benefit from this process right
you're not gonna benefit from this if
it's a struggle just to get through a 45 minute conversation
you're not gonna be able to do the kind of rigorous self critique
that like I'm asking of you as your therapist right
what we need is someone who is able to sort of
grapple with these subjects
integrate this feedback
actually follow through with the tasks that we are in pursuit of therapeutically
to actually make progress
and so like medication can help prime you for that
rigorous self critique
yeah I love that I actually do love that
some medication help
but I still feel like I need good non medication therapy
no yeah you need both right
I mean it's my belief that both are
they're cooperative in the process of this right
some medications can do the bulk of the work
but a lot of them are treating symptomology right
especially when we're talking about addiction
for example
someone stop me at any time and say play the fucking game
as well because like
I will just keep talking if if not stopped
medications that are designed to help people through addiction
for example medications that like
if the person is taking opiates
we're talking heroine fentanyl these sorts of things right
like your brain has opiate receptors that crave intake
and certain medications can basically just park in that receptor
and so the body is like okay well there is something
taking up that slot
it's not all the way there
but like even if you were to try to smoke a fentanyl pill
that medication is already parking in the spot for the receptor
so there's a good chance that
that person's not even gonna get high from it
and that's gonna reduce the sense of craving
it's going to reduce the kinds of like fucked up
damage that does to this whole process
and the person is
eventually with medication and therapy
and peer support and all kinds of other good stuff
going to find that their impulses to use
no longer hijack the healthy operation of this network
so medication is good too
with the right understanding and intention
we haven't done drugs yet in the game
but they give you a bonus to the whole stat line
but that's only temporarying comes off with other side effects yeah
yeah I if I could like
do a breakdown of every single encounter in this game
I would I would but we would never finish it so
let's continue
but now we understand why this is happening
this two lines of dialogue
so let's ground ourselves back in this okay
now that we have like a very
basic understanding of the cognitive model
and the way that drugs are currently
impairing and in fact causing this problem
what kind of behaviors do we think are going to happen
there's a difference between what I want to say here
and what I think my character would say here
so let's get Kim involved
Kim I think I should tell people to fuck off more often
it felt really good
fuck yeah motherfuckers
it's not really my style
we're going with it's not really my style
because we are starting to develop
more into our core belief that we are sorry we're apologetic
we find that that our behaviors
our behavior of telling people to fuck off right
this right here this confrontational
it's coming from giving us a sense of relief
and getting rid of shame
but we're starting to not like this about ourselves just like
I as a person do not like that I get defensive
which I you know I admit frequently like
I don't like that my first reaction
is often defensiveness and avoidance
but you know I understand that's
that's a behavioral result of feeling insecure and that
you know the core belief is like
people don't like me or something
so
sorry cop is finding the confrontation
and the avoidance of shame through relief about confronting people
does not
it's not good for us
we're trying to learn a better way to get relief
without it having to replace shame
and resulting in worse social circumstances
so
let's explore another route to that
and say it's not really my style
hey I've got an idea on how to fix your style
maybe you should just go fuck yourself
yeah ever thought of that
yeah I have thought of that half life
but I starting to think that you're my enemy now
rejected half light rejected
and I don't give a fuck if it damages my morale
sometimes you have to go through a process of rupture and repair
rupture and repair
that's healing
let's
ooh okay
now that we're sorry cop we can investigate this
but we're still not there yet
what was I doing
I was gonna go see Frittte girl
the best character
oh my god this poor thing
is she working still
it's nearly 10 PM honey what are you doing here
I was here like in the morning
how long is her shift
overtime
okay
here's the thing all right
I want to talk about Frittte girl a little bit
if you allow me to indulge a little bit and like
how would I actually approach therapy with this young woman
who from my perspective
spends an inordinate amount of time
doing something that she hates
what do you think that that's going to do to her own self esteem
because I can imagine a lot of her thoughts throughout the day
just being negative ones like this is a waste of time
these people are annoying
I don't like being here
I'm bored
I don't know
I hate this right
how many negative thoughts
do you think are crossing through her mind
and how much of her emotion is going to be dominated by like
feelings that ask her to disconnect
she may feel moments of sadness
she may feel moments of grief
time that she is losing where she could be spending time with friends
where she could be on summer holiday somewhere enjoying life
regret for the decisions made
or the fact that the only way that she sees
to climb out of her economic circumstances
is to work a job that she hates and endure
living a life where
the pipeline of her thoughts are going to be clogged with negativity
how many negative thoughts do you think she's having every single day
because you and I have millions of them
millions constantly right like
thoughts just constantly constantly constantly
when you're in environment where every single one is negative like this
okay
this is her world right now okay
how many positive thoughts a day is she having compared to this
like it's an insane amount
and so at the end of the day
when she gets her paycheck and she maybe has one good thought
like hey I can go buy myself something
this is not a healthy balance
for someone who is still developing
it's not even a healthy balance for someone who is fully developed
like this is what working a shit job that you hate feels like
is you spend all day
doing whatever you can not to observe and reflect on the
overwhelming amount of negative thoughts that you're having
and trying to find ways to avoid or suppressed the negative emotions
for example
spending all her time reading a magazine instead of like working
taking extra breaks while you're working
doing your work slower
like we're all looking for ways to avoid
the kind of busy work that results in this
especially because the job that she's working is not super demanding
she has to spend a lot of time just hanging around and waiting
and that makes her vulnerable to actually like hearing these things
you know if I'm like doing a job where it's like labor or something and
there's a lot of like menial tasks that I'm doing
I'm I'm probably not gonna think a lot about this stuff
I'm probably still having them but I'm not vulnerable to the onslaught of them
but she's sitting here day in day out
for whoever knows how many fucking hours
and she has to observe every
negative thought that's coming through her mind
and maybe every once in a while a positive one wanders through
but it's not preparing her for like positive emotions right
and what kind of behavior is this going to lead into
it's going to lead into being disinterested
right it's going to make her avoidant of conversation
isolation
it's not telling her that this is relaxing
just because she's not doing anything
it's not telling her that socializing
cures her of the awareness of all of this negativity
and she's standing all day long
she is tired she is completely burnt out from this
you can just tell
from the way that she talks and and the like
the subtextual body language that you can hear there right
so like
this is not a good life for her it definitely isn't
so like what would I do to help her okay
again part of this would be trying to explore with her
if she can't get out of this situation
then we need to sort of discover something that
makes this worthwhile for her
because the meaning of it right now is just
I have to do this because I have no other choice
presumably right
and so I'm burdened with all these negative thoughts
and there's no cure for that
I would really want to know what does she want from life right
what would she rather be doing with her time and
exploring with her ways that she might
get that same sensation not in her workplace right
because
the best she can do is just escape into this little book
right this little magazine
but how many times can she read it and not get bored
it's so heartbreaking
I would ask her like what's going on at home you know
does anyone ask you like what what your day was like
and do you speak to them honestly because
I I have the feeling that like when she's talking to let's say her parents
it would be like yeah work was fine
well did anything interesting happen
um I don't know right
I'm assuming that the parents don't care but maybe they do
maybe they do and she's just so disaffected that
she doesn't know how to communicate
because nothing interesting is happening right
she doesn't know how to make this interesting
yeah she might say fine
but like fine is the worst thing that you can say therapeutically
when we say the word fine
what we really mean is we're functional
we are functioning we are standing here
we are completing the day we are cashing the check
we're doing things we're doing behaviors but like
we're just doing behaviors
we're not having any of the resulting emotions right
like this word is garbage it's terrible for you
it doesn't tell a good story at all
and it really limits
your ability to like search for a solution
what I find fascinating is
and I do this a little bit on purpose
this word is so common
and the English language is so poisoned with
hey how you doing how's going good
all that stuff that like just common small talk that
what I'll do sometimes is like
I'll go get my client and then on the way to the therapy session
like if I'm pulling them from you know group therapy session
and I'm going to take them to do individual
I will ask them
while we're on the way
so how's your day going
and they'll say you know it's going all right
and then when we get in the session
I'll be like so you know what's going on lately
and they're like everything is terrible
ha I'm like
what does this tell you what does this tell you that
when someone asks our immediate response is just to
navigate that conversation with a common answer
which is that yeah things are okay
but then the mask comes off and no things are awful
it's not considered socially acceptable
so like how many opportunities is this young girl getting
to actually be honest about how she feels
it's zero
okay
I genuinely want to know
maybe she can try to see her work in a positive light
like hey these bottles look nice
organizing them is actually fun
but I feel like she'd run out of like
I love what our guys are doing
what are we doing
this poor girl
I love that they're doing this
Kim is helping me out with my back after I sat in that awful chair
sport fritter girl is like what the fuck is happening
but hey maybe I'm giving her something interesting to talk about at home for once
so I don't think I would use CBT with Frittte girl
let's see
so I think that
the approach that I would use
would kind of be
something like motivational interviewing
which is not so much a therapy style
as it is a general way of engaging someone
and sort of like
because like I'm going off an assumption
that she wants something bigger than life
but she probably has not had the platform to explore that subject
I would start asking her questions like
can you tell me some of your accomplishments
and she'd say I don't know
what did you make anything recently
did you make a good meal recently
did you read a good book
did you have a good conversation
right I would be sort of like
asking her to explore
things that she had completed
because this feels never ending
it's day in day out same bullshit all day every single day right
so
nothing feels like it has any markers of progress
and she'd be like um I don't know I guess right
so what did it feel like to finish that book
um it was okay
one thing that really works especially with teenagers
is like pretending you do not understand this word
I mean I understand it but like basically like
okay well assume I don't know what okay means like
you know can you tell me a different word like
it was cool
you know I don't know really what cool is anymore these days
like what are some other things that are cool
um I saw something you know
I heard something cool on the radio the other day
oh okay well what was it
it was a story about you know
a new technological development in this region
so what was so cool about it
well I don't know it was interesting I hadn't heard it before
so
what do you feel when you hear something interesting
like when you learn something new
um
I mean it's nice I guess
and like I'm picking up on every time that she qualifies something
as cool interesting nice
she minimizes it with I guess or I don't know
and I would start picking up on that pattern right
you know every time you say
something good happens I notice you tend to
minimize it afterwards
why do you think that you know you tend to do that
um I don't know
maybe because like I'm not sure about how I feel about it
and maybe I'm not sure if
I'm right like
if I say it's interesting and you think it's lame
you're gonna think I'm lame
so what do you think people feel about you generally right
I would want to know about her life and her world
and how she sees the world
I feel like she's so detached and so plagued by negative thoughts
that she doesn't have the vocabulary to discuss emotions
I would be trying to get her to discuss things that are cool interesting
let's expand that what does it mean to be interesting
I don't know this word
break it down for me
what does it mean when something is interesting
well it's fun to learn something new
it's cool that I can share it with someone else
and I feel like they'll feel like it was worthwhile talking to me
because they learned something new
and suddenly I feel a little less worthless
wow that's a much deeper story than this was interesting
let's build on that
you just told me a great story about what it was like to feel something good
and you may have actually done that in a place
where the rest of your life is on hold paused frozen
in this fucking dystopia of a clerk shop
Frittte girl
she's the key to everything wait a second
okay does she have any new dialogue from
um is this about the questions again
because I don't really know anything
I'm gonna cry can I
can I just pull her out of here
she doesn't know anything can you go home please
when do you get off work go home
okay let's let's turn in our money
the tare machine stands in the corner
a sign says "one bottle = 10 cents"
your bottles clunk into the machine
and the money appears with a satisfying jingle
you're a richer man now
d'you know what you should do with that money kiddo
you should *buy more alcohol*
enter the endless cycle of consumption
the thing is is I'm finding my
electrochemistry to wield less power over me
the more I get acquainted with volition
the more I develop a
a yearning for Kim's approval
these impulses are starting to influence me a little less
because they are very much built what my shame is built on
maybe there is some other dialogue I can ask her
I don't know I'm gonna leave her alone for now
okay let's go talk to Garte
fuck you
fucking garbage
just standing there all day
Lena
Best the second best character after Frittte girl
sorry I don't mean to blast you with with flashlight
okay can I can I barter with this guy
can I help you
so about that money I owe
yes have you got it
how much do I owe you again
a lot for the room and broken window 100 reál
how the fuck am I supposed to pay that
let's talk about something else
like what
I was really enjoying talking about the *money* you owe me
here's your trash container key
thanks I hope you found what you were looking for
he doesn't need to know that that's privileged information
just trash
as it should be
anyway thank you for returning my key
goodbye
so what can I like not go to sleep or something
well kuno is the key to a part of this
take bribes
do something else for now
it's like Elena see what she's got
hello again sweetie
ah
sweeties need money do swedies get money
does she have any money for me
I don't want to pedal her but
oh sweetie
I heard your conversation with the manager about your
financial troubles
when do you get your next paycheck
if she could this woman would feed and clothe you
and every other sad lost person on this earth
angel
you've got guns of steel and a chiselled jaw
(somewhere under the bloated alcohol layer)
maybe she'd like to sponsor you
tug on her heart strings
is this exploitative though
I mean I feel like it's in sorry cops
character
to just be honest
that like this is one of the only people that
that I feel would not judge me unfairly
for just asking for help
this would be a huge step for my character
because like I said about the apology as a utility
we would not want to use it as brute force to manipulate people
or to feel that receiving forgiveness is doing the actual work
we need to apologize
accept feedback and make meaningful change
and expect nothing in return
let's ask for help
we've got a 97 percent chance here
your deportment remains dignified
as you shed a single manly tear
it isn't easy for me to ask this of anyone
but I am at the end of my rope
any money you have could help me
I feel like there is a impulse to be prideful
but like this is huge
I would be so proud of my client for
genuinely asking for help when they need it
rather than looking for unscrupulous means to subvert this responsibility
this is good for us
sweetie I only have a few cents on me but I
I could give you this to pawn just to tide you over
no
wonderful he has a pin
the pin is round and slightly tarnished
oh I guess we can't take it back
three sailboats in bas-relief with the sun hovering over the water behind them
a chip to green banner at the bottom reads
Saint-Batiste Summer'31--Dinghy Races
okay I'm so glad that we can make this up to her
because I don't want to
just cope on this
I will buy it back for you once I have more money
oh it's not an ancient family heirloom or anything but
I suppose it *would* be nice to get it back
I will do everything in my power to do it
I hope you are able to palm that old trinket
okay at least I can give it back
just want to thank you again
of course dear
I just wish I could have done more
part of me just wants to give it back and find an honorable way to do this
I would like to explore other means to collect this money
and if I can't I will use it but
unusually tasteful pin was produced to
celebrate the Saint-Batiste Summer'31
oh man this is
it doesn't have enough
it's not enough money to cover this
so I'm just gonna give it back I think
I mean I guess I can always get it from her if I need it
I hope you were able to palm that old trinket
no I just can't do it I just can't do it
I just can't do it
yeah
thank you dear
I confess I am glad to see it again
I just got in some free experience
even the lieutenant seems happy with this turn of events
solid demonstration of character from us
we've won some favor with Kim
now what else sweetie
I couldn't do it Lena sorry
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it consider giving it a like
and letting me know what you thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a little bit earlier if you support the channel
either through Twitch or Patreon
links to both of those and the community discord are in the description
thanks again and I will see you next time
bye