hello
and welcome back to my
therapist plays Disco Elysium analysis series
okay I'm really excited about today's episode
we're finally getting into our first
encounter with the union boss Evrart Claire
and kind of breaking down lots of different
psychological angles on power dynamics and
have a lot to share today on real techniques that
I actually use in my practice as a therapist
to navigate sort of like difficult conversations with people who
either don't want to talk to you
or are in some sort of power struggle
and how do you sort of get that person opening up about things
we're gonna use some of these techniques on Mister Claire
and by the end of this episode
we're going to learn a little bit more about
ourselves and what kind of cop we are
yes we're finally getting our cop type
I'm sure very few of you will be surprised at what I end up with
so I'm excited to share this one
let's dive in
okay so
I have an objective
I have the objective to progress this game storyline like
I do want to
just like
mention why I am going about playing this game this way
because I do think it's relevant
when you see my character
do things like just totally give up on pursuing the narrative
to try to find like cigarettes for example
this is a role play right
so sometimes I'm gonna be speaking as like Brady the therapist
sometimes I'm gonna be speaking as like
Brady the degenerate who is using this as a kind of
escapism from my very serious real life
that I
like this is where I get to give be a goofball
and sometimes I'm gonna like
speak from the voice of my character right
and just like
say random nonsense garbage that I think he would
say or think right
and one of the things that
it is really important about
this character specifically because he is
someone representing the struggle of addiction is how like
we have all kinds of priority structures in our mind
right like
there's the whole just basic needs hierarchy of
like you need food you need water you need rest
and only once those things are satisfied
can you really focus on like higher order things like
you know your self esteem and your self worth and
the balance of health and your relationships
and those sorts of things right
the problem with addiction is that
your body has become dependent on on a chemical
one that is harmful to you
and so it completely hijacks what should be a normal
set of priorities right
and for example like your self esteem
when that is intact
and when you can focus on that as a priority
like
you may be able to say
okay I am going to go complete this task
I am gonna go talk to someone
I am going to ask this person what they think
I'm gonna canvass the scene I'm gonna do real
fucking police work okay
but that's like a higher order thing
my body being
chemically dependent on a substance is telling me no
this is more important this is basically
comparable to your body needs food
it needs this chemical right
like nicotine is a stimulant
so like that's hijacking basically like my
a sympathetic nervous system and telling me
like you're in danger without this thing right
opiates and
depressants like alcohol
they hijack more
like the parasympathetic side of your nervous system
which is all about like the body being at rest
and so
imagine you are someone who is
addicted to both alcohol and cigarettes
and you have two halves of your nervous system
one that deals with very active compulsions
fight-or-flight response
that's your sympathetic and your parasympathetic
which is dealing with the body at rest
regulating heart rate and all that stuff
and you're doing a stimulant on one side
and a depressant on the other
and like they're just pulling you apart basically
and both sides are demanding
you keep this train going right
it's totally going to hijack
whatever like logical emotional empathetic sides of you
that have like all these fucking things to do
if this is your life
like how many things we have to do here
and we've only been like at this for like a day basically
how do you prioritize that
when when something is hijacking that whole system
and telling you like no the most
important thing that you do right now is
you find a way to like get high
or you know
you're not showing the intelligence
that you think you have in these conversations
so like you feel smarter when you're buzzed on nicotine
so go find a cigarette
right like that's the path I'm sort of role playing
when I'm like ooh I'm not gonna get distracted
actually stop everything
let's go find cigarettes like it's all a part of that
okay I'm trying to like represent
the struggle the real struggle
which this game is perfect at demonstrating
so far
probably worth saying that you already do have a past
so role playing as a therapist
might not come through much in the gameplay
well that's true
I've given up on that pursuit
because I didn't know that really when I started this
I thought that this game was gonna be like
just role play
I I didn't know that there was gonna be a
concrete narrative to my character
so I was just kind of like gonna put something in there
but I realized that
now that I've played some more
that's not really relevant so
yeah I mean like I'm very satisfied with the personal
narrative that our character has been through so far
despite us not playing the game very well
I'm okay with it
so as I've already failed at my mission to progress this game
let's continue let's fucking do it okay
what are we gonna do now
we gonna talk to the union boss
I gotta I gotta solve this murder
let's do that
what is this
the coffee and the giant thermoses is still lukewarm
okay we've made coffee recently
a stair made of pallets leading up
oh this must be the union boss
so he hangs out in like storage container
and office as this of
interesting environment
he's got here
where he got up there
swordfish
tells the time
until I run into another clerk look you guys
you guys are starting to detect my patterns
it's like
store clerks
there they're the unseen like pillars of society right
like everything goes through them
every chain of commerce and structure in society passes through
like the the line of store clerk right like
your personal money goes to them
you buy your essentials
that goes back into the economy
they see everything
they've got hidden insights that
the rest of us could only dream of
it's store clerks and children
I have very passionate like
feelings when I see hardships depicted for children
like I said I know I tried to hit Cuno
but it's part of the role play
I'm doing what I think my character would do
which is chase his erratic compulsive contradictory impulses
okay let's talk to this gentleman
let's see what he's got to say for us he's very busy
before you
is the warrus of a man seated behind a large desk
he looks up from his work
not the least bit surprised to see you
okay this lean back hands behind the back of the head it's a
immediate power play okay
I'm putting my detective skills at work here
all right
this gentleman sees me with my flashlight
and now I feel like personified by wearing my coat
we're immediately in a power struggle
with great effort
he straightens himself up in his chair yet says nothing
he simply stares at you
look at this power play
he's trying to size me up
he wants to see what I'm all about
a typical power play
wait for him to speak first
show him you've got a backbone
what is happening in this play through
this is the weirdest real life
like
where my brain is cohesively attached to the game
this has never happened to me before
where like my direct thoughts get an immediate answer by
a game's narrative
this is scary
a typical power play yes
a volition coming in strong with a 12 point
wait for him to speak first
show him you've got a backbone
okay volition let's
say nothing look him dead in the eye
I wish the game
if the game
acknowledges that I have a flashlight in my hand
just like it acknowledged that I had a crowbar in my hand
I'm gonna freak out
I'm blasting this guy with photosensitivity right now
the one good eye of this man
fills you up without even flickering the other
his lazy eye is constantly moving
like a goldfish in a tank
grotesquely magnified by his plus 6 glasses
a perception it's back intact
it's the fucking coat man
let's go this is a this is a boss fight
this is a boss fight of the mine
for a moment you don't know where to look
it is unbearably humid in the trailer
beads of sweat slide down the man's forehead
okay
I'm going to progress this a little bit
but then I'm going to tell you how
I actually in real life deal with
getting people who do not want to talk to you to like
give you information
again from the therapist's point of view like
the the reason I'm trying to get information from them
is to help them
like if I'm working with someone who is like
I don't want to fucking talk to you
and my interest is in like
talking about things will help you through this
how do you actually get that person to
like if you can't get them to trust you immediately
how do you just get them to start communicating
I'll I'll share one of my secret techniques
yet he's unperturbed holding his own
keep staring
endure this
endure this discomfort
at first nothing happens
his face wears a wide and self satisfied smile
every now and then he smacks his big lips
okay so I will tell you about it right now actually
because this is about power dynamics right
the game very clearly identified that so
there is a technique in
I wouldn't say even just like therapy
but it could very well apply to detective work as well
it's called the foot in the door technique okay
and here's how it works
it originated from
I think like
people making like house visits or something
like to individuals who needed help
I'm not totally sure on the history of this but
it's called foot in the door technique because
let's say that I already know I'm invited in somewhere
I don't need clearance to come into this person's house
like I've already gotten that
but I still ask them
may I come in please and they might say yes
I come inside
there is a social unspoken agreement
that like okay I'm now in your house
you sit down I'm okay to sit down
but what do I do instead I ask may I sit here
yes
right I may ask a few more questions like this
like do you mind if I cross my legs
do you mind if I you know take my shoes off right
you ask these kinds of questions to
someone who is you already know
is going to be kind of difficult to work with
do you understand why
why might I start asking questions that I already
know I'm going to get approval for
I'm curious if you can spot the answer
right in fact you may find that like
doing it too much the person starts to get like yes
I don't mind you know like just do
whatever you know you don't need my permission
can you guess
I'm curious to see
making them feel more in control
to show respect for their space
so Immortalzolris
you have it right
if you agree to one thing
you're more likely to agree to other things
is something called compliance momentum
basically right like
if you can get someone to comply
to something very simple
like may I come into this residence may I sit here
psychologically it has primed this person
that the beginning of your relationship is
they have already like
agreed to something with you
you have built an initial foundation of like
agreement collaboration and like this
very small very faint thread of like trust in someone
so it's called compliance momentum
that's what you can build with someone
and so like this is useful all the time
like I said I work with a lot of people who maybe
you know
being released from incarceration or something maybe
maybe on probation
the vast majority of them are actually pretty like fine
and eager to actually start working with me like
I find that most people
especially after
you know going through something as difficult as that
they they're like yes I wanna work on myself like I really
you know appreciate this opportunity to learn more about myself
like I don't really have this issue very often
but there is the rare case where someone is just so
they've been so damaged and so like
learn to mistrust people
not to any of their own fault that
they're just totally
shut down and they don't want to talk to you
and so I will use a lot of compliance momentum right
you know I'll open my office door and like
I'll ask them
you know do you mind if I open the blinds a little bit right
you know do you mind if like I
have my notebook next to me
do you mind if I drink some water right
just little shit like that right
if I just start immediately asking them questions like
hey so what are you feeling right now
what's going on in your mind I will just
I'll just get that right
but even if I'm just getting a nod from them
if I'm even just getting a little bit of this
communication
it's communication
we're working on the problem already right
so it's really useful for that
again the entire objective is to
build a kind of rapport so that you can help them so
that is exactly what I would be doing with this
gentleman right here
as he stares me into the abyss
I would start asking him questions
make him think he's in control of this okay
again
this is a role play
when I start like acting unhinged
as I'm talking like right now
that's that's Brady the character
when I'm like talking seriously that's like
that's me in real life okay I just
I'm gonna get in trouble with like certain
parts of the audience who are like you are bad
therapist
or something but like
that's okay you know like
part of what I'm doing is
trying to give a little bit of education
but then also like a little bit of dramatization right
I had a therapist do this when I was a teen
and I really didn't want to participate
well yeah no I mean
it doesn't always work right
it's a certain kind of technique for a very certain approach
and like I said
most of the time I do not have to do that
I I find generally that most people
are not on high alert you know if they're coming and
Iit's not like they learn five minutes ago
that they're gonna be meeting with a therapist
you know
they've already had time to sort of like think about uh
what am I gonna get out of this and
I will always ask them like
have you been to therapy before
was it a good experience
if they say no
you know I'll ask them
you know to tell me a little bit about that and
whatever they say it was like
I immediately tried to mirror
that it's going to be something different than that
right
oh it did help me
I just realized what she was doing in retrospect
it's interesting yeah
there's also door
so that's what I would be doing with this gentleman
speaking of power dynamics I will also give you another
here I am I
we're progressing the narrative today
I don't care how long it takes okay
I've used this technique before
so like I immediately spotted when I was
starting to work with someone that they
they saw this as a power struggle
like the therapeutic relationship they thought
you know if you have the impression that like
therapists are trying to get in your head
or get in your mind or something
you're gonna be kind of wary of that
and so like
I had someone come into the therapy room once and
you know there was my chair
and then there was a chair where like a client might sit
and when I walked in I
just kind of ushered them into the room
and they sat in like my chair
and I could see there was a similar verbal
like nonverbal communication
like there was a lean back there was like a
you know getting comfortable like
I've just sat in your chair
what are you gonna do now
I'm the boss of this
and so what I did was I calmly just
took the seat for the client
and then just continued to do what I was doing
I didn't acknowledge this at all
I didn't participate in the power struggle like
when you don't participate in it it doesn't exist essentially
and I ended up doing some very good work with that person
and like it was actually
really helpful for building trust with them
because
they didn't feel like I was like ah
you know I'm I'm gonna
upset the power balance by doing this...
what what I think they got out of that was like
oh I don't need to like wear this mask for this person
you know I don't need to
( I don't need to) be in a power dynamic with them
and so like we had a very good
trusting therapeutic relationship from them
Brady
play the game
we're in a power struggle here
sorry this stuff is just really interesting to me
let's go
like a general over his maps he plots his moves
judging by the way he is licking his chops
it's going to be a good one
okay authority help me out here
this is a power struggle so you know what to do
yes we've gotten him to speak
Mr Du Bois Mr Kitsuragi
how nice since you found a moment
to pay a visit to the Debardeurs union
I'm Evrart Claier
head of this little operation here
who the fuck is Du Bois
please have a seat
he gestures to a *tiny* folding chair
opposite to his giant desk
what did I just say
okay the way that your space is laid out
people who see the world in terms of power dynamics like this
consciously or unconsciously see every single environment
as a field to do this kind of battle with
only if you start assigning the same kind of like weight to it
does it actually work though
like I said I just let
if the client sits in my chair
I just sit in their chair
it's just a chair it's me right
the folding chair looks like a torture device
extremely uncomfortable
you go ahead detective
okay Kim Kim has got he's got my back this time
you know what we went through with measurehead
I feel like actually started to strengthen our bonds
especially after he like
he picked up that coin and gave it to me
like I've legitimately been thinking about this
that moment
like since I experienced it
this is where
Kim and I are on a sort of like compliance momentum
right like
that kind of shit would work with someone like my guy
what I'm finding
what I found at the beginning is that Kim would like
he would say
you take the lead
but then I would feel like he was undermining me right
or he
he would criticize my judgments or something like that
and what I'm finding now is
he's like
he's not just like seeing what I'm gonna do
he's kind of allowing me to
actually take the leader
whatever he has in store for you
it can't be good
he thinks I'll do my best
yeah do not be surprised if this conversation
takes us two hours
because I already have a lot to say about it
it's just like I cannot be anyone but myself
unfortunately
forget about that
what's with this De Bois stuff
you're getting some seriously bad vibes from that name
yeah I don't really know
I'll be honest though I'm gonna
just like admit that I've been spoiled on the fact that like
Raphael
Ambrosius Costeau is not my name
it's harry like that's just
that's just a result of uploading stuff to YouTube and
people get excited
I understand that
so I'm already aware that
we have...that Raphael was a fake name
I think that's pretty cool
I actually see it as
it fits in line with Inland Empire here
which to me
Inland Empire has been the force that is trying to
keep you from figuring out who you were
right it's one of the competing mental states that is
in one sense you could say well it's on your side
it's trying to help you
it's empathizing
it's telling you like don't get involved with who you were
it makes you feel bad it has a bad vibe to it
build a new personality from where you are right
but from my point of view
as the therapist and really just as a human
like I think that
this is a kind of avoidance right
I want to
approach who I was but in a sensitive and slow way
I haven't looked in the mirror yet for example
I haven't discovered what my name was
I think right now
where my character is at
especially after seeing those bottles on the ground
going back into our bedroom
like we're starting to get a little more comfortable
with the idea of approaching our past self
we're wearing the coat for example
but we're not sure if we like that person yet
I think that right now I would be saying something like
why are you calling me Mr Dubois
but that would upset the power dynamic
so I'm just going to
what did Kim tell me to do
I don't want to undermine him either
Kim told me to
sit in the chair so I'm going to listen to Kim
we are two and he is one
we've got a we've got a standstrong in this one
take a seat
excellent Mr Dubois
I can see that you are a reasonable man
and reasonable men
reasonable men can be of great use to one another
remain serious
stick through this
so tell me how can the head of the Debardes union
help a representative of the Revershal Citizens militia today
okay starting off with
letting me clarify my purpose here
we know that there's another purpose here okay
I'm here to arrest you or I don't know
the chair you're sitting on has
got to be the most uncomfortable chair in the world
it's *violating* your backside
by the way
I heard you got a rather rude reception from a certain
Lawrence *Garte*
some people have no manners it pains me to say
he's trying to sympathize with me
he's trying to draw me into his little game
I don't like it I see right through
*this* should take care of that nonsense
hmm it's a bribe
he points to a giant novelty cheque on his desk
it's absolutely comically huge
it should be sufficient to cover your expenses for a few days
and patch over your differences with a cafeteria manager
go ahead take it
so he wants me to become dependent on him
not gonna work fellow
hey that's 25 real
that's good money
think of all the *stuff* you could
okay electrochemistry coming in doing exactly what I
said it would do right
electrochemistry is
in my interpretation could be wrong but
the voice that it often speaks from
the way I see it is from the nervous system
it is the priority structure at the foundational layer
which gets hijacked by impulses and desires
it's basically like the ID right in like a Freudian sense
the thing is is like in real life listening to volition
and and like a
savoir fair like the things that are good for you
they take a lot of effort
it takes me a lot of effort to like eat a healthy meal
one it's more expensive
two I have to spend time like planning it
thinking about the calorie intake
making sure it's like you know
I have time to prepare it and all these things
like it's way easier to just go eat junk food
it's not as good for me
logically and morally I know it's not as good for me
but it is harder to listen to volition
and things that are good for you
the voices that are good for you because they take more  effort
it's way easier to listen to like electrochemistry
because it deals in base impulses and
my character has a substance use issue
that has rewired his priorities
there is some tension here between
I'm trying to stick to the high effort stay composed
don't show that you're in pain
but I'm also thinking I could buy a lot of cigarettes with that
......*owe*him for?
this is a trap
I don't want to show that I
don't know the relation here
I don't want
some part of me wants me to wants to keep up the
idea that like we're in collaboration here
but I also think it would be a fucking power
play to just deny the check
the thing is is a little bit of me makes me feel like
having
having my partner with me
makes me feel like
like that's a certain kind of pressure as well
like I've embarrassed myself in front of Kim so many times
that that's a source of anxiety
that's competing with the like
well what if I can't buy my next
substance or something
what will Kim think
yeah he probably disapprove
keep it
okay okay
I respect a man with principles
no handouts then
he crosses his arms on his ample midsection
and sinks further into his chair
okay so
change in body posture
okay
wide open stance like this
I'm in control
arms across the chest
I'm feeling a little defensive
now I'd like to set your mind at
ease about one other matter
your *lost gun*
let me assure you
union people are on it as we speak
I've got my best hounds looking for that *lost gun*
it does seem like
we are previously intertwined with this gentleman
and he knows that
his slug like lips move
but all you hear is an echo
lost gun lost gun lost gun
what he does not know though is that we
have lost our memory
because he's operating on like
an assumption that：I know what the fuck he's talking about when I don't
the world is swallowed by a black hole of fear
only two words escape its gravitational pull
*lost* and *gun*
but I don't need my gun
I have not needed it once
if I just take a look at my character okay
I have already demonstrated that I
have the physical prowess to take down measure head
you did have a conversation about losing your gun though
well but with Kim
it's part of me being a decent cop
but I want to show confidence here
keeping your shit together
that's okay I'm not worried
I don't need a fucking gun
what did I call them
viper and
I forget whatever he called his arms
the union have eyes and ears that's okay
I got this
Kim's got a gun
are you all right Harry
you say you got this
but you seem a little *anxious* to me
don't be everything's going to be all right
anxious I'm not anxious
little anxious
it's not like you left it loaded
you didn't lose a *loaded gun*
local children aren't out there playing with it right now
pointing it into their own mouth
it's in a safe place
I just know it
I have a feeling everything's going to be alright
he's trying to he's trying to set me up
it was loaded
there were two bullets in it
you always keep at least two barrels loaded
shit
okay I don't have an option here this
don't panic
I mean there's no harm in
doing this right
look I
just accept I am never really going to figure out this system
okay
I know it's killing some people to watch me play this and be like
this is how the check system works like
I'm gonna re-evaluate whether this works every single time
I guess I could get Kim involved here
let's get Kim involved first
officer we will deal with this later
we don't need Mr Claire's help with this
we're on the same track
be so sure about that
but I have to choose this now
well I guess I have no other choice
whatever watch me
watch me fucking compose myself like you've never even seen before
God you're sweating
your knee is jerking
you're about to cry aren't you
you are about to cry
because you lost your gun
and those children are going to shoot themselves with it
no they are not
I mean they could
so what men can cry too
you *want* to cry
God you're weak
whatever you do
don't cry you'll think you're disgusting
God damn it
*Mr.Du bois* you don't look so good
hold it in Harry cry later
it'll be it'll be time for healing later
what is this *Mr.Du bois* he keeps repeating
*what* is he trying to pull here
Open it. Tell her to open the store.
you need to cool the fuck down
chill
kim
back me up
put your hand on my shoulder or something
Mr Dubois
Mr Dubois Harry
keep sliding down
this chair like a jello shot
there are no *harries*
let your mind go to a safe place
yes use your coping skills
while Everart is distracted by your odd behavior
the lieutenant's eyes are mapping everything around
the folder
desk papers on the wall
investigate him Kim
Mr.Du bois are you okay
can I get you a glass of water or something
are you having some kind of medical emergency
look we're doing we're doing healthy cop sick cop
all right while he's all focused on me
crumbling to little pieces in front of him
he's enjoying this
okay he's living for this
he's paying no
mind
to the stalwart studious
composed
Kim Kitsuragi behind me
scoping out his whole fuckin game plan okay
he's taken all of this information in
and if I have to
let my ego die
to progress this case then I will do it
I will do it
and we will succeed in spite
of how broken I am as a person
maybe you could use your hands somehow
in a kind of throwing motion
like your throwing that Mr.Du Bios act right back at him
*he's* Mr Dubois
I'm melting
actually this chair is uncomfortable
I could use that glass of water
hmm oh yeah man I'm fucking great keep sliding
nah I'm good as it gets
Mr Dubois
vaguely gesture with your hands above your head
umm...
I don't like any of these options but
that's just life
that's just life sometimes
I don't like like all of life's options either
again I'm gonna try to remain as composed
I can install for time
Kim is scoping the scene right now
what an odd demonstration
of huh
you got me Harry
I don't even know what
as entertaining as it was
I'm afraid we're wasting our time
and I'm an extremely busy man as I'm sure you are too
I am very busy
okay enough we are here to ask you some questions
pertaining to a murder investigation
yeah
investigate him Kim and then let‘s arrest him
quick here's your window
get yourself together and ask him questions
police officer questions
reaction speed let's go
it is about time to stop embarrassing yourself
questions will help you regain
some of your lost dignity
thank you volition
I appreciate
that
this whole series
has been about embarrassing myself
okay
let's hesitate on on asking questions about ourselves
we want to find out
what the union is involved with the drug trade okay
this all gets back to
lady at the docks
pier Joyce
she knows something about the case
she won't talk to us cause I don't have my badge
I don't have my badge cause I am a wreck of a human
she'll only do so if we get the drugs out of Martinaise
so I'm confronting him
so we can figure out where the drugs are
and then solve that
and then talk to Joyce
and she'll help us solve the murder
and then I will impress Cuno
okay I just need to recap where I'm at here
I am looking into your shady brew
I'm told the union is involved in the local drug trade
let's ask him
well
some questions that's not a question that's a statement
so I should really go with like
what's in the container that's outside your office
okay let's try the compliance momentum all right
let's get him to answer some very simple questions
so that he is primed to answer more complicated ones
my dear Harry
there are literally millions of containers in this harbour
I couldn't possibly remember what's in all of them
there's something special about it
it was attached to the Kvalsund crane
Harry you smooth talking son of a bitch
time is a precious resource
and I don't have enough of it
to count containers with you
sounds like you're getting a little anxious buddy
smooth talking
maybe that's the way to go about opening the container
you should at least try convincing it
I already tried that it didn't work
okay let's try another tactic here
aren't you going to ask me how I got in
am I going to ask
hell Harry you spin kicked my strongest man in the face
I saw it from my window
yeah well you should be scared
cause I'll spin kick the fuck out of you right now
would you ask a man like that
how he got into your container yard
he doesn't have a window that's a good point
it was a figure of speech Harry
of course I don't have a window I'm in a container
this is this is a very subtle battle of our wits
or maybe I really do sound like an idiot
I genuinely don't know at this point
anyway I assure you I am a very well informed man
information reaches me
before I even get the chance to request it
let's change subjects before we get into this
you call me Mr Du Bois
why
of course let us dispatch with the formalities
you call me Evrart
I call you Harry
that's what the hang of the corpse called you Harry
so that's really my name
my God so it's true
I didn't want to believe it
but you are a fantastic science fiction
amnesiac cop aren't you
what are the odds of that
figured me out
are very low
my memory is fine I'm just testing you
where do we go with the honest question
the honest statement here
let's uh let's let's hold our grout
so good to hear that Harry
apparently my sources were wrong
however if you did have a spot of memory trouble
I could help you out
with my big fat folder
no
are you trying to tell me
you've gotten a hold of some of our documents
let's go Kim I knew you would be on it
Mr Kitsuragi would you mind
me and Harry are talking about his lost identity right now
asking too many questions will make you look weak
you should maybe focus on the folder
what the hell
volition you just told me to ask him questions
I did read the shipping folders but it's not a
there's no way I can pass that right now
let's just keep asking him things
uhhhh
maybe I will circle back to this
or let's just ask him where he got it
ah this
my friends in your organization gave it to me Harry
I find that very suspicious
may I have a look
put the squeeze on him Kim
I'm afraid this is meant for union eyes only
Mr Kitsuragi I'm sure you understand
please continue Harry
Kim suspect something
and I've read the folders before
this increased my chances
do I have any skill points to put into drama
no
I can't ask him too many questions
what kind of cop does it say I am lets try that
well Harry if I were to sum you up in one word
it would be apologetic
I'm sorry
yes
you seem to be
a lot of the time
but right now there's no reason to be
let loose a little
be you
we are learning more things about ourselves okay
if I am my character if I'm Harry
and I am starting to become invested in the idea of
how much do I really want to know about myself
there are things I
there are some virtues I can detect
that make me want to do this
but there are some things I'm very terrified of
I am very scared of learning
that I am not a good person
I'm very scared of learning that I am actually not a good cop
that people don't see me as one that they don't like me right
I'm scared of the idea that the reason I lost my memory is
because I tried to do something to myself
because I hated myself
that's a terrifying thought
but like building the profile of someone who is invested in healing
there is a hesitation to learn these things
but there is an innate desire to learn them
let's get this straight
what's my full name
it's Harry Harry Du Bois
okay
you feel like a Du Bois
but you don't feel like a Harry
strange
you don't feel like any of these things
you know what your name is
you have a sophisticated name
like that of a ccount or a beautiful man
well that's bullshit that's not how we really feel
that's not my name my name is Raphael Costeau
okay I like it I can work with that
it's not so bad
Harry Dubois I like it it's a cool name
ah yeah
I failed at this
okay
and I can work with you Harry
now what else can I do for you
let's ask some other questions
of course Harry of course
I met Joyce
let`s not linger on personal details and amnesia
you wanted something from me
or let's talk about my lost gun I guess
maybe I can get some more information about the folder there
yes your lost gun
my best men are on it
they're turning every stone searching every playground
asking kids grandmas everyone
I find that hard to believe
your gun will be found Harry
let me assure you of that
it's just a matter of time and effort
the only way to find it seems to be working with him
he might even be holding your gun hostage
hold on could he really hold my gun hostage
I will not be blackmailed with this gun business
yeah I'm not gonna succumb to that
Harry Harry I was only trying to be tactful
a lost gun is a dangerous thing
I can't have it around in my neighborhood
kids could be playing gun roulette with it as we speak
teenage gangs could be arming themselves
get ahold of yourself Harry
he has mentioned children a lot
I don't think that was here
yeah but he he's he's pushing a lot on the kids angle
I think I have to go investigate
I assure you
we are working on locating the missing side armor as well
the lieutenant is concerned about the lost gun
and feels that
the fact you haven't prioritized looking for it
is unfortunate
if inevitable
and doesn't put the RCM in a good light
well what am I supposed to do Kim
do I stop all of this to find the gun
or do I work with the shady guy to get it
I can't do them both
excellent Mr Kitsuragi
that's excellent news
looks like we have a friendly
gun finding competition on our hands
okay
we're back in the power struggle this is it's intense
this is way harder than the
confrontation with measure head
let's see what he thinks about Joyce
oh that's very nice
I haven't gotten around to her yet
I'm very very busy you see
I hope you're getting along
one thing I want to make very clear Harry
is that this is not some kind of union
versus corporation situation
everyone is just pals here
just pals
we're all trying to do what's best for Martinaise
don't feel like you can't cooperate with her
because you and I are such good friends
and I'm helping you find your lost gun
I'm not a jealous guy
that's so nice of him
suspiciously nice
are you sure I find it a little odd
ooh we could press on the Mr Gaunont angle
Joyce said the previous union leader vanished under
let's just ask him what happened
let's see what his false narrative is
so that I have a little bit more room to investigate him
what do you mean Harry nothing I let him go
he made concessions for the company in previous negations since
why would you let an ally like that go
he's an old man Harry
I wanted him to spend more time with his family
god knows how long he's got left
you called him a midget
let's confront him
Harry I have little people in my organization
I would never call someone a midget
what is this
honestly I'm beginning to think you're a midget Harry
I'm only kidding Harry you're not a midget
no one is we're pals
I thought you just said you would never call someone that
and then you went back on your word
it's hard to say if he really lost his temper
or if this is another one of his tricks
this man almost never angers visibly
okay so disarming him in some ways
it's about challenging his character
not his power
his character he doesn't like it when his character is challenged
are you sure I find a little odd
I'm just a nice guy Harry
I wouldn't be where I am now if I wasn't nice
I'm sure you believe that
politics is all about emotions
and I want you to have positive emotion
when you think of me
okay then positive emotions it is
you like positive
no
no electrochemistry stop it
you're intruding
why haven't you let her in to see you
let's challenge his character
he does not like the idea that
I'm positioning his character as being inconsistent
let's go in
if she actually wants to see me she will find a way
voices raising up
and I just don't have anything to discuss with a bad negotiator
I feel like that's an honest statement
I feel like he's there's no mask behind that
he doesn't want to see her
it's as simple as that
he's starting to be a little more uh disarmed
let's push on the union leader angle
vanished
Harry the woman left her casserole in the oven
and couldn't make it here in time for the voting
oh did I leave my casserole on
better go home and check
the election can wait
when she got back the whole thing was over
Evrart Joyce seems to think the union is low balling her
low balling
of course
this isn't a casino Harry
real people real livelihoods are at stake here
but everything's a casino for those rich types
his expression makes it clear
this is childish and irresponsible behavior
okay let's talk about something else
of course Harry let me just assure you one more time
it's perfectly okay
to share anything we discuss here with this Joyce
this is a completely transparent organization
I feel
I have no interest in what she is doing
but I myself have nothing to hide
bullshit
your business is your business and I respect your privacy
just remember none of this is secret
he's trying to give me a false sense of security here
my brother's picture my singing swordfish clock
tell her how overweight I am
and how I'm helping you find your lost gun
tell her about everything
Evrart art doesn't mind
that's so suspicious
this is weird
not nice weird but okay
yeah
I want to talk about the hanging
oh of course that's your main thing here
that's why you're in Martinaise
I know everything that goes on around here
and I would love to help
like I'm helping you with your lost gun
I mean it's no secret
that the ynching is connected to the strike
so much to talk about
honestly it's been weighing on me so heavily
I understand you need to interview me
say nothing
but there's a thing that's been keeping me up at night
I want to talk about the hanging
I mean if we could just calmly talk
now fuck he's gonna tell me I need to do something for him first
This guy
yes that sounds good
let's do that
but I can't think straight
with this thing weighing on me
you are police officers aren't you
I have a crazy idea
you guys are basically door opening machines
incredibly talented at opening doors
I've opened a few doors in my life
let's see where this is going
and I'm sure you're gonna
open this one with flying colors Harry
this really is very simple
and there's nothing shady about it
oh that that that's what I was waiting for I needed to
first I needed to hear him say that it's not shady
and now I think it isn't
come on man
does this jiggling ooze think he's going to use you
he's got another thing coming
play his game son
with your eyes peeled
he's going to slip up
and when he does you're going to come out on top
fucking God damn right
that's the force that defeated measure head okay
now it's coming in with the intellect
whose door is it
oh no one's it's just a weasel a weasel lives there
nothing for you to worry about
why are you asking me to do it then
why not just open it yourself
Harry I'm a very busy man
and more importantly
I don't have that extraordinary fizzy cue do
you look like you could run around all day
I probably could
you want to send someone a message
that the police are working for you
that's right
I repeat I'm a very very busy man Mr Kitsuragi
and therefore I must occasionally enlist outside help
so what will it be Harry
what do you mean by a weasel
a about blabbering weasel
when weasels feel no one is watching
they start acting foolishly
again the the moment that I see from him
where he breaks from like this self security
is when there's a challenge to
the consistency of his character right
like
he doesn't like that someone is spreading something about him
he's putting on the the
the facade that like you can go tell
Joyce anything about me
right there's nothing to hide like
the idea that there
could be a part of him that could be misinterpreted is
scary to him
just go there unlock the door and leave it open
it's been such a burden on me Harry
I just want this to be over
so I can discuss business with you
I bet you don't even know anything about the hanging
Harry my dear friend
I am what people call a local bigwig
I know everything that goes on in Martinaise
I'm refusing I'm not doing this for you fuck that
of course Harry I understand
but if that's the case
I don't think we'll ever find your gun
even worse
we won't be able to speak like equals about the murder
how about I come back in here once I find my gun
and I pointed at you
yeah that wouldn't be very cop like
that's that's my
that's my authority coming
okay okay calm down
let's let's rebalance here
perhaps this was just bad timing for you
know that you can *always* come back to me
I really hope you do
for your sake my sake and for your gun's sake too
yes we both understand what you meant
this may be the only way he thinks
I won't hold it against you
in fact we probably *should* reconsider later
so what is this telling me that Kim thinks it's okay
if I go do this
I mean my thinking is like
if I say yes to the task
I at least get to know more about what his plans are
because then I can go investigate
and I don't have to do with this motherfucker wants
but I can at least like find out his intentions
audio from the game a little low
let's see if I can fix that
so help me out here guys
because again my goal is to actually progress the game
even at the best of my own role play sometimes
so it sounds like Kim is okay if we take on the task
once we get there though maybe we decide to do something else
play both sides
yes yes my best minute
yes yes my best men are
what's that Harry
you're getting a little pale
is it the words *paranoid schizophrenic*
and *lost gun* in one sentence
don't worry it's just a lead
it'll probably turn out to be nothing
yes yes what's that Harry
（选择选项）我正在重新考虑你让我开门的那件事 也许这样会有所帮助
you're getting a little pale
a fantastic change of heart Harry
go talk to Mañana down by the gates
he'll brief you and give you the key
okay
just open *one little door*
you don't need to go in or anything
I just want that weasel to come home and see the unlocked door
that's it anything else we should discuss
well we will be able to investigate that
but let's return to the question about the folder firm now
let's hear it Harry
hmm
maybe I should ask about this it could damage me though
this seems a little too desperate
the thing is is like I do want to know this but not from him
I am self aware enough to know that
he will weaponize that information whether it is true or not
so I am not going to ask
I'm not gonna ask this for now
maybe I can get a point in drama or something along the way
and come back to it
of course Harry of course
（选择选项）我们聊聊别的事吧
let's not linger on personal details and amnesia
好了我们走吧
you wanted something from me
wait you need this to get in and out through the gate
great wouldn't want to get stuck in here
here you're one of us now a real red and white union man
take care Harry
okay
I have made 42 percent checks for I also lost like a
hey so we've been monitoring you internally
and now we know your *copotype*
wait there are *copotypes* what is this
what is a copotype
yes guess what's yours
sorry cop
yes sorry cop
the cop who's sorriest
let's make it official then shall we
huge lack of enthusiasm going on in here
what are the other copotypes
oh you know
Apocalypse Superstellar
The Advanced Interesting Cop Liquid Shadow Cop
but you're too sorry to say those things
so here we go
so
I actually do think that okay
like I don't understand the
internalization thing yet
this is kind of only one of the
third or fourth times we've encountered it
here's the thing
I'll talk about the thought cabinet and all that stuff but like
I'll probably like wait till I'm much further in the game
and I've experienced a lot of it
and then I'll make a whole video on it or something like
cause I'll say some shit that's like stupid
if I start giving my interpretation now
other than to say that like obviously yeah
I could talk about how thoughts
start as thoughts and become core beliefs
I could talk about schemas
essentially like
every time a thought gets reinforced by something evidential
it can become a core belief over time
but core beliefs can be very maladaptive
meaning that they can develop out of like negative experiences
and when we internalize something
that's very negative about ourselves
it becomes very deeply rooted
and we often don't even know that
it's the source of many counterproductive behaviors
what that turns into is a lot of like
outward avoidance of inner conflicts
let me know if you would like me to go on
a very long thorough Tangent about that
or if you prefer I save it for like another time
the thing is is I think that my character
is the sorry type
if I'm thinking legitimately about
who my character is right now
and I actually based this on like
what does it look like when someone
finally crosses that threshold  of
how do I integrate who I was with who I am
in a way that like does not harm me right
in a way that feels like I'm making amends for those things
but not leaning more into like self destruction okay
and I have seen and do think that
a lot of apology would come through this right
because what is an apology right now to my character
what job does this category of behaviors and emotions and thoughts
what is it about right
my character right now feels like
I don't know enough about who I was
I don't know what I did
I'm not in control of the narrative that other people have about me
I don't know my own name
I don't know if I have a family
I don't know if I hurt those people
I don't know if I abandoned them
I don't know that
I am alone in this world
and if I were to find out I have a family and that I lost them
it would crush me
like there are so many things going on in my character's mind
so many things he is not in control of
and when we feel like that
the only sense of action that we can take sometimes
is just a genuine apology
because we say to ourselves and to everyone
I'm sorry I
I'm not connected to
those things that I did or those things that I feel
and the only way I can respond to them is
react to the emotion I have in the present
which is that like I regret it
I regret not knowing
I regret
not being able to give you a genuine response to this
so yes I do think that like apology
being apologetic being sorry
is very fitting for the narrative of this character so far
from everything that I've seen of him so far
there is a lot of shame in that absolutely right
but apology it can be a double edged sword right
for some people
they start to wield the apology
because they get so used to telling themselves that
apologizing is the work for dealing with this thing I don't like
we discover that
oh when I apologize it gives me that sense of control
it gives me a small sense of ownership over the past
and we start saying it and it loses its meaning
but it needs to be apology and action
it needs to be apology and change
it needs to be apology and reflection
it needs to be apology and seeking feedback
I can't just tell you I'm sorry
I need to tell you how do I need to change
it's the same words but the intention behind it is very important
so for my character to actually heal
it cannot just be I'm sorry I'm sorry I'm sorry
absolve me please
it needs to be I'm sorry how can I change
I'm sorry what do I need to do to be better
I'm gonna opt into this because
even though it's not the most comfortable thing
for us to admit
it's what I feel is right
of course you are it's okay
see if you can get something out of this like info
or maybe every time you say you're sorry
you get a million bucks
that's exactly what I'm talking about right
like there's a part of our mind that goes to that place
saids that says okay well
what does apology do for me in a transactional sense
when I say sorry to someone
what do I get back from them
do I get back from them it's okay
do I do I get absolved of what I did because
if I feel like I do then
okay well I've already gotten the reward
for apology which is absolution
but if you're looking for absolution from someone else
you're doing sorry the wrong way
what you really need is absolution from yourself right
I can genuinely speak to this
considering that I just uploaded like
what is essentially an apology video right
because like I've got something seriously wrong
about Kim's character and
a mix of what I saw as my character's dialogue and
my own impressions
resulted in some really bad takes
and
no one was like you need to apologize for this right
it was I felt I needed to say sorry to people but I also like
I needed to apologize because it wasn't okay with myself
right and that's what I mean by this
saying sorry so that you get someone else's
forgiveness is only half of it right you
you
you have to
you have to mean it because it it makes you feel more
okay with yourself right like
life is better when you live it honestly
and you don't avoid even the worst parts of yourself
I think and it's hard to live that way
because it's not always clear that
you are doing something dishonest
sorry therapist that's me I guess it is me you know
I think apology is really important
for your own self healing
and I think it's fitting for what we're doing in this character
lets see what it says
rigorous self-critique
okay
let's check this out
minus authority I think that that's good
I think that's legitimately good
all I have been talking about
is how our character views the world in terms of authority
and it has let to very negative consequences
it let to us trying to hit a child
because we felt like he was emasculating us
it let us to
irresponsibly shooting down the corpse
because we wanted to show Kim that we had it under control right
it let us to like
failing to navigate our conversation with Joyce
because we fail to see that
authority in intellect is comparable or greater than authority in status right
the only place that authority has won out really
was with measurehead so far
I consider this an anomaly
so losing authority is good for us right now
we do not want to see the world in terms of authority
this is not a good way to organize our lives
we can see that in Everett Clare's view of the world
I like this a lot
you're one sorry piece of shit
a cop penitence a flagellant cop monk
this is not the right line of work for you
you should be graveling at the feet of a feudal lord
providing lurid evidence against yourself at a Mazovian show trial
or ripping the flesh from your back with a cat of nine tails
whatever made this way
you can be damn sure it was *your* own fault
do it *really* curious criticize yourself
who knows you might uncover
something of importance from your guilt ridden past
we're absolutely going to internalize this
to me this is the moment I'm looking for from character
but it's also a moment I am looking for
in the process of therapy right
rigorous self-critique
but with a backbone of empathy towards yourself
let's internalize
this is this is good this is good for us
maybe in myself as well totally totally
okay Mr Claire
let's go bust down that door
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it consider giving it a like
and letting me know what you thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a little bit earlier if
you support the channel either through twitch or patreon
links to both of those and the community discord are in the description
thanks again and I will see you next time
bye