hello
and welcome to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
so on today's episode
the plot signed we are going to
see if we can establish our authority with Titus the union boss
we're gonna see if we can get a little closer to a confession from him on
who exactly was involved with the murder in Martinez
and over on the analysis side
we're gonna be taking a deep dive into the rigorous self critique thought
now that we've finally internalized this one
it opens the door for a lot of discussion on
Harry's sense of self
and kind of digging into the question of
is he actually a good person
and if he's not
does  he think that it's possible to become one
this one's a little bit heavier on the analysis
这一点在分析中占比会更大
but it's pretty exciting to finally peel back more layers of our character
so let's jump in
any predictions on where the story will go or who's the killer
I kind of had the idea
that we would be somewhat involved in the killing like
because we are so uninitiated to our own past
I don't think that we did it like would have hung him up like that
but I sort of have the suspicion that
the dock workers are kind of like a red herring
I just don't buy it
that's that's what we're leading
but I could be wrong
I am notoriously bad at predicting the plot
of anything ever like
when you have already probably noticed this
but like when politics or the plot are part of the dialogue
my brain like
it does this it feels like
it condenses down to like
I have to I've had to do this before
where I’m like  okay what is happening here
my brain is just equipped for like character or an analysis
and the way I engage with media just privately
is like when I’m watching something
I’m not really thinking about the plot
I’m very rarely like what
I’m not like watching shutter island
and I’m like where is this going
I wonder what's gonna happen next
my brain just like accepts whatever's going to happen
but what I’m thinking about
is like wow what is that character feeling right now
you know
I wonder how like
whatever is going to happen to them
is going to change their worldview
like it's that's more where my mind is focused
and I kind of just accept the plot
whatever it is it doesn't that matter that much to me
the sequence of things happening
unless it is so egregious that I’m like this doesn't make any sense
what if it was Lena well
I refuse to accept that
Lena is too kind hearted and good natured
for her to be involved in that
（读chat）“有趣的是 心理治疗师们似乎很抗拒做这种事
it's funny therapists often seem to struggle with things like
predicting stuff or telling if someone is lying well
it's true because like at the risk of
like I always go on some sort of rant
at the beginning of these streams but um
that's the thing is we are not detectives right
a therapist is not a detective
if someone comes into my uh therapy session
I’m always pretty upfront about the fact that like
look my role is to help you in whatever capacity that I can right
my philosophy on this is like if you give me good information
if you are honest about what you're going through
if you are open to challenging things
and the the the information that you give me about your life
and what you're going through is good
you will get good therapy right
because like I’m only
I’m gonna work off of what I receive
if you give me bad information
meaning that if you are dishonest if you are withholding things
if you lie about something
I’m gonna respond to that as if that's really
you know that's honest because like
I’m not there to like sort out of someone's lying to me or not
I’m there to work off of their investment
like I can't work harder than them in some respects right
so if you give me good information
you'll get good help
if you give me bad information
you'll get bad help
because you could come in and say yeah
I’m doing great at my job there's nothing to talk about there
and you could be like failing at your job you could hate it
it could be like the source of your depression
but if you tell me you're doing great I’m gonna be like cool let's move on
I may have a suspicion down the line like
hmm wait a second like you said earlier that your job is fine
but it sounds like there are some stressful things
there like I might push into that at some point
but again like I’m only gonna really
I’m not there to like sort out what's true or not
I’m there to work off of what's brought in you know
so I guess that's why I’m not super good at detecting lies
because I’m not really looking for them
it takes you being honest I think
well sometimes I am surprised by my own predictions yes
it does happen from time to time that I get something
I have predicted like five things extremely accurately
in the course of like watching anime and stuff
and everything else I just like someone said it in
in one of the comments or something like
whenever I start saying like maybe
you know that like just some random
unhinged stuff is about to happen
do I have any personal idea of who the killer could be
who do I think did it well
look I gotta ask first if I’m asking who did it
I gotta ask who benefits okay
我要问谁是这起事件的受益者
I gotta ask myself
what does what does killing this man bring okay
and I don't think that it was like a crime of passion
or it could be I don't know
like I said prepare for me to get this wildly wrong
this is wild speculation Brady
part of me wants to reject the impulse
that this is like a crime of passion
because it looks like pretty gruesome
and it makes me want to think well
I would only be here i f there were this murder
I think this is less about the murder victim
and more about the changes to the society
that the murder will bring it will bring myself and Kim here
lead us down some sort of path
I might not know enough about the guy that died to intuit something like that
oh I don't right like I said this is like baseless speculation
just on like trying to find an interesting angle on it
I kind of doubt that it's any of these people
it's Tuesday
we need to interrogate the men in the union booth
find out what they know about the hanging in Martinez
it's gruesome because you didn't take it down for seven days
that's true
确实
do I think disco elysium could be used as a tool for therapy sure
I think anything as useful as a tool for therapy
in the hands of a skilled therapist
I work in games and
there's been some talk about leveraging games in some form of therapy
and for me at least playing
disco was an experience I connect with yeah
I think it would take the therapist and the gamer knowing lots of things about it
yeah I mean like sometimes I recommend my clients to read a book
I'll say here I want you to go read this book and talk about it with me
because it's relevant to what you're going through
so I do see why in the future as games become more universal
that I could be like
hey you know I think this is relevant to what you're going through
I think you should become a gamer and play disco elysium
so I know we already talked to these gentlemen
but I’m ready to give it another try
let's ask him if he did that
The Pretty Boy
You guys really love talking about that Pretty Boy
Funny
But my partner and I have a serious matter to discuss with you
let's see why is there a container belt around the dead man's neck
Container belt Like we used in the harbor
Because we took it
from the harbor where we work
then we went out back and used it to hang him
oh did he just admit to the crime
as he speaks
his fist contract going through the pulling motion again savoring it
what did he just did he  just did he admit to the crime
We did this together All of us until he was dead
that's why there's a container belt around his neck
okay that's it the game's over we got the perpetrator
we got to wrap it up
no you don't what you have is seven honest men
who thought it forthcoming to tell you what happened
so that you don't waste any more of your time
they're plain to their considerable strength in numbers
don't talk about arresting them
you only bring attention to your inability to do so
okay authority I’m going to listen to you this time
so what they just
they just confessed I guess they did it
who called the shots that night
that's what I want to know
there will be no singling anyone out
you can't arrest a hardy boy
without arresting all hardy boys
well  fuck I want to arrest them all then
do you think you could arrest them all
kim's got my back
Titus keep addressing him
he wants everyone to know he's in charge
fucking okay authorities got my back as well
look they may have one two three four five six seven
plus eight individuals here
but I've got like several mental health problem voices
more than that
who are here to back me up
let's do it let's address him
let's play along
who do you fucking think does
bows of the bearded man
you do you give the commands
he wants everyone to know he's in charge so let's play along
that's right asshole
Titus hardy runs the hardy boys ain't that so fellas
I think you got your answer Mr Law
so he's not the leader
no you did not get an answer Titus does administrative work
he pushes paper fills out forms
the others can't read
but on that night they all acted as one man
that's just some fucking psychological bullshit this
isn't that like
wasn't that like part of the defense of the fucking Manson people
where it's like oh well
he didn't he didn't commit the crimes himself
he just radicalized a bunch of people to do it for him
I did spin kicked measurehead I did we did do that
let's ask why that they killed him
why because he was worthless mercenary scum
and he stepped out of line in my town
who are you covering up for
that's what I want to know
so he was a mercenary that's it
and he stepped out of line
what kind of mercenary
get them Kim
the kind that shows up when you start a strike
the *experienced* kind too
had Co HoI and Seminee written all over him
ex-Oranese Special Forces
a live grenade right here in *our* bar
this one has a special gripe with him coming here
I can't prove it
but I *know* he was sent by the Wild Pines
they hired merk-shit like that
story of every strike from here to Samara
so these guys think that wild pines got someone in here to
rile people up
I guess
how do you know that he was in special forces
Cause one night he walked straight up to the mic and said
I’m Oranjese goddamn special forces
and I’m gonna fuck you all
game volume needs some
adjustment okay
let's do that
let me know how that is
uh I sincerely doubt that happened
yeah really had a gin and tonic up there
sang some Oranjese paratrooper song
and said he's gonna fuck everyone
we couldn't believe it either
but he fucking did right there like some kind of animal
but what did he actually do
"但他到底做*错*了什么"
he harassed women raped one harassed workers
threatened to kill some as a warning
there's a slight unease in him suddenly
he regrets mentioning the rape
to kill us all if we don't open the gates
if we don't let the scabs in if we don't bend over
that was *before* he started coming here
yeah he said it was his 'favorite joint' now
started to come in here every night
drinking grabbing girls grab one of ours mid-karaoke
right there on the stage
I wonder why
I'll save it I'll save my critique after
He grabbed someone
the lieutenant is trying to make sense of this float of information
yeah this girl's on the mic a beautiful girl young
gets into the second verse of love of lake
the fuck a grebsal legs start screaming
show me your cunt
why don't you show me your cunt
then gets knocked on the head with a wine bottle
doesn't even fall down
i think we're gonna have to ask if this was the same individual
aren't you fucking listening
my man is talking to you
he took *care* of it
they got the girl out before anything else could happen
yeah me and Eugene got her out
aren't you fucking listening
okay
that's a very serious allegation
i want to know who they're talking about
no
you're not getting a name
that's a Martinaise matter and I'm not discussing it with you clowns
Despite the stonewalling you can slip one more question in
okay volition
let's push further into that because that seems like
I don't know
seems like a serious allegation to me
Titus do *not* answer
you have been forthcoming enough
fuck off cop
she's gone through enough without you harassing her too
she doesn't need more embarrassment
what are you talking about embarrassment
if someone has been sexually assaulted we need to
what you *need* is to get the fuck out of my face
i've had enough of explaining myself to you fucks
he's dead
it's done
as you can see
these men can only take so much baseless scrutiny
baseless
I do my best to keep the situation simple
but
all of my scrutiny is based okay
it is not baseless
it won't be for long she means
it's true she was the only thing holding him back
okay
you murdered him just like that no remorse
how many people have you sent to the *chaise*
ever felt remorse for them
or send them to Reunion to *rot*
for twenty years for *life*
look I'm just doing my job
what we do is *different*
we enforce the law you just kill people like it's nothing
honestly I drink so much I can't really remember anyone
let's see my character okay
like some of the stuff that we've been talking about for Harry is
how he views the world right
so much of it so far has been in terms of authority
and if I just go off of things we've said before
we were like well why can't we arrest those kids
why can't we arrest Evrart Claire
he seems to have a very simple view of like the power dynamic
and I think that that's coming from the fact that
he doesn't really remember who he was as a cop
like imagine you just woke up and you knew you were a cop
but this is like still new to you
you are there are some like ingrained things you know
some of your repressed memory is coming back
but I imagined him to be someone who is like
like if you made me a cop today
some of my questions would be like well
why can't we just arrest them
right
but that's because I haven't lived as a cop
it's a complex thing right
so what I'm wondering here is like
harry is learning that the world does not work like that okay
we cannot just be an authority figure just because we have the badge
we've tried that a couple of times
but what would we stand on would we stand on the morality
like that because we have the badge
we get to decide who is good or bad
we're just doing our job
we're neutral
that's a pretty neutral thing to say I like neutrality
what we do is *different* we enforce the law
so like these sound like strongly held convictions
which I don't think we have very many of at the moment
what do I think he would sympathize with
these men have all come to me and said
based on principle we don't need cops
we are able to decide what's right and wrong in our community
and so he may be more sympathetic to the community aspect
he's gonna say yeah but this guy was bad
I don't even really believe this
it's not like they killed him like it was nothing
clearly there maybe was a crime of passion in some ways
I'm just gonna go with the
we don't have our badge now
being a cop is a conviction yeah it is
but he's he's very inconfident about himself as a cop right
I just did like my whole
analytical piece on how
he's not sure what kind of cop he is right
this part right here
he's not sure what kind of cop he is
and so
to me it doesn't make sense that he be like but I'm the kind of cop who
I have a strong conviction about what my role is
I'm just gonna go neutral here
it's gonna piss people off but I'm gonna go for it
oh so you're just a simple well-meaning man huh
ever been in solitary
prison is a *torture*
that's what it is
he's clearly been in solitary confinement
and at a young age nonetheless
so is hanging a man slowly without breaking his neck
I'm so pissed
well like I told you I
I'm doing what I think a character would do
*how* did you
we hanged him up by his neck until he got real still
wasn't that obvious copper
didn't they teach you *anything* at the cop school idiot
you're pretty sure
you've had at least two years of *cop school*
and many more of active service
that's right
that's right authority
certainly enough to not put up with his back-sass
deliver a knock-down observation
now *you* listen to *me* Sonny-Jim
the autopsy showed the victim's hands weren't tied
no sign of struggle
explain this and make it real simple
fuck it I'm going with it we
uh we huh
look i'm not gonna play Twenty Questions with you coppo
I'll say it again killed him
do I think he's a neutral man no
but I think that he is
while he's still figuring out the difference between
who he is now and who he used to be
like there is an investment in integrating these two things
at least from my perspective
it's very hard for him to start standing on very hard held beliefs
they may and be incompatible with like who he used to be right
I'll talk about this in a second
but it comes down to ego defense
yeah *I* knocked him out
came up behind him and clubbed him in the back of the head
he went down like a sack of sand
that's right lawman
and then we hanged the fuck
oh
we did level up our composure
when we were talking to Annette
still not enough here maybe we can ask some more questions
Mr Tatts what did you use to knock the victim out
my fucking elbow copper
Samaran boxing-style
where did this take place
right fucking here
Eugene already told you that
the fuck had started coming to *our* bar
yeah man weren't you listening
they keep speaking for Titus
so that he wouldn't get his hands murdy with too much explaining
it's a red check it can't be retried
58 percent
maybe I can ask some more questions
first
like what copper
when did this happen
you don't have to keep answering his questions
yes you do I'm a cop
I know Lizzy relax
we killed him last Sunday night
seemed like a good way to end the week
how long had you known him
*known* him
we don't associate with scum like that asshole
look I'm getting science that
the chat is hitting me with lucky tomatoes
so
yeah who do you think we are
"I have gloves for composure" do it?
I can't look at my interventory
I'll back out of this conversation and check
quiet
he came around 'bout three weeks ago
when that *Pines* cow first sailed into town
happy
by the 'Pines cow' you mean Joyce Messier
the representative for Wild Pines
the same company you're striking against
no
I mean *the Pines cow*
the stupid-ass cow they sent in to fuck us over
but you know what
he rubs his chin pretending to mull it over
why don't you ask *her* about the Pretty Boy
I'm sure she has interesting things to say
when you ask her *hard* enough
that's enough insinuation for today Titus
officer your interview is drawing to an end
don't waste your last questions
uh yeah I don't think I can back out of this
and I don't remember
I think we checked our inventory
and we're wearing everything that we can for composure already
so I have to do the check now
why don't you ask *her* about the Pretty Boy
that's enough insinuation for today Titus
how do I get back to that one
which one was it
was it "*how* did you kill him
yes
all right
let's get this fire started okay
we need some fucking tomatoes in the chat right now
to get our dice roll
look there's a secret edition that happens to the dice roll
when chat is full of lucky tomatoes
okay
I'm seeing a lot of them flow through right now
the other thing is look I'm sizing this guy up all right
it takes a lot of responsibility
and a lot of conviction to stand before me
with my flashlight and my cool hat
jacket shoes and Kim beside me
right
and to back all these guys up okay
now look that's a...
whether or not we agree at something that I can respect
is that he's putting himself out there like this
but I can also tell that he's nervous okay
nobody likes being questioned on their morals
nobody likes being questioned on their convictions
and nobody likes to also be targeted by authority figures
okay so I got a lot of respect for this guy
just from a very primal sort of way now
I do not have respect for his actions or his beliefs
flashlight gives us the extra composure I think it does
but let's see if we can break him down okay
I'm fucking going for it
actually they're admirably surprisingly composed
the entire room
given how many questions you've lobbed their way
all of them maybe one of them is fidgeting
well this one
but he's always fidgeting
so don't get your hopes up
we're too fucked
we're too fucked up to
I thought that we had an understanding
what I was getting at is we
it takes a lot of pressure for me to stand here
and for you to stand here and to do this whole rigmarole
let's connect on just the fact that
no one wants to be here right now
but it didn't work
like what copper
okay what are we gonna do now
nothing
your investigation here is done
leave Martinaise
go back to your stations where you belong
every check that I talk about a lot fails
I know it does
and every time I just make a check without thinking about it
it's a succeed
that's true it's so true
I think we are going to stick around thanks
some things don't add up here Titus
fuck
I've done this job for long enough
to know that people don't just confess to first-degree murder
*even* if it is a group responsibility
we are going to look into this
it's all a cover up
good luck with that
who are you protecting
you've heard everything a *rent-a-cop* is gonna hear from us *real* law officials
you're lucky you didn't get a beating
who are you protecting right now
okay who's really benefiting from this
is it Claire
is it Evrart
rent-a-cop
so that's what this is about
he doesn't see you as his equals
establish authority
we have to we have to do it
I fuck this absolutely fuck this
so I'm not even gonna talk about I’m just gonna do it
establish authority yes
AUTHORITY
feverish thoughts race through your mind
damn it
let's just stomp our feet
we could point at him
or we could ask for the gun
hum that's it that's all I got
look
the only thing that we have been able to do so far
is embarrass ourselves
I'm not gonna stomp my feet
I do like the idea of pointing my finger at him
I'm gonna point my finger
and what exactly is it you've been doing
that's so god damn special
shitting yourself in front of us
going around arresting kids on the street
kids who've done nothing wrong
you don't know that
all the while talking racist shit
don't think we aren't watching *fascha*
people here trust us
we're getting *complaints*
I
uh I don't even have a gun
what are you talking about
guns are the only thing you have
waving them around old ladies' faces
trying a gun down kid
he knows about Cuno
Carly said they've been trying to set up a mass execution
bulk-purchasing guns ammunition too
I can believe that
Carly works in a gunshop you see
there's no mass-execution officer
just ask questions and don't get sidetracked
okay I need Kim to rein me in here
please don't set up a mass execution
you'll never be able to pull it off
the logistics alone are insane
just ask questions
be a normal cop
I can't
I've tried
I cannot be a normal cop
fuck okay
the only time I don't get Kim involved by now
RIGOROUS SELF - CRITIQUE
here it is
Hard facts from the man you are
You once jerked off in the locker room
and were caught
you held a young woman by the arm
and kept her in your apartment for 20 minutes against her will
That's right
these are not flights of fancy
These are*real deeds* harry
emerging from the darkness of your past
you tried shooting a fleeing suspect in the foot
but hit him in the pelvis crippling him for life
and above all you let life defeat you
我的妈呀
All the gifts your parents gave you
all the love and patience of your friends
you drowned in a neurotoxin
you let misery win
and it will keep on winning
till you die or overcome it
holy shit
that is the most important block of text for this entire playthrough in my mind
and I will tell you why
okay
what do we get from this first of all
intelligence and chology checks red check failures here or plus one morale
physical and motorix red check failurse here one health
learning cap for pain threshold is raised okay
okay interesting
so we actually get things back from failing
which is kind of unique
yeah there is a reason that harry did his best to forget everything
that's exactly what I suspected
and I want to tell you about what this would mean to me in the context of like
someone learning more about like a part of their life
that they previously were not attached to
so I'm gonna bring it back to my
discussion points about
like this is what we talked about last time
we were not sure if we were a good cop
this is unknown to us right
and it's not like super known to everyone around us
obviously it's gonna be known to any of the people we
interacted with in our past life
but this being here in the unknown
is one of the only reasons that any other movement can take place for us
we've been very concerned about like
is it even possible to repair ourselves
is it even possible to become a better person
because at the end of the day
let's say I live my life in service of good deeds
what happens if everything I did before
this was still horrific right
am I going to be okay with myself
our view of ourself has been changing in a somewhat positive direction
and we've been questioning whether
or not we can call ourselves a complete failure
so one thing that just changed is we discovered that
no we weren't a good cop right
we were not one
this is coming over here
right
we were not a good cop
and in fact we may not have been a good person right
and I think that those two things are intermixed because like
being a cop being someone who is responsible for other people
responsible for keeping the law keeping the peace
our actions and our deeds in that role they
they do sort of like they are married in a way
with our views of ourselves
like if we abused our power if we
did things that we would call inappropriate like you know
shooting at a fleeing suspect
and holding someone against their will
right
not only are we not a good cop
we don't feel like we it's possible for us to be a good person
unfortunately the more we tried to obscure this right
I think it's been like
Inland Empire Volition some of Half Light
there's been all these voices who have been like protecting us in a way
from discovering this
because they they are interjecting at points to say like well
if you discover more about yourself
you're gonna realize that you weren't a good cop
and you're not gonna feel very much like a good person either
and that's gonna wreck you
at the same time I think it is healthier
not to deny these things anymore  and to
I think it would be somewhat aimless to just try to be a good person generally
because therapy and mental health
it's not just random what you do
in some ways you need clear objectives right
we need to know when we're starting off
like what are we trying to actually work on here
because if we're just trying to work on like being good
this is like too abstract it's too broad
it touches too many areas of life right
we want to get things more concretely and say like well
I want I don't want people to be afraid of me okay well that's
that's something that a good person would do right
we're trying to come up with more concrete things
and so learning these specific points would be very beneficial to that
here's the facts from the man that you are right
you jerked off in the locker room and were caught
so to me that says like
there's this kind of selfishness to that there is a
lack of self-respect
there is a lack of impulse control
there is
lots of like
lots of shame wrapped up in that right
you held a young woman by the arm
and kept her in your apartment for twenty minutes against your will
so similar things here but also
we can we have the capacity to be authoritative
we are seeing from ourselves that we are controlling
that we're imposing
we lack empathy
right
these not flights of fancy thses are real deeds
emerging from the darkness from your past
you tried shooting a fleeing suspect in the foot
but hid him in the pelvis crippling him for life so
I think that's like lacking composure right
we were probably drunk let's be honest right um
these don't even have to be emotional things
this could just be like we had we have poor accuracy right
we we have poor accountability
right
we we lack
yeah we lack accountability and I think that we also like
see if you shot someone and crippled him
I mean there's lots of regrets in that it sounds like
all the gifts your parents gave you
and love and patience of your friends
you drowned in a neurotoxin
you let misery win
so its similar things
its selfishness its lack of self respect
it's lack of impulse control it's a lack of empathy right
it's circulating around all of these subjects
and it will keep winning until you die or overcome it
so like
these are more concrete things to work on with someone than just like
I want to be a good person right
because I don't know what to do with that if you come to me
and say that that's our objective like I want to be a good person
I don't want to keep repeating the same mistakes
then I'm going to ask okay well what were some of those mistakes
and so having someone discover the list of things that we just did
and knowing that there are going to be patterns in probably other areas of their life
we can now start to formulate an idea of
all right well let's attack these things right
what are some ways that like we can start living in service of not being selfish
and learning to up put other people first
what are some things that we can do to regain some self-respect
for example not embarrassing ourselves
every time that we get into conversation with someone
caring more about our appearance
caring more about the language we use
and and whether or not we approach people using authority
like we just tried to do right
lack of impulse control
that's like a behavioral intervention that we can start working on
we can start processing like elements of shame
which is kind of what we did over here
these give us clear measurable objectives to actually work on
so in the process of working with someone like harry
this would be a huge moment of self discovery it will
be upsetting to learn these things
as it naturally should be like
part of him wants to forget all of this stuff
and just be a blank slate
that can you know be reshaped into something new
but a lot of the work in becoming more self aware
has to do with recognizing your ego defenses
these are very common defense
we use to protect ourselves from
learning the complicated things that exist in our unconscious
I'll just draw Freud's like iceberg thing here right
Freud said that a lot of our thoughts are unconscious
and that's been maintained by more than just Freud
but the iceberg analogy works for this right
and Harry has not like
just because he lost his memories does not mean that he has no
that some of his unconscious thoughts
and behaviors are not going to surface constantly right
I think there were some questions and some of the chat or comments
I forget where they were asking like well
why would he still have an addiction
if he just woke up and didn't have his memories well
because like whether or not he has conscious awareness of them
his thoughts and behaviors
they are still chemically and psychologically bound to his actions right
even if he says oh yeah I really don't want to smoke like
he might be going through nicotine withdrawal anyways
and that's going to dictate a lot of his behavior
he may tell himself look I don't want to be authoritative
I don't want to be selfish I don't want to be any of these things
but simply because you have that thought does not mean that this
suddenly follows suit right there's
there's a certain amount of this that like
the work that you have to do is how do you translate things this way
how do you make something that is unconscious conscious
and that's what we've been trying to do
as we explore our past and explore our
our good and wrong deeds
but this line right here is very treacherous to cross
for someone who is like Harry
who may be afraid of what he used to be right
and so a lot of times as we are trying to bring things up this way
our ego defenses they get in the way of that
and they try to send them back down right
because the the ego is basically like
it's called the reality principle right
id is like your pleasure principle
it's like dealing with all the primal desires and those sorts of things
and the super ego is like
where your sense of morality and bigger ideas live
and the ego sort of moderates these things
and translates both of the extremes down to reality
所以当我们面对那些不好的事情
and so it gets protective when
we face things like hey you used to not be a good person right
oh no my super ego is now challenged by that right
like hey you just learned that you were a fucking asshole
and that you did all kinds of horrible things to people
this has the power to shatter your self image
and so the ego tries to moderate that by
either keeping things like kind of where they are or interpreting them
so let me give you an example of that
so common ego defense right
so like here's the thing right what we don't like
when things don't agree right
we do not like to see our behaviors
disagree with one in one another so for example
let's say you look around at my apartment right
and you saw that things were neatly set up right
like there's the environments kind of clean
there's not like dishes in the sink
there's not a bunch of like I don't know cat toys lying around
like it's neatly put together
and it's organized and it's well taken care of right
but then let's say you got in my car
and you discovered that there's like Gatorade bottles on the floor
and an expired air freshener and
old receipts that I haven't taken out right
and you would look at that and say like well
like why why could this happen
because we see this all the time right
I have seen this from people
and sometimes I see it in you know my own behavior
not specifically this my car is pretty clean right now
but like sometimes we see that
where one part of someone's life looks super put together
and another one doesn't
and you might start asking the question of why
why would this happen
why would you walk into my house and see that it's put together
and then you go into my car and  it's a fucking mess
let me ask what your read on that is
what do you think is going on there
because it has to do with all of this
there's a million rats in the walls yeah
me at work versus day to day yeah
could be it could be
I've seen many people like that in real life maybe it's OCD yeah
this is this is good right
we're looking for like what explains this what explains
two behaviors that don't actually agree with each other
one area of my life is super pristine and put together
and another one is like kind of a mess
car is go go time
maybe I don't care about my car couldn't have guests coming over
maybe the car is not important to the person
no mental energy for cleaning
this is all good stuff
we're this is the area where I'm a detective right
where I'm like what could be the explanation for this behavior
I’m curious
one is elevated at the expense of the other
one of my
the car is a more private versus
showing your home as to guests
a lot of times people will say well I don't live in my car right
there's all kinds of good reasons
and and none of these are wrong by the way
it could have been any of them right
it could be just like a lack of energy or whatever
but very often people
would say well look I'm not trying to live in my car
it doesn't matter that it's not put together
I might not have guests over or something
but all of those are basically ego defenses
because what we're saying to ourselves is look
we don't like when things don't agree
when two behaviors don't agree
so when things don't agree
we tend to force them to
we will come up with a way
to make these two incompatible behaviors agree
even though they don't right
and we will call that like a justification
right we will say to ourselves well
I’m not living in my car
it doesn't need to be clean I'm not showing it off to people
it's not representative of my lifestyle as much
these are just ways to make two incompatible behaviors
that don't actually agree agree
and I would rather come up with a way to make them agree
and make this okay
than do the digging for whatever is trying to come up to my conscious mind
and that I'm sending back down by saying
no there's like a rational reason for this
it's because I don't sleep in my car right
here's another one that's that's very common as well
oh I went to the gym earlier today
so today I’m gonna eat a bunch of sweets later I deserve it right
I’m gonna eat this cake
because like I am gonna work out later right
it does not make sense to go spend five hours at the gym
and then blow it on eating sweets right after or later in the day right
these are two behaviors that don't really agree
and rather than sort out the disagreement
we just come up with ways to force them to
and those are in defense of our ego right
that's that's an ego defense right there
what I'm saying is there can be absolutely no reason for this behavior
yeah  I mean I think that
part of this is down to like these are simple examples right
where I'm talking about like
the difference between cleaning an area of your life and not
or just changing your impulse to eat something sweet or not
but think about this in a more complicated sense okay
now that I've given you a simple example what is this right here
what is a functional alcoholic
if not exactly this right
oh well I am able to go to work or go to school
and I get my stuff done
and I'm not destroying my life in this area
and so like you know I'm functioning
even though I'm drinking all the time at home
and I'm not putting a lot of you know effort into stopping that
this is the same thing right here okay
except it's on a more complicated subject
these two behaviors do not agree with one another
to be diligent and measured
and taking lots of care to keep your life structured in only one area
and then not putting any of that structure in your health
or your finances
or whatever you have to do to keep the lifestyle of addiction up
and so yeah two things don't agree here
but we force them to we come up with a way to
not integrate whatever is trying to come up to the surface here
which is that like wow I have a problem
like imagine someone discovering that idea that
oh actually being an alcoholic is making parts of my life unmanageable
or is ruining relationships right
and to become aware of that
would start to change the make up of your self-esteem
it would start asking you to change behaviors
you have to you know
suddenly give up this thing that you've become dependent on
it's a lot of work and a lot of effort
and so what we do is our eco defense gets involved
and keeps this from coming to the surface and it will stay down here
because we've come up with a way to make a degree
so this is a force that opposes
your behavioral changes and your cognitive changes
and I see a lot of that in what is going on with
our own rigorous self critique here
every time we learn something new
there is a chance for us to suppress it
and Volition and Inland Empire they have in some ways been ego defenses
to be no you don't have to integrate these things
it's okay for these not to agree who you were and who you are
you can just be a new person
but I think that this is unhelpful for Harry's healing right
I genuinely think that it's much healthier
for all of this stuff to come up here
and even if it is psychologically damaging in the moment
to have the kinds of protective factors
to integrate it in a healthy way right
and we'll talk about protective factors in a moment
like we don't just want to suddenly
make everything bad about our life conscious
because it would break us down
that's what Volition is worried about
but we can't just go through our life
with our house clean and our car dirty
I mean we can but bigger picture
we cannot go through Harry's life with
I used to be a shit cop and a shit person
and now I'm trying to be a good cop and a good person
and does totally separate them
if we want to actually heal from this
we're going to need to make a lot of that stuff conscious
and not try to defend ourselves from the lack of agreement
we're going to have to find ways to face the idea that
we are a walking contradiction
but there are things we can address to make them more consistent
and it's this stuff right here
so this applies to harry's life
and applies to the lives of a lot of people who I work with
who again you know is is a lot of people in addiction
who may not even remember everything that they've done
may have very similar experiences to Harry
where they have stolen from family members to support their addiction
they've committed crimes to support their addiction
they've done all kinds of stuff that
as a sober person today they are not happy with
and I am not working with them on
how to somehow make those two lives compatible
by saying like well it was your addiction its its
it's not who you were it's like well
let's embrace the fact that we're not happy about those things
and find a healthy way to integrate them
by working on what they represent to you
if we need to work on selfishness let's do it right
if we need to work on our regrets
then we need to learn how to make amends to people
rather than just try to move on from it
that's my viewpoint on why we have been going about
approaching Harry's past and his present
you know I think that like not looking in the mirror
in some ways is like one of these
like here's two things that don't agree
I don't know a lot about who I am
so I'm gonna
deny myself looking in the mirror right
to actually like face that side of ourselves would mean
embracing some of these uncomfortable unconscious things
I just think don't think that we were ready yet until recently
until we have started to actually do some good deeds right
because what we did recently was
we gained some self-respect in our interactions with Annette
we have changed some of our impulse control by not
chasing around every bit of alcohol and cigarette
we struggled at first but we're doing it now
we don't have to be as shameful about who we used to be
because we are apologizing for a lot of it right
this is stuff that we are still struggling with
is like how not to be authoritative
my read on Harry is that like when he gets in a bind
he's still struggling not to like do the kinds of things he used to do
which was holding someone in a in a room
which we just learned that he did
like it's very in line with me trying to just arrest everybody
so this is still an area of work
but we are changing our selfishness we're changing our composure
our accuracy is definitely much better
after shooting the guy down
and we're trying to be accountable by apologizing
by a lot of things right
and in addressing who we look like
is sort of addressing the shame around that
our Harry is going through a journey of
change and acceptance and development
and it's messy and it's not it's not holistic either
not all of these things are going to come together all at once
for example this one is still very much in work in progress
but I fucking love this
I love this rigorous self critique thing this game mechanic
because it's so representative of this issue
that is like very common in psychological work right
this journey doesn't sound very disco  I mean it's a
it's the journey that we're on
are ego defenses ever valid in their reasoning
yes so I'll tell you about some more ego defenses
which are not the worst thing ever right like
displacement is one of them
we talked about displacement
which is like the
when we're dealing with something
where we don't have the right target for an emotion
so we displace it to someone else
right again to become aware of that
to make an unconscious feeling conscious
could be damaging to ourselves which is that
look I'm struggling with anger at myself over who I used to be
so I lash out at everyone around me
like that would be really insightful
but it would also bring up a lot of shame
and so displace it would mean like
we just attribute it to someone else
and say yeah no I’m pissed off because
you know I can't find my badge
and that's not my fault it's someone else's fault
like it's an ego defense right
the two other common ones are what I might call
sour grapes and
sweet lemon
so a sour grape right
this comes from an Aesop's Fable where there's a fox whose
going through the forest and he finds some grapes
some delicious sustenance in the jungle or whatever forest
and he wants them
but there's like a thorn bush between him and the grapes
and so what he tells himself right
because he can't get them is that they must be sour
like I didn't want those grapes anyways
they're probably sour I probably wouldn't want them
like this is an ego defense right
this is what happens when someone gets rejected
and then they're like yeah well whatever you're ugly anyways
you've just made this into a sour grape like
you wanted something and instead of embracing the idea that
you can't have something that you want all the time
and that that's like you would embrace the idea that
you know maybe I'm not attractive to this person
our ego defense gets in the way
and it keeps it at an unconscious level
to say that yeah well you didn't even really want that thing
so that's a sour grape and the opposite of that is a sweet lemon
which is this is making this is
forcing a good situation to be bad
this is forcing a bad situation to be good right
it's like biting into a lemon
and telling yourself that it's actually quite sweet
and that it's not sour at all right
a good example of this would be like
let's say I'm you know in a fucking office all day
and it's super hot and I'm sweating
and it's like making me dehydrated
and so I tell myself  you know this is really uncomfortable right now
but at least it's getting me to drink more water
I have been trying to drink more
right like what you have done is
you have forced two things that don't really agree
to somehow have a better outcome.
sweating is actually good for me because it's making me hydrate more
It comes through when people are like well
you know this job doesn't pay me enough
but that's actually good for me
because I'll have less money which will teach me to budget better
right that's not like
someone asked if the ego defenses are always negative
and this is what I'd say no it's not that negative
like look if that's your reality
if you're Frittte girl
and stop me from talking about her
if I if I'm going back down that direction
but imagine you're Frittte girl okay
her whole fucking life has to be a sweet lemon just to survive all right
she has to go into her fucking claustrophobic little booth
and tell herself that like
oh this bad situation this fucking lemon of a life
is actually quite sweet to me right
because not getting paid teaches me to budget better
having to spend all day here keeps me from spending time at home
where I don't feel like anyone listens to me
every time I go to work I'm reminded of how bad my life is
and it makes me work harder to get out of this
have you ever felt like that
that the job you have and everything around it
and the people that you have to work with that you may not like
and you look at them and you're like I'm glad I'm facing this
because it is reminding me of what's important to me
and that I need to get out of this right
then that's what you're doing right here
and this one's not so bad right
I think that this is these are not all equal
that's not forcing something to be unconscious in like a suppressive way
what it's doing is protecting ourselves from the ego
which which would chime in to say
your life sucks and they're getting nothing out of this
like I think we just have to believe that
even the bad things we're going through are worth something
and in that sense this is not a problem right
that's a coping skill in some ways
as long as it's not leading to like deep denial right
so it's a thin line between helpful positivity and sweet lemons
or is sweet lemon toxic positivity
no I think yeah
toxic positivity would be like
always saying well look at the bright side right
I think that sweet lemon is not as bad
because there's still an acknowledgement that the situation sucks
you're not trying to like twist reality
because like toxic positivity to me would be like
going into Frittte girls job and being like no I actually do like this
you know it's actually interesting to see the people and
like no then you're trying to make something positive when it's not
at least here you're telling yourself yeah this does suck
it like it really is shit but
I got to get something out of this
even if it's just motivation to change it
right
so that's one of the the ego defenses that's like not super bad for you
but yeah a couple of other ones are like projection right
projections when we hear a lot of the idea is that you are
you think you're looking at a window but you're actually looking at a mirror
you're looking at someone else and saying
yeah this guy's a pain in the ass he thinks he's so smart
what's his deal what a jerk right
and I think I'm like looking at someone through a window like I'm not
like I'm not seeing that that's actually me
and I'm actually looking at a mirror and I'm like
wow I hate the idea that you know this person
intellectualizes things to hide from their insecurities or whatever
again it's keeping something from surfacing here
right
it's a defense against the ego
and the ego just meaning the thing that dictates what reality is to you right
another common one is called reaction formation
reaction formation is when you express the opposite of what you feel
so kids experience this a lot when they are
picking on the girl who sits next to them but they actually like them
right when you're mean to someone that you actually like
that's reaction formation
and we have probably seen a lot of this in Kim's behavior
where he says things like I'm not interested in this
but he actually kind of is
why might he be doing that
unconsciously
there is a desire to be a little more free and loose and whatever else
but part of his like whole thing is staying composed and professional
and so he doesn't always allow this like childlike spirit to come out
and so he keeps it here by using this
I'm not interested in this he said interested yeah
he's separating work and personal stuff
yeah I mean like again these are not all bad
do not get that idea ego defenses are not bad
they are just worthy of being investigated
that like
look if you're struggling to face the thing in reality
there might be a reason for that right
and if we find that it's not worth bringing into reality that's fine
but we do have to notice that
we do force things to agree when they don't
that's what this is about
yeah a tsundere is a little bit like that right
pretending not to like someone
when you actually do
a cigarette a day
exactly this is kind of an ego defense as well
it's a kind of a justification right
it doesn't really agree with like
it not being a full habit
but still doing it like it's a habit just not at that intensity or something like that
can you explain the core difference
between intellectualization and rationalization
I would say intellectualization is like
talking about an emotional subject in an abstract way
giving a history of an emotion rather than
expressing it
where where I'm like yeah
I got in an argument with my friend yesterday and he made me so mad
like I'm just giving you a history
I'm like reading the Wikipedia version of what happened
that would be kind of like intellectualizing
which again is not bad
it's just that's not our objective
if our objective is to be emotionally insightful
then we want to avoid that
and rationalization
it's kind of similar to this
it's coming up with a logical reason to do something like
well I don't live in my car so there's no reason for me to clean it
yeah anyways I bring all this up
because I think it's very relevant to what we just learned about
the ideas of rigorous self-critique right
which this is not just self-critique
it's rigorous it's painful it's it's challenging
it's challenging to this right here the ego
which is defining our our understanding of reality
it's trying to integrate ideas of morality and ideas of
like the primordial voice right
so yeah pretty interesting
that we just learned more like an hour ago
yeah I know
I know I know
okay let's
let's return to what we were doing
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it consider giving it a like
and letting me know what you thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a little bit earlier
if you support the channel either through Twitch or Patreon
links to both of those and the community Discord are in the description
thanks again and I will see you next time
bye