hello
and welcome to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
so on today's episode I'm very excited
because we are finally getting to use one of my absolute
favorite frameworks for analyzing characters
this is something that I use in therapy from time to time
and it's an incredible way to explore patterns of psychology and patterns of behavior
and sort of really uncover what is driving a lot of the complexes
that we see play out in Harry's thoughts and his actions
and the reason we are doing that now is
because we are starting to learn more about ourselves and our past
and take another look at that Ledger
and see what do we actually think about the person that we used to be
before we became a sorry cop
all that's coming up
so let's jump back in
oh there it is there it is we are back
we're so back
and I'm so excited
okay so we are back in the game now
I just wanted to say
the community that has arrived around this game and specifically
this playthrough continues to amaze me
especially after last episode was like a lot of politics talk
and I was very like anxious avoidant of talking about politics
I have been very encouraged by the response to that last episode to like
not be so anxious about it
I don't I still don't know
if I'm gonna like start getting full political
but I will try not to to like avoid it in the game because of my personal
issues with getting political
I'll just say that
I won't let it divert the game
because at the end of the day I want to talk about like mental health
and there's probably some interesting avenues in the narrative of the game
that will miss out on if I just totally ignore it
however I will say this game is
so wonderfully designed that you
you have a main character who has a real backstory
he's not like a blank slate
like I thought that he was gonna be from the beginning
he has his own backstory and at the same time
it allows you to have your own beliefs
and the character will like have the same behavioral patterns
like genuinely imagine
if like literally Brady was the detective
imagine
what you know about me so far
I would go about solving a murder
would be exactly like you've seen it
like I would spend crazy amounts of time
on things that you just wouldn't like you
you wouldn't think I have the significance that they do
and I would be I would totally overlook lots of stuff
and my priorities would just be a total mess
that's why I'm not a detective
I genuinely don't think I would be good at it however
I am the detective of the mind
that's actually something i
encourage pretty often to my clients
is to be detectives of their ownminds
because like what does a detective do right
they show up to a crime scene and they do not just immediately
make a claim about like who did it
they don't just show up
and they're like it was it was the butleror whatever they
they canvass the scene
they taking the evidence they talk to witnesses right
and like you should be doing the same thing
when you arrive on the scene of a new emotion
we are like oh that that really made me mad
it must be because that person is an idiot
no like
investigate that a little more right
do some detective work of why you might be feeling that way
and you know your first impulse may be correct
it may have been the butler but sometimes it is the butler
sometimes you show up to the scene
and you realize that you're the murderer
which judging by the twists and turns that this game has taken
I would not be surprised if we
killed or were involved in some way in the murder
now
I also want to talk about the dream sequence
that we saw at the end of the last episode
I was a little too tired to really talk about it
very haunting scene
something that I really took away from it is
like I've been getting the sense
as we wander through Revachol and stumble upon things like
our room
people we've pissed off our missing gun
the bottles on the roof top and stuff like
I had the suspicion that we were not happy with who we were
pretty evident right
but the dream sequence scene was like
really hammering that home visually for me because
here we have harry hanging from the tree from a disco ball
which was pretty cool and very thematic
and he's talking about he says something like you've
billions of people in the world
and you failed every single one of them
that kind of inner dialogue like
if I'm imagining that
this is someone's conceptualization of themselves
this is past harry
the drunken hanging corpse
is like who he feels like he was before all of this right
and so genuinely a lot of my work is on
like reauthoring narratives about yourself and
learning to be kind to yourself
and so like I think it would be very pertinent to
investigate that side of Harry right
like in a therapy session or multiple therapy sessions
like when you the kinds of questions I would ask
would be like so let's say harry came in and he said well
I had a dream last night that I was you know
the hanged man and whatever else
you know my line of questioning would be kind of like
what do you feel about this person that you saw
what kinds of ideas do you have about them
you might say well I hate him I'm afraid of him right
this would start putting us on to like well
what is your relationship to this person
because like there's a very different kind of emotional posture
you could have to say
well I hate that person when I see him hanging from the tree
I feel like he deserves this versus
I feel so sorry for that person
when I see him from the hanging from the tree I feel so much regret
one of those is a path to self empathy
right and healing
and the other one is
you just want to forget this person
but I don't think that that would be as helpful to just forget
we cannot just
one day to the next like
okay well I'm just going to be a different person
I think it's fine if he wants to reinvent himself
and be someone new but like
part of really making it clear what virtues you want to develop today
is knowing specifically the kind of
bad qualities you're running away from
and if you just close the book and say
no there's nothing worth looking into here I hate that person
he deserves this
then you will miss out on that deeper sense of clarity
to know truly how bad things were
is to give you guidance for what to work on
and a lot of that is going to come down to learning to love yourself
he is still on his journey of self discovery
which is why we have not looked in the mirror yet
and I don't think I'm ready to frankly
we just saw our past self like hanging from a tree
bloated drunk dying
and this was so shocking to myself and my character
that I feel like it's the first inclination to wanting to learn more
but we're not ready to to say definitively
like am I happy with the person that I am instead of that person like
I may look in the mirror
but I just don't think he's ready yet
I know that that's killing some people inside
but this one's really important to me because like
that's one of the first options that you get
and I've approached it several times
and I just got the feeling that like it's not time
maybe you‘re a vampire could be I love that the game is giving me the option
question how do you interpret dreams in your profession
that's a good question I don't generally like I'm not a
the one reason I don't is because I'm not like an expert on dreams
by any means
if someone comes into the session
and they are talking about a dream and
I guess my approach to dreams is like
let's say I'm working with someone on their relationship with their mom
and then they come in and they're like I had a dream about mom
I'm like okay well
let's that's good like let's process that
what did it feel like what was the situation
in the dream why do you think your mind was going there all these things right
I guess what I'm saying is that
my intention to analyze dreams is when there is like
already context to that subject in the sessions
if someone comes into my therapy session is like
so last night I had a dream where and they just start telling me randomly random stuff
and it's not related to anything that we're working on
I'm not gonna like
so let's unpack that you know what I mean
but yeah I don't know
I'm not like super well versed on like what things mean
I'm more I will unpack it to say like
okay so you had a dream that
you were in an argument with your mom
and she was wearing your shoes like
I don't know whatever
this is random stuff
what does it make you feel to talk about that right now
like I'm gonna bring it present
I'm not going to be able to make an objective analysis about what it means
what I can do is grapple with like well what does it mean to you
that you saw this
like what do you interpret from it and is that useful
sometimes it is
okay so we are on day two finally
and it is once again my objective to
progress the game and solve the murder
we have to solve this murder
good morning Kim
let's get him involved for this sprightly morning
morning
love it love it
just one of those quick nod
I've got some good news
I took care of the body
the thought of him decomposing in my mc
wouldn't let me sleep
I took care of the body
yeah I know we missed out on some of that narrative
but I'm I'm okay with that good
well let's see what happens
I don't know if I was ready to let him go
well he's in processing now
we have other matters to attend to
I'm okay with that
he kind of wishes you'd acknowledge this contribution
but you've missed your opportunity now
fuck
now I'm invested in like being Kim around a good trajectory
now I'm worried about disappointing him further
the union muscle finally turned up
and he looked rowdy
we need to talk to them
okay
what do you mean rowdy
I mean ungovernable
Martinaise isn't exactly enthusiastic about the RCM being here
they prefer to be policed by the union
these men here men who drink beer for breakfast
there's talk of an armed wing of the union called the hardy boys
who are responsible for sage policing
I think it's them
that's a great word ungovernable
well look that's what happens in real life sometimes
you you say something with one intention
and then the other person like
you read into it that they are disappointed in your response
and then you just have to move on that's just life
why do we need to talk to them
everything points to the Duckworkers’ union
the belt used for hanging him
tracks in the mud
the circumstances in Martinaise
my preliminary information
which may of course all be wrong
but we still need to talk to them and it won't be easy
okay
are these the men Garte told us about
I completely forgot
sorry I had a rough night sleep
it's them by the looks of it
loud and nasty
just like the manager said
so Kim may have been having some of his own disturbing dreams
one loose thread less to worry about
and one big problem to replace it
okay
there are so many of them
maybe we should call in reinforcements
that would just escalate tensions
no captain would sign off on it
solving one murder
isn't worth a conflict between the rcm and the Debardeurs' union
in fact even the *death* of two detectives
might not warrant an all-out war
so let's keep a cool head okay
okay kim has telling me to keep a cool head
let's see how that goes exaggerating about that mortal danger
just calmly factoring it in
your fist clench and your pulse rises uncomfortably
why why *half light* do I
am I scared I'm scared of what's gonna happen
I'm scared of myself
that I won't be able to control my urges to fight them
let's roll
one more thing before we do
we don't have to talk to them immediately we can walk right past them
continue with our business
oh okay
so we can go on a bit of a side quest to binge I guess
good a power move
purposefully concentrate on something else first
look I love a good power move
yeah streetwise zoom right past do it on your own terms
yeah boy
they are in no hurry to leave they think they own the place
anyway I leave that choice to you
whatever you decide is fine by me
look I I want to progress the storyline
but I also have a lot of things I need to do
there are so many things okay
we're not obsessed with getting our smokes
we've sort of resolved that one
I'm gonna need some more money
I'm sure we'll find that along the way
I need to make a truce with Cuno
that's a priority
that's a big priority for me
I have to offer him something so
I don't have that book in my possession
it's the jam mystery
there's a lot of things I could do
I mean
I guess none of these are really a priority
let's see what lena's up to
let's get her perspective on all this
just a moment
and there's no public phones nearby
the closest phone booth is down the coast
sorry for the inconvenience ma'am
that's not just an inconvenience friend
you better not do anything to make lena's day any worse
it's fine I understand thank you anyway
I'm glad to see you again dear
she's so understanding
the lady is distressed perhaps something more upbeat might cheer her up
howdy Lena what's kicking no
why is it giving me options to say these things
good day ma'am everything all right
sorry ma'am I didn't mean to eavestrap on your conversation
tell me how I might make it up to you
that's very polite that's very sorry cop
let's go with that
please don't trouble yourself about me sweetie
I was just hoping to make a call
but the whirling's phone line isn't working
thank you thank you for subbing with prime
that's very much appreciated
the union office probably has a phone
but I can't really get there
or to the phone booth down the coast
and Gary's phone is dead too
what's wrong with the phone line
who did this
the manager was vague about it
he was vague you say
now I gotta ask the question
why did you need to use the phone
to let the young woman whose house sitting for us
know that we may be delayed
Morell my husband and our friend Gary
were supposed to get back by Monday night
but they're still missing and I haven't heard from them
interesting okay
so Gart may be involved in their disappearance
I don't know
look you gotta ask yourself who benefits
in times like this
the phone line just suddenly goes down
right when sweet Lena needs it come on now
I don't see how those dots connect naturally
I was also hoping she'd heard from Morell
you hear that someone's missing
there could be foul play afoot
I knew it I knew it
I love missing persons cases
that's right
now skip the foreplay
time to dive into the dark alleys
start shaking down the usual suspects
you know legwork
yes
doing some good will alleviate the hangover
at least you're of use to someone
thank you volition
I appreciate the encouragement
this sounds more like a side thing
I need to take care of my main thing
no this is the main thing right now
okay I'll bite
has your husband gone missing before
that's just it this isn't like him at all
He always plans his expeditions so carefully
a cold breeze hisses through dense thickets of reeds
something sweet in it somnolent
a damp chill goes down your spine
when you look around
you're still in the whirling in rags
but you have more important things to worry about
don't don't do that to yourself Lena tell me more
what was this expedition he was on
just some field work sweetie
Morell is a highly trained scientist
he and his assistant Gary
are studying an extremely rare species of insect
they should have returned by now
they were just going down the coast
across the waterlock to set a few traps
he said they'd be back on Monday
oh shit so they've been missing for like
some time
hmm
who's this Gary person
sweetie
it's nothing like that
Gary's as loyal as they come
I trust him with my husband's life any day
what about the traps
I doubt it sweetie
the traps aren't big enough for humans to get caught in them
they're for the inset
anyway
do it find him
this will surely lead to a mystery with that extremely rare insect
this sounds like police business
I'll help you find your husband
are you sure we have time to go chasing after bug-hunters just now
I did suggest we played cool but
Kim you just told me
this is part of my power play okay
look the union guys
they're a rowdy bunch okay
they're muscle men
what better way can I show my my prowess
then helping this poor lady with her issue
it's just a little side thing we'll do it down the line
I've already given my word I'm honor-bound (to up hold it)
honor bound sounds pretty cool
but that sounds kind of like a like
an excuse
the scientists could be connected to our main case
that could be true
I know he tells me don't worry like do whatever you want
then he's like
sorry friend is that really worth your time right now yes
it's just police work
hmm it's just a little side thing we'll do it down the line
if you say so
that sigh is very unappreciated at this time
oh thank you officers truly
I'll be right here if you come across any sound of Morell
the waterlock on the canal is broken
so your husband is probably just stuck on the other side of the coast
that's good intuition
oh my what happened to the waterlock
probably just some technical problem
well whatever the cause I'm thankful
to both of you
you've spared me another sleepless night
you're welcome ma'am
I hate to ask
but if your investigation takes you to the other side of the coast
please do keep an eye out for my husband
and if you see him
let him know Lena is waiting for him here at the whirling
he gets so tangled up in his work that he may not know
the water lock's been repaired
and it's cold out there
if I see him I'll let him know you're here
oh you're such a dear
thank you sweetie
let's find out more is he some kind of scientist
oh yes a zoologist
a cryptozoologist to be more precise
what is a cryptozoologist
it's absudoscience
that attempts to legitimize research
into mythological beasts and urban legends
he does sound unimpressed
that's one opinion yes
and people are entitled to their opinions
ah shit okay so there's some tension between Kim and Lena
my two loves why
I thought you guys said this was about a detective in a murder case
no one told me this was gonna be a fucking love triangle
my apologies ma'am I did not mean to undermine your hobby
he is just jealous
he's jealous that Lena and I have a budding trusting friendship
and that he and I are still on our first date
it's not a hobby deer
it's a subfield of zoology
one specializing in animal species that are so exceedingly rare
that many assume them to be extinct or even fictitious
Kim I can't believe you just called it a hobby
searching for such species called crypteds
is difficult and often thankless
and frankly many scientists are too lazy to do it
universities these days are rarely interested in supporting real research
okay see this is where the detective work comes in all right
Lena is looking for the cryptids her her husband he's a
he's a bonafide scientist man
he is looking into the mystery of some sort of spectacular insect creature
and he is gone missing
this time I really do wonder like no memes
like who benefits
legitimately like who would
who is trying to stop the discovery of this
a new species of bug
you just gotta act like you cannot
you cannot go through this without asking that question
she's completely internalized her husband's struggles
they are her own
maybe you should convince her to tell you about some cool cryptids
well that's yeah now that she's less worried about her husband
tell me more about this rare insect
oh sweetie it's fascinating
I shouldn't bore you with entomological minutiae
the lieutenant gives you a sideways glance
I don't like that I don't like being ch- like forced to pick
I want to make Lena happy but not at the cost of kim's patience
no I want to hear about the insect
Kim this is interesting okay
this is the this is police work play along
well it's a phasmid technically but
oh yeah here comes the interesting
other phasmids imitate sticks or leaves
this one's a living reed
it disguises itself among the reeds here on the Insilindian coast
it's named the insilindian phasmid
perhaps you'll end up co-discovering the phasmids with us officers
I'm sure Kim would enjoy that
there's a touch of awe in the way she enunciated the creature's name
I knew it
we're gonna be chasing made of insects with cryptozoologies
yes
it's not made up officer
I can assure you
there's a hint of defensiveness to her retort but also confidence
she seems to sit up a little straighter in her chair
there's the power play
it's simply elusive
so much so that most establishment zoologist doubted exists at all
um is it dangerous
not at all why else would it hide itself so carefully
Is it valuable
I doubt it no one gets into cryptozoology for the money
does it have cool powers
yes it can blend in almost perfectly among the reeds
it's how it stayed hidden all these years
centuries even
look okay aside from like whether this thing is real or not
this is all she has
like let her enjoy this
what makes you think it's around
some teenagers making out in the reed saw one
they didn't know what it was of course
but there was a brief article in a local newspaper
about their encounter with a ghost insect that looks like the reeds
Gary sent us the clipping
was Gary real Lena
or did you fabricate him
as well
of course most phasmid sidings turn out to be false alarms
but their description matched the insulindian phasmid perfectly
and they didn't even know what they were looking at okay
okay so what's so special about this stick bug
I'm afraid I'm not explaining this very well
it is very special
that's painful
that's the worst thing when you're like really excited about something
and you're trying to talk to someone and they just don't care
it's sick
there are some parts of you that are so innocent
that are not worth being embarrassed about
you know if you like something
like enjoy it
don't feel like you have to censor your enjoyment
because of the embarrassment
I'm saying this out loud
because that's something I also need to hear myself sometimes
Morell can explain it all much better
I wish you could hear him describe it
then you'd understand I'm sure
tell me about some cool cryptids
there's really no point in manipulating anyone
she'd be only too pleased to tell you about her work
go on and ask
hey Lena I'd like to hear about some of the cryptids you've studied
could you just tell me a couple of them
oh I'd be delighted
truth be told I could really use the company too
one *cryptid* not a couple one
this won't turn into some kind of cryptid extravaganza
okay Kim just one little kryptid promise
he nods and assumes awaiting posture
I love this little triangle
I don't know I don't know why
they decided to make the relationships like this
but I'm enjoying it
cryptids cryptids let's hear about all the interesting cryptids
what's the biggest cryptid
that would be the Giant of Koko Nur
okay
the Giant lives in the most arid parts of the vast Koko Nur desert
in south salsamara
casting a strange light across the barren wastes
how big is it
no one knows for sure
it is like an *awful* mountain appearing from below the horizon
and expanding to cover almost a third of your field of vision
is it dangerous
luminosity of Koko Nur is a bad omen in local folklore
some say it's a fata morgana
others a fate unimaginable
hooey
no animal can be that large
it's a mirage
that's what makes it so peculiar
a species surviving at the very limits of scientific law
the Giant of Koko Nur must be the largest animal the planet can support
let her dream Kim
there are limits you see to how large metabolism and ecosystem can beget
some say a gravity anomaly below the Koko Nur desert
might allow the creature to grow to these *gargantuan* sizes
so so because the folklore doesn't make sense
you also need to like invent a secondary
abstract explanation to justify it this is interesting
great this is great shit you need more
yeah what's the littlest cryptid just one more
hey you promised you'd only ask about one cryptid
but Kim don't *you* want to hear about another cryptid
right okay we can move on for now
it'd be dishonorable to renege on the promise
I guess that's true look I'm
I'm hanging on for dear life here with Kim
I don't want to disappoint him
he nods approvingly
okay
maybe when maybe when Kim is busy
we can come back and hear more about the cryptids Lena
I'm gonna leave
Lena
okay
no more distractions
okay let's just I mean I guess I don't really need to do any of this stuff first
I can just ask them
because maybe that'll give me some more direction as well
let me handle this
detective disorientated
are you still wondering where you are
this is Martinez in case you forgotten
I advise you not to overstay your welcome
you're the gardener right
no I am not a gardener
I'm a legal counselor for the dog workers union
what you lied to me
so let's get to it you're looking for Titus Hardie
you think he has information that will help you
maybe he does
I've been manipulated again
that's Titus talk to him
but know this I'll be keeping an eye on you
no strong-arming nothing official
the district of Martinaise does not recognize your authority to make arrests
what I can't just arrest anyone that I want
it doesn't matter if you recognize our authority
we will make an arrest if we have to
fucking that's right Kim
she says nothing her glare speaks for her
fucking kim's got my back
you're sure Easy Leo mentioned something about a lawyer Elizabeth someone
but you're too dumb to remember what it was
god damn it my brain is like
it's so poor it detecting simple things
umm
what's your role in all of this how do you benefit
like I already told you I'm a legal counselor
do you have hearing problems
I I
like one thing I am already having a hard time bearing with is how stupid I am
I do not insult me as well
my character is very fragile
that's one of the things that I think is actually really tangible about
what my character would be going through
becoming a sorry cop finally facing
the very negative picture you have of yourself in your own mind
they are evidence that the character is like interested in
developing a more realistic view of himself right
and that's actually something that comes through in this kind of work
when I'm talking about like
the narrative process that I see
is you go through identity deconstruction and then reconstruction
and deconstruction looks like
listening to feedback right
hearing what people have to say
good bad critical praiseworthy whatever
you're integrating everything
you're allowing yourself to be exposed to
as many views of yourself as there can be right
because the whole issue with narrative
is often that like we only view one storyline of our life
and so we want to acknowledge as many as we can right
before we start reconstructing the identity
with something that's
maybe not more positive but is more realistic
so you have to be able to listen to what people have to say about you
you have to be able to integrate that with what you think about yourself
Harry does not really know what he thinks about himself
but he doesn't like being called stupid
and he doesn't like when people insult him
which is a good sign
because it means he is in some ways protective of like who he is being
he doesn't want Kim to think he's too distracted
he doesn't want Lena to think that she is delusional
the concern that I am having about how people perceive me
is evidence of the deconstruction process right
raise my arms
I mean I guess that could be a power play
what if I want to talk to *you* not Titus I am talking to you
she's going to say you are talking to me
what you want is of no significance *officer*
don't test your authority
in Martinez you are no one
fucking let's go authority chime in
I saw what you were thinking
you want to say what are you going to *do* to me
yeah
don't just because it's in your head doesn't mean you have to say it
fucking yeah right
you will not use out on anything good by not saying it
okay interesting little flip here
like Authority is being the more reserved
and Volition is telling me to say it anyways
what are you going to do to me
hmh
what are we going to do to you
shit
Volition you have steered me wrong why did you do this
you were specifically asked *not* to say that
and then you said it anyway
you junior delinquent
but you still did
the union isn't going to *do* anything to you
it is not a crime syndicate it is a labor organization
we're stumbling through every
look I it's in character our guy is like
he's trying to be an Authority figure but he's a total failure at it
we failed with Cuno
we failed with Joyce
we pretty much failed with Evart Claire like
and we fail here again like
it is so within our character to keep doing this
god damn right it is
which is don't have the intellect
if anything it is the RCM who *do* things to people
but we digress
why are you so aggressive
aggressive you make your living enforcing violence
these people are just *duck workers*
hmh so you were spying on us
and now you represent murder suspects
*just dock workers*
listen you Moralintern lackeys
you're a mob enforcing the unlawful privatization of Revachol
twenty fat men in the Occident are stealing it all
and you're their bodyguards
fuck yeah
hmm
so ask what you came to ask or get back to your commanders
ah fuck this looks like politics stuff
let's take it a step further armed uprising
where are the union's plans uhhhh
yeah let's ask those questions
that's another thing I'm warming it up I'm warming up to it
okay let's do it all right
this is that was just a test okay
what I what I'm doing is I'm playing them
I want them to see that
I have no game and now their defenses are not up
this is a strategic police work in action
this is where you say your bit
let's let's keep it together
he's used to giving orders and having them obeyed immediately
you should not indulge him
okay
detective
the lieutenant acknowledges you with a sharp note
he's leaving it to you
precinct 57th's finest scans the room
leaving the speaking to you
he trusts you
maybe against his better judgment but he does
okay
got kim's trust
don't say anything yet okay
we've been down this path before
hey hey dipshit you hard of hearing or something
the boss man's talking to you
fuck off cross your arms
what is he fucking kidding
this guy high or something
hey asshole up here we're talking to you
we are looking for Titus Hardie
um
no we're not gonna we're not gonna feed the troll
we're not gonna get into their attitude
let's get straight to the business here
we need to talk about the man hanged out back
oh this is about him
a real looker that one
you sure took your time huh
waited for him to get real ripe and pretty for you
oh he was a real pretty boy hanging up there
letting out that *pretty-boy smell*
I can't for the life of me understand why you did it
I mean I would have just left him up there
you must really like cleaning up other people's shit
you might want to start asking your questions now
it's not going to get better than this
I don't like being
these guys are so macho they're ready to confess to first-degree murder
ask if it was them
there's too many there's too many people
I feel like I'm being triangulated
let's scan the room let's get a scope on this
starting from the right boot size 44 blond man in his thirties
overbearingly masculine
okay
sitting on his right standard working boots size 45 or 46
eldest in the room probably mid-fifties
smoker quiet
across at the other table
hobnailed working boots size 43 gang tattoos
Mesque or Saramirizian in his late thirtirs/early forties
a symmetric burn on his neck
resembling the letters *Los Los*
has he tried to burn it off
leave that life behind
and then standard working boot steel reinforced toes size 46
the big dick wide at the shoulders and lean at the hips
rugby cap fingerless gloves
and numerous scars a little under forty
the emblem on his vest says Rowing club
a little patch below it reads T. Hardie Captain
in the far corner standard working boot
steel reinforced toes size 44
forty-something non-alcoholic beverage in hand
(you squint) is that a *plectrum*
what is a plectrum
on his neck forget it
it's not important
size 41 with the light step
not a child after all
an older man with a rat face
mean watery eyes and two front teeth miss him
the whole gang is here
in the middle heaving and wheezing big guy boot size 46
deep marks probably carried the victim over
he alone is 130 kilos
add the man in armor
and you could easily exceed 220
in conclusion
these seven are the actors on the crime scene
the footprints were theirs
but there's a discrepancy
can I not just arrest all of them
right now it's pretty evident that they did it
it's probably more to the story than that
but I want to exert my authority
exactly you've stood there for about four seconds
not saying anything
hit them with questions
where's the eighth Hardie
let's do it
the fuck is with you fella
the hanged man in the back yard did you do it
or no let's just say let's go straight for it
I found eight sets of footprints
but there's only seven of you
what are you talking about madman
there's no eighth Hardie boy
there's seven of us and we're all here
or what
you want to be the eighth Hardie boy
we ain't hiring
we could have been
actually boss we've been talking
and we think she could maybe
this person Glen wants to hire
he really respects her
she
so there's an eighth Hardie and it's a Hardie girl
who might it be Elizabeth the gardener
shut the fuck up Glen
I do talking here
now what the fuck do you want cop
so let me get this straight
there is an eighth Hardie boy it's a she
and you don't like us talking about her
that's that's good insight
that's right we're not talking about this
this is a private Hardie boys matter
nothing to do with your shit
and you're not cops here
don't go digging around
if you don't want a bullet in the back of your head
I'm watching you
good we are all watching each other
officer your question
there's no pushing further he thinks
this is already a victory
we'll learn more about this 8th Hardie sooner or later
all right that was the first good double team that we've had
fucking power dynamics all over the place
interesting
what do we got up here
photos of men and overalls toting guns and union placards
oh there's some money
what do we got here
all right we've got some good information from them
and see if Elizabeth has anything else
I have nothing to say to you why are you wasting your time
are you the Hardie girl
let's just hit her with a hard question
I am not
you could be Liz
you could be anything
you could even be a model
even a mod
Glen I went to law school
I am an attorney
he's right with a face like that
she could be on the cover of la debutant international
get a grip Glen she went to law school yeah
let's let's divide and conquer
so fucking what
lots of models are actually really smart people fuckwad
I hate being insulted like that
no Glen they aren't
ah fuck okay
don't insult me I am very fragile
Lena get in there and show them
show them what it means to be a good human
okay
let's talk to this guy what is he got for us
got any insights he's seen anything around
it's all about money you know
this guy this is the who benefits guy
right here
that's he's just sitting around all day
and that's what he's thinking he goes he
what's his story
let's say psychoanalyze him
what's he got
money is what really matters
they say money can't buy you happiness
but that just means you don't have enough money
you have to invest your money wisely
you can buy stocks with money
and then use those stocks to make even more money
that way you'll have enough money
when you grow old to make new money
real estateis the grave yard where tired old money goes to rest
money is what literally makes the world turn
the laws of money are just the laws of nature
unpaid labor doesn't net you any money
there's no
how many fucking lines of dialogue does this guy have
money is all about numbers
money is actually all about trust
it's all about money you know
wow
I I am shocked at how many like just
ambient dialogue choices this guy has
okay
it's all about money is it
then what has led you sir to sitting around drinking all day
where's the profit motive in that
I think your system is flawed
okay let me let me try this out he's a capitalist right
that's the money politics
I don't know let's go see what Cuno's up to
I can go tell Garte that I understand money now that's true
I just have to hit him with it's all about money friend
have you come to make your offering to Cuno
okay look
I do want to make up to Cuno
but I can't really give him cigarettes
I think that would be
well it would be amusing
our character is starting to develop a better moral path to solving problems
I'll come back when I have something substantial for you Cuno
I have not forgot about you
let's take another look at those footprints
what do you see
no we've been through all that okay
um so I don't have my badge I can't talk to Joyce
I guess I could ask around about the tattoos
the watermarks I don't know let's what I should do is actually
look at my ledger right
I had something in here that I didn't have yeah
can I do something with this
let's try this again
it's the ledger you found in the trash
a cabbage of papers hanging from the board
with the permeables' drawer inside
it's barely held together by a clip
then made complete by the faint smell of urinal cleaner
okay so
my odds aren't great
I can always try though
let's try to read the case files first
yes at last
you find a way to piece them together
using the alphanumeric code on the margin
HDB41 date of initialization and time of arrival on the scene
followed by the title for example
HDB41120117:00 the next world mural
weren't those officer precinct
why yes
your precinct number is 41
and HDB
every last alpha numeric in the files begins with it
and these are your case files
it's safe to say H.D.B are your initials
Harry Du Bois
H.D.B.
still feels like there's something missing from that
I think what you meant to say was RAC Rafael Ambrosius Costeau
yes I'm ready to give up on Rafael
he was a necessary
facade
but I'm ready to move on from him
that's comforting to hear
now detective
it takes half an hour to piece one of these together
if you still want to
here are your options
I want to okay the next world mural let's go
this one is relatively easy to reconstruct
overnight on 1202
a graffito nay a mural
appears on an eight story tenement overlooking central jamrock
the building is a sparsely inhabited ghost tower
part of a failed real estate development called Grand Couron
the mural is enormous
two silhouettes a man and a woman are kissing
the text cut into their form reads
TRUE LOVE IS POSSIBLE
ONLY IN THE NEXT WORLD
FOR NEW PEOPLE
IT IS TOO LATE FOR US
WREAK HAVOC ON THE MIDDLE CLASS
true love is possible only in the next world
for new people
it's too late for us
wreak havoc on the middle class
not sure how those two ideas are really
connected this could take up my whole day
people call it that thing and that fucking thing
it's visible for miles
in two days
the station's complaint's desk gets clogged with requests to remove the bummer
you and your partner are assigned to the case
the graffito crew is easy to track down
only the Belles Lettres
have the literage of industrial paint to cover the surface
one of the graffito artists is rumored to be rich
they take responsibility for the execution
but not the design
the idealogue of the next world miral
as the crew calls it
remains an unknown
do I ever find out who came up with it
the case files do not show you finding the author of the design
okay
the crew agrees to clean up after themselves
however your partner JV is against the removal
citing public support for conservation
this leads to a debate in precinct 41
which then spreads to the streets of Jamrock
ending in a rare plebiscite
organized by you and the rest of Row III
the nine thousand people subjected to the murals message
all of Lakeside Central Jamrock and Villalobos
plus half of the Eminent Domain participate in the vote
although the case begins with
what appears to be a lot of rambling on the streets
as to how juvenile and stupid the mural is
given a choice between two options
so I'm to decide basically what happened or
am I guessing what I did
I mean I'm okay with the
true love is possible part that's kind of poetic
but I'm not sure about
the whole wreak havoc on the middle class thing
what I did
remove the mural it's wrong
keep the mural it is right
I mean I probably go with what feels right
I would probably remove it just because it's controversial
someone's gonna be mad about that
a staggering 78 percent of voters choose to keep it
turns out the opposition were allowed minority
and that love truly is possible in the next world
for new people
and it is too late for us
I don't know I guess
all that remains is to wreak havoc on the middle class
someone is going to I don't know if someone's gonna like
don't read into the choices I'm making here
I have fucking no idea what this is about to be honest
I'm just gonna choose something
I must have voted and possibly even lobby to remove the thing
because I don't believe in that rubbish one bit
it's human nature
I mean I think that this is accurate right
the middle class are not to be blamed it's human nature
like that's a pretty centrist thing to say like that
this is not a politically motivated thing
they really read into me
look I have no fucking clue what I'm
I gonna make a choice here
I have no idea what deeper thing it implies
I just don't
have
if this were like a psychological question
I would have more depth to say about it
yeah I'm just gonna go centrist
it's human nature
did anyone ask you what you believe in
man with the smelly toilet ledger
what do you want to tackle next
or are we done
I can revisit this
stream like
good man doing nothing
not much has changed in the meanwhile
a bunch of sudden papers still sags from the clipboard
it's pretty in character as well
like what is my attachment to these things
I mean my memory is gone
I don't know if the person I am right now
would make the same decisions
that prior Harry would have done
let's see if we can open that compartment
just relax
the two sides of the board are slightly misaligned
like a draw that's come off the slides
all you need to do is bend the plastic on your knee slowly
okay
the slides snap back into place
it should be possible to just you know
slide the drawer open
without resistance or sound
the two panels move against each other
the compartment is now open
what's inside
two ticket stubs and a handmade postcard
okay
what
pick up the ticket stubs
two octopuses are smiling reaching their tentacles toward each other
in the colored pencil drawings
the tickets permit access to the zoo in Revachol East
the aquarium costs extra
these let you go there too
OK
pick up the card
thin wax paper has been glued to a piece of cardboard
sounds like leaves rustling when you pick it up
you see violet flowers
floral patterns
patches of glue
it smells of chewing gum
apricot flavored
a touch of cinnamon
the end of summer
you think the label says TuttI Frutti
let's open it
familiar handwriting lines the inside of the card
looped round letters in a woman's hand
yes this is what I wanted I wanted to know more
about whatever relationship that we were in that
this is a clear point of major tension in our character's past right
like I've been saying for a while
that there has to have been probably something
something that made us very upset with
I don't know the direction of our life was taking and
that's not to say that the relationship was everything
but a breakup
or some sort of disruption in a major relationship
is often a catalyst for many other things going wrong
that were already going wrong
but that you were withstanding right
like if I have a shitty job
and I don't like the location I live in
but I am really you know happy in my relationship
like there's a lot of stuff I can withstand between those things
but
suddenly something starts happening in my relationship
it's going to like
excuse me it's going to make me
reevaluate how much I'm really able to put up with those other things
and I feel like that's probably what happened to us
lots of stuff was already going wrong
but the relationship
really is what kind of set it all off
yeah I am having some sort of issue with the chat
not only is it not appearing on this green
but I am also like it's like not refreshing from me either
something that led us to amnesia inducing heavy drinking yeah
let's continue
Harry
it begins you're already reading
I wanted to write you a letter  so you can read it when you wake up
maybe it will make you happy
oh shit we actually have something from
from her
throw it away please
we're gonna keep reading
your hand shakes holding the card
every morning when I step out and you're asleep behind me
it says
I find a little piece of sadness in me
I carry it in my chest down voyager road
every step I take it grows
by the time I reach the fuel station
it has filled me entirely
I step onto the light rail and look back
sparks fall from the bow collector
I know it will be like this until late afternoon
when I get off the forty two and walk back to you
keep reading
you you every step I take will get lighter
it almost makes me run sometimes I do
I can't believe I met you
I can't believe the happiness I feel with you
you have a vast vast soul
and I will always always always come back to it
kisses kisses kisses
you feel the air sucked up your lungs
and the blood sucked up your head
everything around you gets dark
small white dots appear
you feel the ledger slip from your hand
no no hold on
we're gonna hold on
to what there's nothing
detective is everything all right
no Kim nothing is all right
what just happened did I die
what
there is nothing again
nothing nothing
nothing sad brother
no treachery just blackout
just lie there
well almost nothing there is the ground below you that's still there
and the small light that's on fluttering somewhere in the basal ganglia
who is that
that's me blue eyes that's me
and who was that
who is what
he speaks of the sickening longing the unwell emotion
even in the darkness he's grasping for it
still trying to hold on to the great sorrow slip in the water
slimy
no I was cool I'm cool
the cool when you're dead brother
here in the palco-mammalian cortex we call it
the shadow
because it's always there
was that the ex-something
bloated corpse of the past resurfacing
no it was beautiful
beautiful
believe me stupid ape
its lack of beauty was not the problem
where is voyager road
there is no voyager road
there are no roads no houses no lights in the windows it's all on pause
my name appears to be Harry
your name is fuck all
it certainly ain't Harry
then what is it
your name is passed out on the ground
dragged around by one of the other evil apes
they're taking you somewhere
just motionless
you think they would let you
until you disintegrate into biomolecules
no someone is breathing on your face now
inspecting your pupil stupid idiot
what is that it's cold
they're pouring something on you it's in you
and it's
it's delicious
glowing lights on a dashboard emerge out of nothingness
oh shit where am I
in the upholstered cabin of Lieutenant KitsuragI's motor carriage
seated in the driver's basket
the air is thick with leatherworks and heavy fuel oil
cold water runs down your chin
volition tried to protect you from this but you needed to know that's true
drink water
ugh Kim saved my life
he saved my fucking life
the water is cold silvery
the stuff of life itself as it pours down your parched throat
the pounding in your head recedes the darkness parts
drink
you haven't drunk water in two days
did you know the human body is not made to survive an alcohol alone
you need a secondary form of hydration
well I suspected something like that was true Kim
with greedy gulps you down half a liter of cold water
some of it spills on the driver's seat
the lieutenant pays no heed to it
what happened
I came in contact with the burnt out ruins of the past
god it's beautifully written
I should ask you the same
you were reading your paperwork then you passed out
I carried you to my Kinema to take you to a hospital
then you came to
how long was I out
I was dehydrated
I fuck it start climbing out the motor car
I have I’m starting
I'm starting to feel that I can trust
Kim to understand what I am going through
and maybe that it explains some of my behaviors
let's tell him that we burnt out
that does sometimes happen
you dropped this
are you okay to proceed
let's solve this case
good
the Ledger of failure in Hatred is a special item
that can be used both as an INTERACTABLE
and a TOOL equipped in your HELD slot for skill bonuses
find it under the TOOLS tab in your INVENTORY
okay
okay there is something that I have been wanting to do
and I think
this moment has given me some context  that I was hoping to find
first before I did this
let's check out the new thought that I got
white mourning
you see yourself from above
you've passed out on the blue tiles of the hostel room floor
even from this distance you can see your eyelids flutter
at the mention of what
a great white object letting out its sweet smell
like a Lily of the valley
the little man's forgotten its name
but he still remembers the feeling
and look he moves the feeling animates him
he instinctively reaches out for the feeling's best friend
a bottle of Commodore Red
he puts on his disco clothes and gets smaller and smaller
okay
what I appreciate about this game is that it tends to
it gives you stuff like this
that's like I understand it viscerally
like I know what the emotional context I'm getting in
but I have no realistic context
which is actually very psychological right like
people either get one or the other
usually like someone is able to give me
a very quick history of what happened to them
and they can say yeah I got in a car accident and I got hurt
and I was scared and whatever else
but they may be missing the visceral or emotional part of that
sometimes people are so shocked emotionally
that they have a hard time like
with the other side of it right like
not so much what happened to them
but pulling together all of the different pieces of what happened to them
for example
Harry is not able to piece together why he was an alcoholic
why he feels so depressed
why he sees the world in terms of power dynamics
why he is so afraid of being seen constantly as pathetic
like these are not
these are things I can't tangibly point to and say in reality that's why
and that's what we're discovering
through the Ledger through all these different things
we're starting to get some of that context
right
a lot of this speaks to like universal language that
we all have about emotions
but we're missing the context of our life right
so there's something I wanna to do
on my
my white board here
I'm bringing out the Brady Board okay
for those of you who are long time viewers of the channel
you will recognize this thing that I have in front of me
so this is called a Johari window
it's called Johari because the guys who invented it were named
Joseph and Harrington
it's a cool name
it's a pretty cool sounding name I have to admit
so the johari window is something
that I do use in therapy with people
for specific things okay
I used the johari window for specific things
like
when we are doing some of the identity deconstruction reconstruction process
when we're trying to learn more about themes and patterns in someone's life
we might use this
framework
to explore some of that
so it's pretty simple how it works right
this is about understanding
how we represent ourselves to the world
where we are right now
so there are things that are known to other people
and that we know about ourselves
for example like certain parts of our personality right
um we're gonna get into everything that belongs here for Harry
but for example
like he is a cop he knows that everyone else knows that right
that's not like this is not an obscured fact about him
so there are things that are known to us
and known to other people
there are things that are known to us
that are not known to other people okay
this is a lot of our emotional conflicts
this is secrets
these are things that we are not super open about yet right
then there are things that are known to other people
but are not known to ourselves right
this is a blind spot
things that other people intuitively know or think about us
that we may not know yet ourselves
and sometimes it could be something you've heard before
like people say I'm a bad cop right
you may be aware that people think that
but it could still be in your blind spot
because it's something known or concluded on by other people
but it's not we haven't like internalized that yet
or gossip
it could be as well right
it's a blind spot
and then there is the unknown
which are things that are not known to ourselves
nor any one else right
and we're going to use this metric to understand harry du bois
as he exists right now
because he's he's a very fascinating person to use this on right
specifically because he is someone with memory loss
but also because we are on this path of self discovery
and we're not sure exactly how we feel about those things
so like from the very beginning right
we can see that we are a cop
but we're not sure like are we a good cop
right
that something unknow to us
and other people don't really know this either
I mean I'm sure that there's some some opinions about it right
but
it doesn't seem like we've internalized that
there is a conclusion made about this yet right
so some things that are known to us and known to other people are
our I'll just put addictions right
we are clearly struggling with the substance use um
what is known to others is that we are
let's say like
struggling with
intelligence we're lacking intelligence
that's something that we are also observing
other things that other people know about us that we also know
is that like
we're struggling
we're struggling emotionally
we're struggling physically rights
we're struggling with all kinds of stuff
so these are some of the things that people do know about us
and we'll keep building that
but I want to put something in each category first right
so something that is not known to other people but known to ourselves right
is like our sense of shame
the reason I'm putting this here and not known to others
even though we have definitely made some shameful actions
is like
we're trying everything we can to protect this from moving up here
and that's kind of more so about what goes in these categories
is we use this to understand where things move as you make decisions and
asking the question okay well what does it mean to you
that having shame about this
like people know you're a cop
but you're not sure if you're a good cop
you're not sure if you made good decisions before you blacked out
you're not sure if you actually have the intuition to solve this case
those things give you shame
and so what you do with that shame
is you try to present yourself as an authority
you try to present yourself as intelligent
and you are failing at those things
we trying to use authority
and so the question we have about being a good cop
is leading to a sense of shame
and to protect this from entering the arena
which is where things are observable to everyone right
we're trying to act out this behavior
we try to use authority to minimize people's observation of this quality
because we're afraid they'll discover that this is
we're afraid that this will no longer be an unknown
and it will become known to everyone that we are a bad cop right
so this is about understanding patterns of behavior and themes
more so than a lot of other things right
that's something that we can point to
because like
my client may come in and say well
I don't know why I keep getting into all these power struggles
with Cuno and Elizabeth and Claire and Joyce and that sort of thing
very simply we were able to discover
what the relationship between these things are
and why there is a protectiveness over that right
so we're trying to use authority
there is definitely some shame that we have
there's a little bit of our past
that belongs kind of like in both of these right
we were sort of starting to learn more about who we were
let's do that
but we're not sharing it openly a lot right
we're not discussing frequently
like what we just saw in the dream sequence
or what we saw on the Ledger
we didn't immediately tell Kim what we thought about it right
and I think that we're not sure about ourselves
our view of self
is kind of a mystery right
it's something that we're not
we're not sure what we think about ourselves yet
all we know is that we definitely have some shame
there is definitely some
like I see it going this way where
because we have a questionable past
and we have
we're not sure what we think about ourselves as a cop
we're already assuming that we regret a lot of what we did
and we're bringing those regrets up here
which is that we're sorry
this has been a big part of reconciling the confusion about the past
is that we don't even know exactly what we did with all of our decisions
and so what we're doing is trying to preemptively apologize
because we just assume that we have regrets about this
our shame
this shame is like driving this motion very strongly right
and so we can actually identify shame
as one of the driving emotions of all of our behaviors right now
because we can look at this and say
yeah we're not totally sure about our past
we can see that the way people look at us about our addiction
about our lacking of intelligence
and even the way Lana talks to us
that she's like so soft spoken
and Kim is so like
he's kind of like he lets us be on training wheels
like we internalize that
and we can see
that people are treating us a very different way
like they're almost they
I think other people can see how fragile we are
in a way that we sort of can't right
we are not actually totally sure how fragile we are
we are not sure
that if you pushed us in a certain direction
we like what our limit is
and I think that that's something that other people can kind of see right
Lena is so soft spoken with us
and Kim kind of puts training wheels on us
because they sort of can tell
what's going to happen if we start
getting too involved with our own feelings right
if we start looking more into this area
and it's evident that
what we just experienced
is learning a little bit more about this right
our fragility sort of moved in this direction
because we looked at something in our past right
when we
when we learn about the past
our fragility sort of like becomes known to us
and in this case
it became known to someone else as well right
it became known to Kim
and we may find in future interactions
that he he tells us like
maybe you shouldn't look into your past so much
because it's harmful to you
and it could disrupt the case right
and so
learning about our past what does this do to us
what does it mean to discover that we are actually quite fragile
it could lead to us
trying to use more authority to sort of pump ourselves up
and show other people that we are not so fragile
what that would be doing is trying to
we're trying to make our past and this fragility become secretive
we're trying to remove other people's ability to see this
because it lowers our chances of sort of convincing them that we're legit
so that's the kind of avoidance that I'm seeing
when we're using the Johari window
we might start looking at some of this
and say okay well
you're scared of people discovering this
you're scared of discovering it yourself
and so what behaviors are you doing to force things down here
when you see things moving a lot in this direction
and concentrating in the facade
you can call that avoidance
pretty clearly right
we can call this like self defense
we can call it trying to control the narrative about how people see you
that's a very common pattern right
if we see things concentrating somewhere else though right
for example
before the story started
it is clear that a sense of shame and regret and fragility were known to us
these could have all been things that existed here
and so drinking alcohol and you know pushing ourselves to the limit
could have been an attempt to move things here
to sort of erase ourselves
and erase our view of ourselves
because this is something that we are not happy about
and so when we are interested in reevaluating something
like for example
you know that we are struggling
sometimes we try to move it here right
because we don't want to
we want to deconstruct it right
are we really struggling right
we want to understand like
is that something that we're really struggling with
and we want to remove it from other people with perception right
so things can sometimes concentrate this way
they can sometimes concentrate that way
what I see more about the rigorous self critique though
when I think about what that means thematically
is like a lot of the motion that we're seeing is really more so like this right
we are invested in learning what's in our blind spot
what do people think about us
we are
what
what manipulates us
what are some of the desires that we have
that we may not even be aware of
that other people are aware of right
someone in the chat asked where would you put desires
honestly I would probably say
it's in the blind spot
because we're not sure what we want yet right
it's not like we know exactly
were not entirely sure if we want to engage with our past
that's why we haven't looked in the mirror
it's not totally unknown
because other people can observe our behaviors
and see yeah well you you spent a lot of time looking for cigarettes
you spent a lot of time you know trying to get alcohol or whatever
and so desires feels to me
like it's here
and that's why manipulation works so well on us right
because it is it's our blind spot
we don't even know what's really gonna trigger us right
our face is definitely in the blind spot
definitely
some amount of our identity
sort of moving like that
like it our identity is is becoming known to us
but the more we learn about it
a lot of times we don't like things moving directly from blind spot over this way
because we haven't been able to decide privately what we feel about it
we are much more comfortable moving things like this way
because it passes through
let's remove people's awareness to that thing
decide how we feel about it
and then maybe I'll show it to the world right
but our identity is kind of like move in the reverse in my opinion right
it's becoming known to other people and ourselves at the same time
we sort of reflect privately on what we think about it
but then the more we learn
like for example that
there's a relationship
one which we are very heartbroken about like
we suddenly learned about it
but it's also unknown to us
like no one else really knows about this either
but what I was saying was we have all these things right
and what I see a lot of
what I see happening a lot is
things converging in the arena here right
it's called the arena because like this is
where your qualities receive the most critique challenge feedback right
its where things are observable to you and to other people
and they are really put through their trials for like
how central they are to your identity right
for example the whole thing with Kim
and my discovery of some of my unknown biases like
they went like this right
like kim's cultural background was a blind spot to me
like I had the wrong read on him
when I learned about that
I tapped into maybe what some of my unknown biases are right
and sort of brought them to the arena like
I shared them with you all
and that's what I see harry doing right
the more you make this motion
and the more you try to bring things here
the more invested you are in
like facing your problems you know
and I see that in the way he is apologizing a lot right
being a sorry cop to me is about alleviating this sense of shame
because we can't change this we can't change our past
we can't change what we did
but we can try to change what it means to us right
and the more we learn about our past
the more we are able to apologize for what we did
the more we're able to apologize for what we did
our identity does become more clear to us
because we see it as a growth of moral character
which slightly reduces the amount of shame that we have
and makes us feel much more
like we are a good cop right
that's also coming up this way
and what happens to our view of self when we apologize
and we see that feedback from other people right
it also improves somewhat
I think to other people first and then to ourselves right
so I know this looks like a mess
joharI window always does like
because we're looking at patterns
we're looking at behaviors
and we're trying to understand like
okay if this is the machine that's driving a lot of this
we need to understand why this is so important to you
and that doing this right here
trying to use authority to protect people from
finding out that you're fragile or manipulatable
is not reducing the shame
it's actually making it worse
what's actually reducing the shame is the apologies right
and the positive feedback that you get from them
so harry's development is very much like
this motion right here right
so it's interesting
this is something we'll return to the more we learn about him
because there's so much stuff here right about his past
and there's so many things
we're probably not even aware or in our blind spot
but yeah we're gonna keep this in view
as we continue building out our view of mr harry
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it consider giving it a like
and letting me  know what you thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a little bit earlier if you support the channel
either through Twitch or patreon
links to both of those and the community discord are in the description
thanks again and I will see you next time bye