hello
and welcome back to my therapist plays
Disco Elysium analysis series
so on today's episode
we are delving even deeper into the psychology of
our main character
as this case gets more complicated
so does our relationship with ourselves
because we're also going to start
discovering more about who we were and
finding that we are not so happy with that person
before we had amnesia
and woke up as the person we are today
and so what does it mean
to be faced with some of those challenges
do we avoid them and try to shut them out
or do we look for
healthy ways to integrate them and move forward
but we also do get into a major confrontation
we're going to face
what it is like when we go up
against an individual named Measurehead
who stands between us and
our next objective in solving the case
so all that is coming up in today's episode and
perhaps our first moments of
genuine trust starting to build between ourselves and our partner Kim
I'm excited to continue this journey with all of you so
let's jump in
hey there's a big gentleman
bastards
we have a right to work
maybe this is the gentleman who
was asking about our case is a large lad
what's going on here
hold up and stay frosty everyone
cops are here
the broad shouldered alpha male turns to you
he's a full head taller than everybody else here
you here to fuck with us
beat the honest worker down
why should I
we're here to fight for a cause
stripes usually have problems with people who have causes
okay then I think I
I think no I want to be on your team friend
good
we're fighting for a cause here
right to work
besides
we're not that different
it helps if people see us talking
cops and strikebringers together
shows authorities around our side
builds confidence
I like his perspective I agree
I agree with that
I think it's also kind of a power play that
I'm like grinding the flashlight in everybody's face
because it makes them feel like I'm really targeting them
which is good for my interrogation
what kind of problems are we talking about
rights of workers to have gainful employment
to make a salary
and feed their families
well I don't want to politically align with him
but I want to be on his team
because it looks like he could beat me up
so I don't want him to be angry at me
I don't think I've chosen any sides
any time
don't let the fat bastards tread on you
cops tend to sigh with the higher-ups
you're essentially still workers
I don't trust cops but I can see you understand though
right to work
let's just ask them some questions
hey Chris Wilderness
thank you so much for subbing my friend
enjoy your early access to things through the channel discord
you have to link your discord and
your Twitch account you'll be able to see all the
prior streams and stuff
maybe you should ask them
(maybe you should ask them) the questions like
why would not allow to make a living here
shame on you we have families to feed you piece of shit
so do we scab
found you from your YouTube channel
on your playthrough of this game
very excited to see more of your content
thank you
it's been a very interesting seeing all of this unfold
but we're having a great time
throwing some fucking tomatoes in the chat for our friends
tomato is like my my hype emote
you may not understand why but that's okay
just know that tomatoes are a good thing around here
they mean something good
I don't like them as fruits
but I love them as metaphorical devices
we flood the chat with tomatoes when we're happy
that's all you need to know
I actually need to speak with the union boss
that is true
have fun
union shits are on full strike
don't think they're going to let you through the gates
why you want to meet that fat asshole
this is an official matter
yeah I'm not gonna get this guy involved
he looks like he would use my information against me
right to work
it's shameful cops doing nothing
you should bring backup open up the gates for us
blockading gainful employment for workers is a crime
yeah the tomatoes are a Gundam reference
witch for Mercury
this isn't really my area of expertise
we are not picking a side in this  just yet sir
finally Kim stands behind me for once
let us work
who are all these strikebreakers
(honest men and) women with rights to work to be useful
not toys for corporate interests
this guy is a he's a communist right
we came here to help the harbor
run smoothly in time of crisis
if Union fucks don't want work
they ought to let indulgs who do want work
I have a question
why do all these men follow your leadership
that's a good question Kim
no he's against the strike of the union
the other guy is a communist
let me take off the mask of if there even is one
that I know anything about politics
I do not it is not my area of safe commentary
I am a mental health professional
I don't really have the vocabulary or the knowledge to
to give commentary on any of that shit
and I will just make myself look like a fucking idiot
if I do
so
don't worry this game will teach you
I hope it does I don't like
it's just not my sector I spent my life studying people
and psychology
we're just informing you don't worry I know that's okay
mental health is political yes
I can see the parallel but it doesn't come up in my work as often
this is the crossover that you will find
in mental health and politics
is what we might call SDOH or social determinants of health
what I'm referring to are all of the
environmental political economic systems that
contribute to mental health
so you're correct
an economic system that
does not offer like equal opportunities to people
is going to lead to suppressed angers resentments
it can lead to racism
that sort of thing
like homelessness
obviously is a big impact on mental health as a social determinant
and it is influenced by political things
I understand that they are
that there is a thread connecting them but
my expertise is not in commenting on politics
it is understanding the mental health outcomes
that result from political systems
I don't even know really what I would say I'm
politically but it's
yeah I don't know
it's that it's not worth diving into to be honest
so I do know about politics
sort of
but not not to any sort of like depth about this like
I know about them
mental health relation but not like by themselves
you think they follow because I'm big and loud
no they follow the rules of the market
the rules of the economy
because they were
given a job to do
yeah I guess what I would say is
I don't know how to spot what political system is which
what I do know is like
this is going to lead to lots of outgroup resentments
when workers feel underprivileged
and they haven't been fairly represented democratically
what is your goal here
we were promised work we'd be in there working
working
if the bastards hadn't shut the gates
and your are unable to breach the entrance
would take heavy ordinance to bust it open
could try to get in through the secretary's office
doors locked
the guards blocking the way to the access panel
I don't mean the scrawny Mesque punk either
I mean head measurer
or whatever he is
why don't you just talk to them that's a good idea
like civilized folk you mean
these native fucks don't understand civilized
it would be better for the neighborhood if you went home
at least for now if you can't get in anyway
it's a very neutral stance to take Kim I like it
no
they will give up eventually
or get drunk leave the button unguarded
then we charge
sounds like this guy needs a little bit of that boost
he gets from alcohol to his physical instrument
what is a strike
(when a) bunch of ungrateful
lazy cockroaches can't get their act together
decide to block honest work for other people
what do the strikers want
they mumble nonsense about board rooms and workers rights
while we have the right to work
when the man moves around
you perceive some serious abs underneath his tight fitting shirt
this man is in shape
yes he is
this seems odd in the way he carries himself
his sets of clothing looks vaguely mismatched
the different pieces of the attire seem ill fitting
what is that (mean)
it is far too small and an unpleasantly tight fit
while the overalls held up by a belt
seem to fit a man with much more corpulence
interesting
he ignores your question
choosing instead to turn to the emaciated workers
raising both fists in the air
the close are obviously not his
very interesting
if all the other workers are emaciated
why is he so buffed out
here's the thing guys
you gotta ask yourself who benefits
maybe he's a stooge
maybe he is actually on the wealthy union side
or is not really a part of these individuals
but he is very impressionable
and
able to assume the perspective of a leader archetype
which lots of people will crowd around and follow
and think that he has their best interests
when really he's the one saying well we can't storm in yet
he's actually a plant to stone wall
their initiative by pretending to be one of them
could be
who's to say who benefits
silence is the answer
there's something off air
but he won't say what
fucking rhetoric coming in now
you've been talking to him for quite a while man
something is off with the sky
asking where he's from
where are you from friend
what's it to you
routine part of the investigation
am I a suspect
done no crimes
I only fight for the rights people
I'm interested in your background
we're all workers right
workers stick together
came from the eminent domain jamrock backgrounds
and odd jobs heavy lifting cargo hauling bouncer work
I know the drill
a bouncer huh
where I frequent a lot of bars maybe it's one I know
worked at Territorial
ring a bell
never heard of it are you lying
we're done here
I have a strike to break
sus extremely sus
I don't like it
okay
we need to get up in there
scab
wait
what's happening
am I about to like
okay
I'm not a scab I'm a cop
ah I was just messing with you
no one's ever seen a cop scab
imagine you cops going on a strike
but then another cop comes in and says
let us cop for less money
speaking of what brings the RCM here to the Wild North
come to see the strive
I need to speak with your boss
I'm a bit short on money right now
can you give me some of it
actually I think we're pretty good on money right now
what's the strike about anyways let's find out more
(you know) serious business
I'm sure the big boss will be glad to tell you
you'll have to ask him first
okay I'll ask him first
wants to talk about the strike
return once you've met the union boss
and are on a better footing with the organization
finally suggestion coming in with some actually good insights
I mean I guess it can't hurt to ask him for money right
(sure thing) my friend
I can help you out
wait
why don't I just let it fall on the ground and then pick it up
right can't I
I don't want to embarrass myself again
I can't go through another embarrassment
I know let it fall in the ground
because it's lame well he think it's stupid
catch it
should I go for it we don't need worse morale I know
well look I
either I try to catch it and I embarrassed myself right
let it fall on the ground and I've seen his lame
what what am I supposed to do here okay this is the
hardest like conundrum to be put in
a cool cop would catch it
it would be so fucking lame to let it fall on the ground
and then pick it up
that's almost even more embarrassing
what would authority say authority would say
snatch that fucking coin purse out of this man's hands
this is the decision
I feel like everything kind of hinges on this
what if I drop a point into my hand eye coordination
I feel like I've been failing these over and over again
let's do it
yes
58 percent roll the dice baby
the coin narrowly slips by your outstretched fingers
and falls to the ground
fuck
God damn it
spending a point made it uncool
well look
all I'm trying to do is be the coolest cop around
no feeling like investing into a skill and then failing anyways
that's just my guys life
lost the point and dropped the coin
I know that's extremely lame
oh I'm sorry didn't mean to throw it like that
it's a thing we harbor folk do
passing around cargo and such
oh well he didn't he didn't actually
(was not meant) as provocation or ridicule
okay so he didn't he didn't scold me for it
but what does Kim think
the boiadeiro stares at you with respect
then gestures towards the trickles of blood
adorning your clothes
wait
not catching the coin
just brought me and Kim closer together
I think yeah I think chat's right
there is probably a wrong voice line
but Kim just picked up the coin and handed it to me
that brings me closer to him
something about getting out of the labyrinth of
words and dialogue
just by showing with his actions that
he will pick up where I fail
and not challenge or judge me for it
actually makes me feel a little more trusting of him
do I have a crush on Kim no
so far I have not been very trusting of Kim and
part of that is because I don't know
if he is earnest towards me
he says he has my back
but I don't know if I am just useful to him
but
so far he's been happy to just let me embarrass myself
and not really
well if not like directly feed into that embarrassment or
critique me in front of people
undermining me
but this time he just like
quietly picks up the coin and gives it to me
yeah this
maybe maybe for me
an action speaks louder than words sometimes
thank you Kim
right always glad to help out the RCM
we're on the same branch you and I
humans I mean not slithering scabs
okay I need to get moving here
good good what matters do you want to discuss with Evart
I'm not gonna disclose those details with you yet
so mysterious
I'll come back to you
either way the road in front of you is wide and open
does this mean you can let me (through the gate)
I don't operate in that capacity
I'm not a granter of passage
the passage grants itself
that's simple
walk right past Measurehead and go in
okay past Measurehead
yeah the two and a half meter tall Semenese supremacists there
walk right past him
okay
then press the button to unlock the door
go past him again
okay
enter the arbor through the office
uh okay
I don't think that's gonna be that easy
(don't worry I'm sure it's not) completely impossible
for example you could best Measurehead
in a physical confrontation
or you could convert to a Semenese supremacist world view
or
maybe it actually is completely impossible
well why are you misleading me
how do I get to where I want to go
I do have the physical instrument shirt on
are we extolling why
Kim Kitsuragi is the best damn cop in all of Revachol
and a damn good friend
well best cop I would say
I can agree with
best friend I'm I
it's a it's a I want to trust him
but I'm scared kind of thing with me and Kim right now
due to my character's
extreme trauma and abandonment issues presumably
that's just what I detect from him
it's making it hard for me to trust that he truly is
what he says to me
I want to believe it's true but
I still have my doubts
and yeah also he's been really fucking rude to me at
very important moments
not yet no
he's
incredibly strong
nothing a couple of solid hooks from Dexter and Sinister won't fix
wait is that the name of my hands
Dexter and Sinister
Jean-Luc himself would say the philosophy has proven
overly heroic for the scabs to convert to
sure
alright friend
there's got to be another way to get around this guy right
what do we got here
in case of a strike press button behind the guard
there's no lock picking or door kicking this one
we've got another cigarette friend here
can we talk to them no
okay we're finally at the harbor
let's see if we can
discuss our way through this conundrum
your body betrays your degeneracy
yeah Measurehead
his body totally betrays his degeneracy
don't say anything
size him up first
yeah fucking let's go authority
this is when I need you
this is when I need you to throw out your best dice rolls
let's fucking size this guy up
that's a power play
are you admiring my morphophysiology
a ripple of muscle passes underneath his skin
he lets you look
it must be frightening to stand in the shadow
of this *Racial Pinnacle*
be calm ham sandwich
you are not in danger
because you are not a threat to me
you know what friend I'm not a threat to you
let's keep him talking
let's just puff it out a little bit
what is this *androgynous* display of sexual maturity
merely standing up makes you swept profusely
your breathing is erratic
your own heart beating your ears grows frantic
and you feel your blood pressure rise
okay
stop it
you are embarrassing yourself in front of this woman
and your pedomophic friend
everything I do is embarrassing
khm...
my endurance is down by the cigs
no I trust that the cigarettes have had
no negative consequences on me
this display of weakness may appeal to older women
with a stronger maternal instinct
but it is a liability here on *Battlefield Martinaise*
okay
Jean-Luc
his body is betraying his degeneracy pretty hard
maybe you can ask him to leave
how about I just go with the uh
well let's ask him to clarify that
you have succumbed to *Al Gul*
you reek of it
an invisible sword of *Al Gul* emerges from your throat
you cannot see it but others can
it is making the woman in my company sick
look I don't give a fuck about her
if she's there or not
has nothing to do with my investigation of here
sir
you
you think you think that just by
by
triggering my inferior masculinity that
that I'm gonna be afraid of you because
A: you're probably right
but B:
I just smoked a cigarette
my intellect is gonna help me out of this
let's just stand our ground
well maybe I can get him talking
yes *Al Gul*
what is *Al Gul*
*Al Gul* is an ancient Iilmaraan poison
a parasitic fungus that has colonized your race
it is a trick that desert pygmees played on you
for humiliating them stripping them of their land
you mean alcohol
correct my small-skulled servant
enough I need you to open the door
no you don't
you need to get another drink
occidental haplogroup B4 is done giving orders around here
the influence of the *ham sandwich race* is waning
show him the ham still got it
fucking yeah authority
I am the police and I need you to comply now
or do I ask him to help me do my job
there's no way I can
I'm gonna get my fucking ass beat aren't I
what do I do here Kim
Kim let's get Kim involved I need your help
why is he standing so far away from me
I just noticed that
Kim
I need you up here
I'm just gonna try to rationalize with him
begging for help
attempting to pass fear for cooperation
how far the occidental haplogroup has fallen
you were once a noble and powerful race
yeah let's get Kim involved
you gave the world *eugenics* electricity
and powerful weapons of war like missiles and aerostatic aircraft
you made great gains in metallurgy race theory and statecraft
you dominated lesser cultures
like the deformed Himeans and the inexplicably potato-obsessed Kojkos
but now your ascend to the genetic summit has halted
you are obsessed with sadness and with frivolous pop culture
you've got me all figured out buddy
you will be superseded
isn't that right babe
it is baby yeah you know it
isn't she a part of the ham sandwich collective
that he is deriding so much
there is a button right behind him
just out of reach
it must be the one that opens the door to the harbour
push him out of the way no
I need you to move 20 centimeters
whoa this
I'm just gonna cut right to the chase
enough with this begging
you should leave the stage of history with dignity
by inviting the other races to a *great world war*
bring your troops to the Semenine Islands and to Boogie Street
and we will pulverize you
when you are gone we will build a museum for you
the walls will be lined with bottles of *Al Gul*
your beloved beverage
inside we will store the odes to homo-sexuality you call art
and your microcephalic skulls
okay I have a 42% chance to knock this motherfucker out
I mean it's about defeating racism right
I can retry this one
do I have any skill points I do
let's fucking go
let's drop one into physical instrument and go for it
or I could become a racism
oh
nah
I don't think I don't think I'm gonna go with that one
save the skill point
time to get physical I feel like I kind of have to
this is redemption for Cuno alright as Cuno's...
as Cuno's Pig what better thing can I do
than try to knock this guy out
let's whittle in about down a little bit
with some dialogue
oh don't be vulgar
white or not has got little to do with this
the *race enigma* runs much deeper than that
it could impress Kuno it could
there must be some friction there
he's keeping it well hidden however
good point authority
only invest points after the failing
yeah I can retry it
you still surf him how does that factor into your life
oh we're gonna wheel him down and then suck him
Mr Claire is a man of vision and means
he has the will to confront antarma shunal capital
which is something *your* race navistic communists never did
let's fucking defeat racism chat
also
to serve is noble
it takes discipline
your petulant individualism has only
contributed to your *race failure*
it is lax and moronic
my jam is a mysterious fourth thing
jam
individualism
you have gotten these
ideas from degenerate you've culture have you not
you have picked them up from rock and roll songs
she is the definition of cool and
the cultural center of this world
as far as I'm concerned
I've gotten it from disco actually
offshoots of the semenese people invented disco
while having sex under the influence of cocaine
it is a shame upon my race
but what is done is done
you have heard enough
about our phylogenetic secrets for today
you have extinction to come to terms with
and *never* getting him into the harbor
let's get Kim involved Kim what do you think about this
I think this racist is better than the last
but the next racist will be the really good one
okay that's a good line
I like the previous racist better actually
that is understandable
the previous racist was probably at occidental
did not prove a real adversary
this guy is advanced racism
these cops are just jealous Jean-Luc
just jealous
let's ask him about his stupid tattoos then
how about that
make a fool of them
racists are generally not
very good examples of their race
I am not like them
I am chraniometric perfection
I have taken the trouble to
permanently draw a freenologic grid
on my skull and features
this should dispel any doubt
so not only are you a racist
you subscribe to fraudulent
scientific theory about phrenology
that is a noble cranium
but you got a hard noggin yourself
I do I do physical instrument my noggin is pretty hard
you sure I'm not craniometrically superior to you
you exhibit forward projection of the jaw
indicative of schizophrenia and sexual inaccountability
from a purely aesthetic standpoint
the dimple in your jaw makes you look like a baby
this is not craniomtry
just an observation
what else
it is impossible to see any more of your bone structure
it is covered in the ravages of al gul
from what remain of your features I can see *fleshy lips*
*baldness of the head*
and long arms relative to lower limbs
this leads me to conclude you are not a police officer
you are a common criminal
an offspring of murderers and sailors from SUR-LA-CLEF
and Vesper
and possibly even the degenerate shee headers of *UBI*
interesting so my ancestors was Sir Lucklefe and the other one
your racial heritage is uninteresting
it is the same as all revacholians
your parents and their parents
made the decision to reproduce
while under the influence of al gul
that's the only reason you are here
he's right there
it's almost impossible to get it on
unless you're both drunk
it's too scary when people are sober
all right
let's fucking do it
let's fucking swing if I'm gonna get any checks
hand it back to me
it's gotta be this one for for all of the fucking
non racists out here let's knock him out
Kim back me up
fucking let's go
just like that instinct took over
a solid strike straight into his throat
into the cartilage
you can swear you felt the soft palate break
let's fucking go
the man is reeling gasping for air
time stands still around you
in the distance
the sounds of the harbor are falling silent laughs
yeah so how about that fucking Al Ghul defeats racism
all you hear is a small gurglin sound
as a trickle of blood appears on the mess
okay there's no way I can do a 360 flying spin kick
let's rip into him with a right hook
or can I fail this
360 spin is there spin to win
can I fail this
should I try it
do it
fuck it
Raphael
no fucking way
the man lands while a dull thump
like a broken down puppet of muscles and sinew
for a moment he still tries to keep his head up
dazed eyes looking at you with unimaginable suprise
to your left is *the button*
the coolest thing to do here would to be say
nothing right
just press the button
fucking let's go
as you slam your fist on the button
the man collapses entirely
his head rolling to the side
yeah what do these fucking ladies have to say about that
Cuno would be so proud of me
looks like you're the new measure head now
I'm measure head dude
Cuno is gonna think I'm the fucking coolest
her voice is surprisingly calm
no one is the new measure head
let's go before he gets up
let's go let's fucking go
get wrecked
the man is still knocked out
he breathes slowly and steadily
all right well let's check out what's in that box first
maybe there's some trash
I'm rewarded for my efforts
let's go let's go
that was the best outcome I could have hoped for
I can't catch the coin but I can knock out fucking
a giant racist man
Knoked him out good..
like the Flying Desperado
what is the Flying Desperado
it is that really cool
flying desperado spin kick you did boiadeiro
often performed by
the most hard-bodied boiadeiros on the steppes
that was nothing
so what's on your mind this time
yeah good talking to you I just wanted to get your
impression on my fucking sick move
let's pop in here
all right we're in
I love how there was an option to
become racist
that I could fail
but try again like
somehow I could go away
become more racist and then convince him that I
subscribed his ideology
what does it look like to fail racism
with someone that you'd assume would be
more than happy that someone was trying to be racist
oh he just you can deny it later that makes sense
okay let's check out our environment really quick
every worker a member of the board
what we got over here
we've got a postcard
probably sell that for some cash
see here coffee machine like the sound of that
on second glance
someone has forgotten to properly close one of the drawers
that's gotta be an Inland Empire thing
it's unfortunate for the union
to just leave the paperwork laying around like these
let's see what's inside he thinks
open the drawer
the drawer opens smoothly
inside is a well organized selection of brown folders
browse them
hundreds of documents containing logistical data
two kinds of transactions stand out
materials coming into Revachol from the outside world
from Muindi Grod and even ilmara
I like to think that shining the flashlight on them
makes me be able to read them better
and the same materials being handed over
to companies inside Rivershaw
Couron Coal City
LA Delta and Jamrock
are listed among the many districts
where the imports are being sold
it's hard to make sense of this thicket of company names
dates quantities and percentages
you try to focus but the lines are getting blurry
oh 83 percent
I mean I can't fail that right
every time I say that though I fail it
I'm definitely gonna succeed at this let's try that
look how blurry all the lines on these papers are
how unwieldy your own willpower is to yourself
you're like an absurdist Samuran monk
focusing through not focusing
it's unbelievable
it's actually unbelievable
I defeated racism
I defeat
this is such a weird playthrough
what the fuck
Raphael what's wrong with you
do I have a point still yeah
I do
what was that one for
I guess I should probably put something in volition
was that what I failed at yeah
I wasn't too far off
I spent all my luck
too high on nicotine to read
is that what you're doing with those folders over there
no of course not
my thought exactly officer shall we
okay should I put one in volition for other reasons
I mean I'm kind of like mainlining my psyche here
and I feel like I've messed up some volition checks
makes you hypersane when you're about to get funky
it keeps you normal
I do need some help keeping myself in check
I'm losing morale daily here
volition to balance out my crazy side
yeah I have to agree there
what other checks could I do that's a good question
oh one of these was with Kim
what was it
map information in complete
I thought I had a map
didn't I have a map earlier
the drawer slights shut smooth
what the fuck I thought I had a map
don't metagame that checks too hard
I mean
I still feel like
volition was is a worthwhile one to spec into here
I know you can get them from things as well
oh I just don't have a map of this area okay
to be a good guy to yourself
to others and yourself
I feel like that's important
for the healing of my character
the will to finish the investigation
well I need that my guy keeps getting sidetracked
okay we're gonna level this up I feel like it's
not something that I can really
it's not gonna
chat:所以你*确实*想要治疗？
I do want to heal I do
the whole game is gonna be about psychological healing for me
I feel like I can't lose if I before I
the file cabinet stands steady as ever
and the unlocked drawer slides out to greet you
92 percent that's a mighty success rate let's go
whatever's hidden here is hidden well
concentration isn't enough
only a trained accountant with a background in logistics
would be able to *really* make sense of it
however there *is* a little hand-written note
stuck on the side of the drawer
look at the note
it appears to be a to-do list
written in large uneven capital letters
remember Leo
*Everarts shoes
*special whirling borscht
*water Evrart's plants
*sweep office floor
*more banners
all items on the list have been crossed out
and the note itself is crumpled
let's get Kim involved
Evrart Claire probably the head of the Débardeurs' Union
one of his aids must have left it nothing incriminating here
what is so special about this *borscht*
code for drugs booze blood
let's take another look here
remember Leo
*Everarts shoes
*special whirling borscht
*water Evrart's plants
*sweep office floor
all items on the list have been crossed out
and the note itself is crumpled
hmm okay
the drawer slides shut smoothly
all right I'm not sure exactly what we learned from that but
I'm sure it will prove valuable
what do we got what do we got here
looks like someone left his tarpaulin cloak
hanging on the railing here
the white rectangle of the Revachol Citizens Militia
is clearly visible on its back
this is *your* cloak
what
you can feel it
let's ask Kim does he think it's my coat
yes it does bear RCM insignia
and we're the only detectives in Martinaise
maybe it has my badge in it Kim
the service cloak issued to you by your station
yes yes I do
as your fingers touch the tarpauling
oh fuck yes
it almost feels like the cloak wants to deliver
a message of comfort through your fingertips
yes
*I will shield you from the elements and give you my life for yours*
that's what the cloak is relaying
okay
fucking finally
shivers absolutely going for it
look at my dude
fucking
badass
okay what is it doing up here is my next question
this is a very cop like coat
right now the answer to good benefits is it's me
no I don't think I'm ready to look in the mirror just yet
all those empty wine bottles and cigarette butts on the ground
someone *partied* really really hard here
did I do this
well yes I think we can say with relative confidence that it was you
oh this is really sad I must have been miserable
see this is the kind of introspection
I have been looking for right
every new moment that gets me in touch with who I was
challenges my character
on do I want to integrate these things
because I have the strong sensation that
Raphael does not have very positive feelings
about the person he was before he woke up
and this is very much the experience
of people who I work with in addiction
where they're reflecting on like
who they were when they were in their addiction
they do not have positive feelings about who this person was
and so there is a strong urge to like
let's move on from them
but we neglect the idea that
there are valuable things left in who you were
that we can integrate with
the person you're trying to be right
it is not an all or nothing process like
integrating the past parts of your identity with your present one
it's way harder than saying let's just start clean
but it's a lot more impactful if you're able to do it right
it's impactful if you're able to sort out things like
the fact that someone who was selling narcotics
gain some valuable skills from this
is able to read and understand people very well
knows how to put pressure on someone
to the degree where they
you know get what they owed from them
but not doing so that they might
remove a repeating customer
were these used for good intentions no
but these are valuable like psychosocial skills
that are not worthy of abandonment right
and that's something I legitimately work on
with people in recovery all the time
which is we have to understand that
the qualities you have are not what made you a bad person
or made your decisions bad
it's the decision making that wasn't in your best interest
and that decision making was influenced by the addiction
and all kinds of other life pressures
and so here's what I imagine my character doing it's like
he doesn't want to integrate his past
I can sense that
like in the way that I haven't looked in the mirror yet
I know it's kind of odd that I haven't done that
but it's part of a role playing decision
and it's also like how I genuinely understand
people in recovery to experience this
because he's not ready he's not sure yet
if there are things about his past self
that are worth bringing forward right
that's kind of the struggle that he is in right now
and I think finding his coat finding his badge
starting to see the destruction that he left
both in his own life and just to his own body
are the early signs of like
is that person I was worth saving something from
or is it all bad
and that's some of the that's the line of questioning
I would probably go into therapy with with him
but yeah I think that
that's a question I often ask people in recovery
what is worthwhile about who you were that's
something you want to keep
let's go with some self reflection here
yes this scene isn't exactly ripping with joy
let's just move on
sympathetic I understand
Kim
wants me to avoid feeling sad but I do need this
I need this Kim I need to face who I was
or my healing to take place
this is the nightwatchman's booth
the name on the door reads *René Arnoux*
so this is where René works I'm gonna look around
if you must
but please hurry we are pretty easy to spot up here
equip the bag
oh I forgot I wasn't holding my bag
nothing incriminating catches your eye
the cabinets are clean
and their sparse contents meticulously organized
there's a framed photograph on the table
let's get that picture
it's a black and white photo of a young couple out in a street fair
the man René is dressed in a Royal Carabineer uniform
the girl is young and very pretty
she is smiling playfully at the camera
Renee looks like he's about to smile
this photo must be tied to some good memories
why did you take that picture of René
I'm gonna ask him about that
you're *really* interested in that old soldier
not sure I understand your fascination
but sure
as long as it doesn't take up a whole lot of time
oh
buddy everything we do takes up a lot of time
okay I totally forgot that I have to equip my bag here
I don't need to be holding my cigarettes at all times
even though it does make me feel comfortable
let's pick up these bottles
oh I can take all of them
I'm rich
I'm gonna be fucking wealthy
perfect
what about in the windows
all good can't do anything there
umm let's see here
let's go check out that door
okay I think that was all I could do up here
I think we might be a communist
also I'm gonna be fucking wealthy
hell yes we are
look wealth is how I gain
the influence to help the people
that's how we do it
an imposing combination of a punch clock
and a payphone is looking down at you from the wall
a note on the side says
tokens unavailable due to strike use change
I did just pick up some cash
the machine swallows your coin
and seems to be waiting for your next move
I've been here before huh
let's try it out
it's unclear whether you actually have muscle memory
right now your finger is just drawing
vaguely occult patterns in the air
god damn it
I might try this again
undoubtedly no
sure why not muscle memory is a tricky thing
nothing tricky about that
you just do fail repeat
until it works
all it takes is motivation and practice
okay I guess there were some stairs that I missed
are these ones okay
what do we got here
White Pine trees are printed onto the screen covering
looks like a forest under snow
what's this
a rusting control panel with several knobs
two buttons marked *Marche* and *Arret* are faded with use
it seems to control the large crane above
a container is attached to its hook block
marche on
arret of
rusting control panel with several knobs
two buttons marked *Marche*
sorry I was distracted by something
hello there this is editor Brady
my apologies for
interrupting your viewing of the episode
but I just wanted to
mention for those who didn't catch this stream live
around now in the play through
I started to like really lose a lot of focus because
I started to notice there was
a whole bunch of spam comments happening in the chat
and so my focus was kind of like all over the place
trying to like ban these people
um but the longer it went on
we started to realize that like
we were just getting like bot rated or something
there were just like hundreds of people
coming in and following all at once
and just spamming the same comments
so
there's a couple of times during this whole like
part at the docks that like I'm not
you know paying
the closest attention to what's happening
um and it actually did have to like
end the play through early because of it
so if you see me like
looking away from the game at important moments
uh that's why like
chat was just being totally overrun with these things
so my apologies for that
and uh yeah editor Brady out
container is trashed to its hook block
I mean let's turn it on
with a loud grind the crane shifts overhead
moving a massive metal container through the air
and with a surprisingly quiet thunk
the crane places the container down
this crane was built with a purpose
which has now been fulfilled
to move this container
what's inside the container
who can say all you know is it's special
I can't see how that was worth the ruckus
except for seeing the crane in action
which I admit was satisfying
okay
let's go inspect
some cash all right
oh and something that can heal me
thank goodness
so was this a container
before you stands a cargo container
just one of many in the yard
lieutenant
I think there's something special about this container
you do
because I don't
there are a million containers here
why are you fixing on this one
it was hanging from the crane
maybe there's contraband in there
there may very well be
but we are not here to look for that
we are not here to interact with containers
we are here to interview the union boss
well we did say that we would investigate the drug trade
we did say that Kim
you attempt to turn the handle to no avail
the doors seem to be mechanically locked
to your left the lieutenant considers your actions
with some puzzlement
no reply
let's persuade the door to open
3% I mean
what's the harm right
why are you even trying to open a door with rhetoric
because getting physical wasn't an option
now is not the time to get philosophical detective
you can do that after hours
okay
somehow we'll have to get this door open
but we won't be able to do it right now
can try this white once every day
I don't think we're gonna put any points into rhetoric
so
oh I've got some money here
I'm fucking rolling in cash right now
four real that's enough for two packs of cigarettes almost
oh I do have a crowbar yes
let's get the crowbar
fucking that door is coming open now
look I was able to knock out the racist
if I can't get this door open I am truly lost
let's go let's fucking go
I will bust this thing open
you're back before the cargo container
open it
you attempt to turn the handle
to no avail
to your left the lieutenant considers your actions
with some puzzlement
I can't open this with the crow
the package not the door okay
oh wait there's some money
why is there just a bunch of money hanging around out there
what we got
oh some gloves
okay so I can swap these for my interfacing ones
the union is rich
that's a good point
mechanically sealed shipping crates are stronger than a
pseudoscientific Übermensch
look I just figured that
if I could defeat racism with a punch
then I should be able to pry open those doors
wait there's a gentleman here
let's ask him what he thinks about the situation
container container I'll turn you nice and red
container container put the logos on
I've been having a lot of luck with my interactions
when I point the flashlight directly at them
I feel like it's sort of a power play
so I'm gonna keep doing that
the accent is so thick it's impossible not to notice
he's Ubi
from the vanishing Peninsula of Ubi Sunt?(sic)on Mundi
okay
container container used to be Wild Pines
container container now belongs to Evrart
Hello
Evrart Evrart Evrart he looks after everyone
well
hey there how can I help you mister
the look in his deep blue eyes
is as sincere as you've ever seen
kind of makes you feel like an asshole for no apparent reason
what did I say about social comparison right like
it makes complete sense that seeing someone so jovial
makes me immediately recognize
the contrast in my own mental health
I see you are not a union man Mister
did you get lost
you're not one of them scabs are you
I am not a scab no
what is it with you people
I mean I don't personally mind
folks are just folks you know and folks gotta eat
just some of the other guys
don't look too kindly on the scabbing kind
if you know what I mean Mister
you're Ubi right
Oh yes born and raised in Iraesh Mister
Mum had to leave my dad after he got a bit violent
took us here to the new new world
I was about 10 then too old to lose my accent then
people say us
Ubis are up to all sorts of
trouble with sheep and other animals and what not
I just want you to know
there was never any of that where I come from
no sir those are just nasty rumours
thank you for clarifying that sir
okay
where is everyone
oh most of the guys are down at the gates
keeping the scabs from coming in
we're on a strike
the whole union is
you don't have to work when you're on strike
we haven't worked for two months now
I guess it's good
no one is working
not everyone is down there of course
Mr Evtart is in his office where he always is
and Jean-Luc is guarding the gate
not anymore
but Titus and his boys got into some drunken trouble
and Eva sent him on a nice vacation
for a week or so
um one second
what kind of trouble did this Titus and his friends get into
to talk about that
that's union business
sorry I'm a little distracted
because there's a bunch of people spamming
a bunch of bullshit in chat
so I'm just trying to like clean them up
while I'm doing this
I'm not really supposed to talk about that
that's union vision
him and his boys stirred something up in town
probably drank too much and got into a fight or something
I heard Mr Evrart telling him to take some time off
don't go all bad cop on this simple friendly fellow
here's the thing
every time I see someone
who is in good mood
or approaches me with a very open posture
I'm immediately suspicious of them
it happened with the very
approachable lady in the wheelchair
however she immediately disarmed me with her
I guess like
simple admiration of me and her very honest reflections
guys mod team can we
ban all of these people
who are just spamming a bunch of bullshit
I'm trying to do some of them myself but
I'm suspicious because like
the natural conclusion
that most of the people who like I encounter in this world
have some sort of issue
they want something
what does he want
what does he want from me
I guess the boys got a bit too rowdy and had to let out some steam
I don't really know the details
that's just how boys are you know
I haven't been in a fight since I was in middle school
easy Leo let's keep this on the Hardies
too rowdy Leo what kind of a fight did they get into
did they kill a mercenary
too late Leo's mouth is still moving
and the words are sprewing forth
words words and look even more words
this guy could go on until the end of days
what's he seen though
now he's talking about some drunk Sawmill owner who
no he already
switched to a prized fishing rod
he apparently owned at some point
you know what
just cut in there with your questions
all right Leo what's up with the containers
oh I'm just making some covers for them containers here
yes I am yes I am
so it's easier for the crane operators to spot them
17 percent
I have not failed a 17 percenter yet
17 percent is 100% so far it has been in my book
everything is so pretty and red
you and Leo look like brothers
as you glance around with similar childlike wonder
okay I'm starting to recognize
that my early luck was very very limited
I'll just keep the amazement to yourself
and hums a jaunty to himself
okay
yes everybody needs a job and this is mine
I'm Leonard by the way
Leonard Bellec but everyone calls me Leo
oh my God
every every time I ban someone there's another one
fuck off
I'm like Mr Evrart's right hand man
when Mr Edgar is out of town
and Mr Edgar's right hand man when Mr Evrart is away
actually Ms Beaufort is the right hand man
but she's a lady
who is this Miss Beauforr
a real pretty lady
with a skin like those 'Doux & Sucre'
caddy bars my missus like so much
them are real nice to suckle on once the dinner is done
and me and the messes sit down
besides the radio
but I can't listen to the radio all the time
there's so much to do around here
and I'm always busy keeping things running here
yes I am yes I am
stay on this Miss Beaufort topic
who is this Miss Beaufort
oh Lizzie
she is a real sharp tool
Mr. Evrart put her through some fancy school and everything
east of the river
four years she was gone
and when she came back she was all fancy and loyerly
yeah I am only lucky with the important checks
it's a good point that like a lot of these like very simple ones
those are the ones I'm failing
but I'm not having any trouble with like the major
game defining ones
like shooting the guy down
but she's a real nice girl
grew up in this here neighborhood
knows everybody and gets along with everyone
real pillar of the community one day I'm sure
for a fraction of a second this sadness in his eyes
let's peel back the layers of Leo
if me missus and me was to have a child
I'd be real happy if she turned out like her
but she can't have kids
oh fuck Leo
and she knows about such things
being a doctor for almost 50 years she has
I think you're doing a great job around here Leo
this place really seems to run like clockwork
keep it up Leo
well thanks a lot coming from you it means a lot really
sometimes I feel
some of the guys don't really get
how much I bust my ass for them here
but you guys are all right
the white rectangle on your clothes
might not mean an awful lot in Martinaise
but the recognition from an authority figure
made Leo's day
oh look at that
see here's another point that like I said
sometimes people who are
really working through something difficult
especially like
the relationship with yourself kind of thing
they tend to overlook moments like this
where they actually do like
do something that they should be proud of right
I think that my guy would
find it very easy to minimize situations like this
where he would say well
it was only because Kim was there that
Leo felt good after we said that
oh it's only because I was wearing the coat
I think he would overlook and not necessarily assign
the fact that it was my dialogue with him and
the earnestness that we were having this conversation
that actually made this guy's day right
something about this interaction should tell Raphael
that like you have the capacity to be a good person
and empathy I'm glad chimed in to let us know that
but look I almost didn't succeed at that
these are the kinds of narratives that I would want my
character to focus on
are you the Leo who wrote the note to make more banners
oh yes yes I leave all kinds of notes for myself
that old head of mine
ain't so good at keeping things in no more
I almost forgot about the borscht
what was that about the borscht
oh yes
I've been taking special whirling borscht to the men
every day since the strike started
that's very very good
makes a man feel so warm and happy
I feel like I could take on Mr Renaudin's boardogs
every time the lunch is done
see measurehead okay
a little bit of Al Gul
is what is brightening up Leo's world
look how happy he is
power borscht
never heard of a borscht that turns little
guys into dogfighters
alcohol however
yes yes I'm taking it to them
the borscht keeps them happy and in Fighting spirits
makes you all warm inside
they brew it in the whirling in rags
wait hold up is it the guy in the
in the kitchen who I couldn't talk to
oh the whirlings cook
he makes it
It is
talking with Mr Manana in that weird language and laughing together
he doesn't speak what we speak he's from Graad
fuck okay Mr Manana is the guy we need to talk to then
looks like the borscht is spiking
oh sure master
sure you do that yes sir
what's in the container
oh that one that should be empty as far as I know
lots of containers here have nothing in them
they're just waiting to be loaded up
told you
Alright I'm looking for the leader
oh you want Mr Evrart then
he's an awfully nice fellow he is
him and his brother are both nice fellows
they've lived their entire lives in this here neighborhood
guys like Mr Evrart and Mr Edgar his brother
are real good guys
made Martinaise what it is today
Mr Evrart and Mr Edgar and I
went to the same school we did
when we were boys
patience
deep down you have the mental power to keep listening
not many would but you do
I'm glad I expected to volition for this
let's keep going
at an arithmetics teacher Miss Bellows
her real name was Miss Bellams
she was a real pretty lady but when she got mad
all the boys liked her if you know what I mean Mister
we used to sneak in her yard in the dark and
peek through the window
one time we saw Miss Bellows with a fellow
yes we did yes we did Mister
don't say anything
or no I should play into it
yes we did we did master indeed we did
Ham was a big big fellow
used to drive the Troyka near our'ses school and everything
them was all naked too
that's all I got to say about that
thank you for telling me the whole time
thank you eh
almost forgot
Mr Evrart is usually in that container over there
but he usually leaves around 10 PM
so you got to be quick if you want to catch him
wait he's in the container
lonesome long Way home
ah this was the thought there we go
home awaits
walk past station 41 and through the market
past the Boogie Street sparehead
to the other side of the lake
the frozen eye at the center of the district
then past the video rental store on the corner
there at the end of a street lined with pine trees
a small house no larger than a matchbox
11 Voyager Road
you no longer live there
those times are gone
and so are those people
why did you come here
why are you still here
and where's the dealer
you have to get back to work
that's all you have now
okay
some more insights into our past here
what did we get
our perceptions learning cap raise to 5
speed gives one to sigh
okay
so it seems like
we're actually looking for Mr Evrart in
the container
perception capterized
yeah the thing is is I don't have very
many points in perception anyways
Evrart it's to the left of Leo so he's over here
okay well I'm thinking of pausing here
one because
I can tell that my brain rot is developing
and also
this will make a good starting point for their next stream
yeah we're going to stop here
one because where chat is currently being overridden with bots
and I would like to cleanse all of them immediately
it's a little distracting and also
I've been streaming for almost 6 hours and this
this is where brainrot settles in and
I no longer have anything coherent to say
yeah I did say I was gonna stream disco for one hour
didn't I
well that didn't succeed
I've been streaming disco for almost three hours now
what can I say
it's a great fucking game and
I feel like this time we actually
made a decent little bit of progress in the narrative
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it consider giving it a like
and letting me know what you thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a little bit earlier
if you support the channel
either through Twitch or Patreon
links to both of those
and the community discord are in the description
thanks again and I will see you next time