hello
and welcome to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
on today's episode we are meeting what has become
another one of my absolute favorite characters that we've met so far
so we're gonna be talking a lot with Annette and her mother today
learning more about the economic reality
of being a child who has to work out in the cold all day
and in that dialogue we're also gonna be continuing to build our own character profile
sort of continuing the analysis using the JaharI window that we started in the last episode
there's a lot of emotions to dig into and discuss in today's episode
including some that may come up when we finally face ourselves
so that's where we're at I'm excited to continue so
let's jump back in
okay
what shall we do next
I guess we can go enter the green the door behind the greenhouse
let's go do that
it's in the yard basement door is that back there
yeah it's more useful in counseling
what's this girl up to it's been a while since we've checked in
every snowflake is like a little gift from the sky
she is way too positive
oh it's snowing
what is this crime business
crime fiction is about murders or burglaries or things like that
and the work of a policeman or a private detective
who's trying to solve a crime and catch the criminals
I need to know what *crime* is
it's that bad (point to your head)
crime is what we were solving before this conversation began
why would anyone want to *read* about crime
it's exciting to people I guess
they get to imagine dangerous things
and it's kind of like a puzzle where you can guess who the criminal is
or how the good guys are going to catch him
i'm a policeman myself by the way
you don't look much like a policeman
I know
well what does a cop look like then
didn't mean to offend sir sorry sir
it's just that you don't look like Dick Mullen
she points to a book cover on which you can see strapping Vespertine officer
he stands grimly over the body of a dead woman
you know nobody actually looks like the guy in the picture
it's not your body that's important in police work
it's your head
emm
i'll never be as good as him that's probably pretty accurate yeah
don't say that he's not even real you're real
am I
okay that's getting heavily existential Annette
and that's what I mean I'm gonna put that on the board
I'm gonna fucking put that on the board
that's my blind spot we're we're real
someone else sees this that that we don't get right
and this is part of identity
it does right what does this statement
like what does it mean for a statement like that
to suddenly become real to you as well like when you
because my character is like well I'll never be that good
i'll never be the ideal policeman
and she's like well that doesn't matter you're fine as you are
like don't try to live up to that
I think what
what's behind we are real is really like
and not everyone hates us
that is very often in our blind spot
hell it's often in my blind spot right
we tend to develop ideas that people hate us and
that everyone sees how fucked up our life is just like we do
but they don't right
part of my shame makes it impossible for me to see this sometimes
from the character's point of view
so like to learn about that
again makes me feel like I have to let this drive less of this
trying to use authority to to get people to listen to me
and that fits with what I just said right because like
what we're saying is I'll never be as good as him meaning
people will never respect me like they do this cop
like I'm not a good cop
it all comes back down to like is this true for me
maybe Annette just fucking gave us some little bit of therapy
made us a little more comfortable with our identity
yeah
and
maybe moved goodcop a little bit up into the blind spot like
something someone else sees that you know we're not understanding
so maybe we're gonna see a little bit of that motion
right
that's right a real failure
well it would be it would be pretty
oh yeah that's right Seachelle you're right
Lena and Annette
I forgot that the other character's name wasn't it
that's right a real failure yeah
that's how we feel
cheer up sir no need to compare yourself to a fictional character
it's too real it's too fucking real
maybe you can show me some *real* deductive police work sir
like in the books
okay I want to do that let's see
what is romance
it's a type of book where there's a rich lady
and she has to choose between the good man and the bad man
she imagines herself in that situation
or that could be a story about a poor lady getting a rich man
it's about man and lady business sir
what about
a book where the man and lady business doesn't work out
that feels pretty
that's on our mind right now
I haven't read many of those maybe should ask Mum
you think she has one about an *excruciatingly painful* breakup
I don't think it's a romance story if the main characters break up though
it can be
think about it one where they plunge into a torrid spiral of pain and recrimination
recrimination
only it's *really long* and drawn out
scarred for life phantom limb
ummm no I don't know
she's she's giving me Fritter girl vibes with um I don't know
you can take this blossom like a pain-flower
and it drags on for years and years with no resolution inside holy shit
the girl is at a loss for words
each of you filling with resentment and bitterness
for having *ruined* each other's lives
this poor girl
she shifts and sways on her feet
looking confused and uncomfortable
somehow this young girl has been totally like insulated
from whatever fucked up things
have influenced all the other kids in this world
and I am very curious about why
stop there's no need for this
it's in your power to change the subject
so I find what Volition does to us very interesting
so far volition
it's almost like the different voices have different tactics
for how to work on these problems right
like Volition wants us to not move anything out of this box
it wants us to
not enter this space because it is too painful right
there's so many scary things in the unknown right now
that it maybe doesn't feel like we're ready to face
or doesn't think are worthwhile to face
it's in our best interest that it doesn't want us to be heard of course
but I don't think that that's the goal
we actually do want to move things that way
Annette isn't really the appropriate person
hey Seachelle that's never stopped me before
on second thought this seems like an inappropriate topic to discuss with children
it's gonna hurt me if I don't stop isn't it
I think we've gone far enough with this one
this is a little too intense
poor girl
um what about when everyone is poor
that's really not a proper romance story
that's more like everyday life
god damn okay so she is aware of reality as well
the economic reality as Frittte girl would say
I bet she I bet she's had her own little chapter of wandering into Frittte and
getting a bit of a lowdown on the economic reality from
from best girl
sometimes you gotta real right about real life things
not in romance books sir
these are about nice and pretty people
and everyone is happy in the end
what about when both of the men are bad
these are not very common
you can't have a choice between bad and bad
nobody wants to read a story like that
true
what if it's written really well
well maybe then it's fine
maybe if the lady then decides not to pick either
because she doesn't need a bad man
yes that would be interesting
what about a poor man getting a rich lady
it happens
but usually the guy gets rich in the process or should actually be rich himself
but has lost his family property unjustly
like during the revolution or something
I see
those are unhappy books for most of the pages
people sad about what they have lost
but then it all turns out just fine in the end
just like I'm sure this story will
that's enough romance for me
maybe some about other books
yes let's ask about famous people
kings and queens and generals of old
or artists and writers or musicians
those kinds of people
there's usually something extraordinary about them
I discovered you through your disco playthrough
and just want to let you know your video and volition
helped me not spiral into my destructive habits
after I slept in past an appointment today
hey that's that I appreciate that
I am always enthusiastically surprised when
people actually see those patterns in their real life
and do something about it
that's awesome thank you for sharing
I think that's why people read them to find the secrets of their fame
can I be famous
I don't know about that
but I imagine life is great when you're famous
they're all dorks
they sound like dorks
fame sounds delicious
maybe someday someone will write a book about me one day well
we're not too happy about ourselves right now
let's yeah let's this is called a sour grapes
it's coping skill or not coping skill
defense mechanism eco defense mechanism
it comes from the asap fable I think it is
where the fox is in the forest
and he sees some grapes that he wants
but there is a thorn bush between him and the grapes
and he can't get them and so he convinces himself that
I didn't want those grapes anyways
sort of like
the famous people suck anyways why would I want to be them
and its expression remains ever so helpful
but she doesn't say anything
never mind I literally had nothing else to say
okay
okay let's do some detective work for Annette
okay guys throw me some of your best lucky tomatoes okay
look we have not done very many good things in this playthrough yet
we're trying we're becoming a sorry cop
we're making up for our past
we're trying to solve the murder
but and we're making up with Cuno
we're gonna find lena's husband
we're gonna do it all okay we're gonna do all the good things
one of the most important things we can do right now though
is like make Annette smile
she's had a long day standing out here in the cold
thinking about the economic reality that she's in
and transporting herself to fictional worlds
where the outcome is always good
because that's the only way to escape from real life
where the outcome is always bad all right
she loves cops she loves crime
she loves the mythological archetype of human experience that it represents
detection
uncovering secrets
finding resolution
making the world right again
providing structure where there is chaos okay
she's a philosopher she's a queen
all we have to do is make her smile
all we have to do is validate that
her time spends enjoying the fictional reality
means that the emotion she has in reality are
just as real as those ones in those books
let's do it
let's roll the dice
let's roll the fuckin dice baby
you fail to deduce anything substantial
fuck
god damn it
i'm sorry Annette I'm sorry I'm a sorry cop
I'm so sorry
I'm such a broken man I have I can't even
I can't even use my detective work to
brighten up this poor girl's life for a moment
she waits intensely
I actually I can't deduce anything
no I can't look I
and that's whole structure for viewing the world
is that there's good cops out there
maybe that's it
maybe her entire thing is that the reason she's not so depressed
is because she sees people like fucking what's his name mullin
and she sees me and Kim walking around and she's like
oh well I know the world sucks but like I'm safe because they're here
and they must be good cops and they must be doing good things
and here I am standing in front of her and I can't  I can't I can't even tell her that
she's
I can't tell her anything interesting
I can deduce that you are very small
no that's not a good one
I just I can't deduce anything
it's okay sir
no it's not
a small disappointment rolls over her but she promptly gets over it
it is a massive disappointment for me
you disappointed a small child well done champ
no
why is this world so cruel to me
do I have any skill points to waste on this
I
what is it composure
this composure do I have any clothes that I can wear
I have two
is it is it worth using a skill point
yeah I mean it is right it has to be
I I like
I cannot let Annette down like this
okay
72 percent
we've got this
all right lucky tomatoes in the chat
roll the dice
we are we are so close to shattering this poor girl's worldview
okay
we have to be the cop that she is dreaming of
the one that provides structure to the world
who doesn't just apologize
but can solve the case of what's going wrong in her little world
Kim back me up
do I have to uh oh
hello again sir
okay
do I have any do I have any clothes that give me composure
conceptualization no no no
interfacing
uh
useless it's all a bunch of useless garbage
okay 72 percent chance this is an easy one right
I shouldn't say that I should never say that
it's always a predictor that it's gonna fail
any close lowering my composure that is a good question
got plus one to composure from the green snake skinned shoes
and that's gonna find that very impressive
reaction speed is okay
okay nothing nothing is interrupting us here
the faster I click it the faster it goes okay
the girl keeps her hands folded hidden why is that
yes yeah
this is this is healing
this is healing time why do you keep your hands folded
what do you mean sir
she knows where this is going
you don't need to be worried I'm here to help
awww
what's what's I think our character genuinely believes that
I think maybe for the one of the first times
we can categorically say that this is like our true real intention for someone
because all of the other things
solving the murder we still don't know exactly why we are doing that
are we doing it to impress Kim are we doing it to make up for something
are we doing it because we think it is right
do we even have a grounding on what is right or wrong
the thing with Cuno we're just so ashamed of what we try to do
that we're trying to reconcile it
there's so much confusion behind every decision that we've made
and this is one of the first times that I feel like we genuinely believe
this this is real healing
you don't need to be worried I'm here to help
she looks around anxiously her hands remain folded in front of her
she doesn't want to show them
the lieutenant stands by looking at the two of you with little interest
kim mate you are not interested in any of the things
that are directly impacting my healing
a facade of true professionalism
he is far more intrigued by the situation than his poise reveals there
there goes my failure to detect kim's stone cold facade
you heard me hands up no
it's okay
she brings out her reddened hands
her nails frayed nearly chewed down to the flesh
oh my god
you bite your nails
and you knew this for me keeping my hands folded
yes
well that proves nothing anyone could do an easy deduction like that
she actually is impressed this is more like a defensive reflex
want more bet I can figure out *why* you bite your nails
she nods half provocative half enthusiastic
hmm rats have been nibbling on your fingers
child labor is dismal in dismal working conditions
you're uptight because of your mother and the pressure she's putting on you
that seems kind of realistic
recycling your body material
I don't think so
there's no riches without personal sacrifice hm
this is probably the most realistic one I guess
maybe so sir okay I know it's a bad habit and I shouldn't
either way another *ace* detection by the number one detective in town
I mean she's she's in she's entertained by this right
it was okay sir
more that can be achieved here ask her to do the same
whatever kid I don't need to prove myself to you no that's not us right now
you think so fine do better to do something about me
we're playing around here
you're quite sober
what
that's a very strong observation
like like you don't just say that to people right like imagine
imagine you are meeting your friend in the park or whatever
and you walk up to them and they're like hey how's it going
and you're like oh you're quite sober
like you wouldn't just say that with no context
so she can deduce that sobriety is a
limited state for us
yeah there's some implications there
what she's probably interacted with us before yeah is a power move
I wonder what authority is gonna say about that
the lieutenant does not flinch at the comment
he does not flinch even a single bit
he is intensely not flinching it takes out effort
how do you know I'm usually not
because you usually aren't
how would you know
i'm also sad and my head hurts
i'm sorry sir I hope things get better soon
gleam of sympathy on her face
there she stands swaying on her feet
assaulted by the early spring breeze
she smiles at you
the whole situation suddenly feels familiar somehow
we have definitely interacted with her before
so
one of the things that I find interesting about this is
who is actually moving these things for us right because
when our identity was revealed to us
in a situation where there was manipulation
for example with Evrart Claier
there was confusion and anxiety and
probably more of this and more of this right
when our identity is revealed to us by someone who is trustworthy
or who we do not feel as manipulative of us like for example
maybe someone who is allowing us to feel more like a good cop like Annette or Lena
suddenly the disclosure of our past identity
does not bring up so much of these things right
and I no longer feel the need to
be protective of myself  by being an authoritative person
so this is also showing us what kinds of things that we respond to right
the kinds of people who are in possession of
what we don't know about ourselves
what are you missing here why does this feel familiar
please let me succeed
you have absolutely no idea familiar how
come on
you must have forgotten something you heard again
seventy two percent
my luck is so all over the fucking place
it's easy to forget the Ledger
yeah I could I'm gonna go back to the ledger at some point
this was on suggestion
yeah we didn't do any lucky tomatoes it's true
do I have something that's impacting my suggestion
no
I have something that could make it worse oh
and something that could make it better
see if that does anything
hI ace detective are you here for more books
ah shit
this is essential I need to learn this
yeah let's do it
let's do it we have to know
hI ace detective
I am the ace detective 92 percent no tomatoes required
because you know each other
she's been talking to you so openly
because you've talked before
I knew it I knew it
you know me we've met before
yes I stand in this spot all the time
you've been running around all week without your shirt on sir
apologizing to everyone
don't really understand what you've done wrong
that checks out
did I ever talk to you
of course you've stopped by a few times
you suddenly look better than the last time I saw you
what do you mean better I look like shit
yeah but you don't have party eyes anymore
party eyes yes of course
that makes sense
i'm not surprised children have seen you running around with party eyes on
he thinks not at all
*party eyes*
you know like a cat in the dark or big and wide eyed
it certainly looks odd on a man
the swiveling eyes of a Looney drug addict
that is what she meant
you were probably good into
fuck yeah you should get some party eyes right now
snap those sequins on you boy
does that mean I've been partaking in narcotics
oh baby that's not what you have to worry about
worry about the important thing
so why didn't you tell me you knew me to begin with
what are you protecting about me
I didn't know I had to do that
hmm thanks I've learned something about myself today
i'm glad I could help you sir
so what have we just seen happen right
something else in our blind spot is
there are two things that I just learned here
actually a couple of things
one of the things that we did not know is how bad we were
we did not exactly know
like we knew that we were destructive and chaotic
and that we had things to apologize for
but the more we learn about this the more we start to understand
how bad it actually was right
the fact that a child like Annette
someone with a very unique world view in the place that she's in
was able to see this and deliver it to us again
it very much matters who the person delivering this information to us is
at the same time we're learning how bad we were
it did not seem to change Annette's perception of us
she's the one who told us we're real
and this discovery that not everyone hates us
even though we were really bad
because down here was like
this was one of the ideas is that like
we were
we are
a complete failure
that is one of the central ideas behind that dream sequence right
we are a complete failure
billions of people in the world you failed every single one of them
what's fascinating to me is that
this is something that we suddenly intuitively know about ourselves
through the dream sequence through the way we just feel
this is one of those core beliefs that I was talking about
that we just feel we don't always necessarily have a reason to
like where it came from
sometimes it's maladaptive
but what just happened
somehow someone told us that this is how bad we were
and it still didn't change their perspective of us
like it's not like the second Annette saw us she went running
she was not terrified of our real identity
nor did she think we were a worst cop just because we couldn't remember
and so something very important happening
again this is why I tend to use this in therapy
is this idea might have just moved this way
and the question
may become something like this right
are we actually a complete failure
and can we through some process of self discovery and healing
find a way to see ourselves not as a failure at all
I think that one of the big things
for people struggling with failure is that we tend to go to the extreme
failure is the experience of losing something so completely that it feels total
but something our character may be discovering is that
failure is kind of like a gradient right
it is uh
not necessarily something that has
only two ways of feeling about it right
like failure in this context can very much be
a gradient between like complete failure and failing in some things
and so actually
this is a good motion for something that we feel like
we intuitively knew about ourselves to suddenly become in question
what does that tell you
it tells you that
some of your core beliefs may not be as fixed as you might believe
if this one may not be totally true
maybe some of the others aren't
maybe some of my other core beliefs
that I am incompatible in a relationship
that I am a bad person that I am
untrustworthy manipulatable unable to solve this case right
when there is a foundational belief like this that suddenly comes in question
many of your other foundational beliefs
maybe worth more investigation
and that's something that like we just
earned through our little dialogue with Annette
like the children of this game are the real therapists
like she's unpeeled me
I've been unpeeled
it unzipped
my soft gooey internals have been exposed in this winter hellscape
and it makes me feel warm and welcomed
Cuno just wait till we get to Cuno
children will just call out what they see
while adults have ulterior motives totally
you can stop calling me sir I am but a working man
no  sir I can't
it would be too tiring to refrain from it
it's already tiring enough to remember to say it all the time
it's nice if you'd say I could stop though
okay yeah when the next person comes you'd have to sir or mam them again
sir it is then soldier on
by your command
I love you
you've you've saved
you've dislodged something in my brain
that will become essential for my future healing journey
thank you little wanderer
you see a sturdy woman humming to herself
she seems to be browsing books
hello
and she literally made me improve my composure and suggestion
that is true
that is very true
she's like literally healed us
and I also got some of my what was it morale back something
and I didn't even need to down some magnesium
no ceremonies just hello
who are you
no one i'm just a working class woman
she doesn't really want to be disturbed that much
what are you doing
looking for something to read
good good
it is
I'm a policeman
I know you are
do you need the help of a policeman
what with
this citizen thinks she can do without your assistance don't buy it
they all need help
interesting comment from authority here
let's just observe
her hands move over the book covers
the tips of her fingers look rough stained with yellow
it seems like she has spent a lot of time at work smoking
an array of neurons fire up with joy
bum her a cigarette lest it turned to pain
uh yeah
maybe we can build some rapport
do you smoke
no I don't
what I know for a fact that you smoke
why do you think that I smoke
your hands look like they belong to a heavy smoker
it's not like yours look much better
that's because I smoke
take a look at your hands
she is right
your hands look even worse than hers
with tiny cuts and gushes covering your skin like a spider web
your fingertips have become an ugly shade of brown
just give me a cigarette please
I already told you I don't have any go bother someone else
she's lying she's god damn lying she has smokes
what should I do here
I feel like we're not at the point
where we're like demanding them anymore
but we probably would ask
I mean we already have a pack of cigarettes
don't listen to half-light
yeah I'm trying not to listen to it
I'm trying to think what my character would do though
well right now
like the priority is getting people not to hate us
so we're gonna move on
she sighs
maybe her husband's missing
my husband no he's not
why did we ask this
I don't know
so where could he be
I don't know at home now
out drinking with his friends working
where is this going officer
so what I'm hearing is you don't really know where your husband
or just
she gives you a short nod and shifts her attention back to books
maybe your children are missing
no absolutely not
okay so where are they
are you a policeman or a nanny
nanny where are they
thet're not missing sir
you know where they are they're at home smoking
given the ladder of vices a chance
what
what if something horrible has happened
what if they're dead
that's the bad vibe you got before
oh no
what if what if
they're at home smoking cigarettes
such an odd way to confront someone
what if they're in the sewers
I mean sure
what that's just
my daughters are perfectly fine
they're with their friends down in Jamrock
there's nothing to worry about
they are almost grown up now anyway
their past the age they need me protecting them from everything now
i'm afraid that danger is now greater than ever
tell me how old are they
why did they give you the option for this
okay
I don't think well
let's just ask about the Cockatoo
I don't mean to disrespect sir
but you are being a bit of a cockatoo here
for what it's worth I agree
but cockatoos can't be stopped when they get like this
it's better to indulge him at this point
there's Kim having some fun
I was asking about your
ma'am I was asking about your cockatoo is it missing
I don't even have a cockatoo and guess what
what
even if I had
it wouldn't be missing
all right cockatoo not missing I just wanted to make sure great
just one more question what did you mean by me being a cockatoo
go read up on them if you're so interested
there's a great book in the bookstore
maybe you should watch
if the cockatoo is your astral captain or your heraldic bird
actually that's exactly what I'm going to do
we get a quest from this
no way
the story is open
I love this
I love this game
the woman before you nods and returns to her reading
I guess I can I can go read up on birds now
maybe I'll have something to talk about with Lena
oh this is Annette's mom
oh no
oh no this this
she's a clerk
okay
I will try to restrain myself
welcome to crime romance and biographies of famous people
my name is Plaisance
be welcome and please
take responsibility for the energy you bring into this space
okay
a golden pendant hangs around the woman's neck
in the shape of what looks like a tiny fish head trapped in amber
hmm a curious pendant you're wearing
oh yes
helps to have an anchor in these times
I could just ask her for money
I mean her business seems to be doing pretty well and we do need money sir
sir don't be ridiculous I certainly will not give you money
I would be doing you a grave psychic disfavor
one has to earn one's success
even if one is a police officer
handouts are nothing but manipulation
all they do is make you dependent
so who are you talking to
because like I handout to another adult I can understand
but is is is like your daughter
having like basic needs met a handout in your perspective
what is this insolence
she misunderstood
no that's not me
of course no one puts words in your mouth
so are you the owner of this store
I am the proudest owner of our little shop of culture
she has fine tuned her voice
to find the most welcoming approach for attracting new customers
it doesn't work
your daughter is the one standing outside the store right
Annette yes
my daughter
I hope she wasn't slacking off again with her nose in science fiction
tell me was she at her post doing her job like a proper girl
oh this is fucking this stuff pisses me off so much
no she was definitely
right
yes of course
I always thought that said
no she definitely was not slacking off
was she at her post yes of course
wonderful did you talk to her
yes
great on a scale of one to ten how compelled
were you to buy books after talking with her
so is that all she is to you
she's a little saleswoman
her opinion of her daughter
depends on how well she lured you into the store
oh my god
this fucking grates at me so much
she's the algorithm
ten she's very polite and helpful
my precious
her dedication brings joy to my heart
if you have children
I hope they turn out as great as my Annette
now look i'm not gonna assume I'm not gonna jump into
head canon that she's a terrible parent by any means
but
I just find this perspective very
troubling
is it in my place to start commenting on her parenting though
here's what I'm thinking okay
at the end of the day
Plaisance is counting her money
from the amount of books that she has sold
and the first question that she has for Annette is what right
how many books did you sell
or maybe she gives her feedback
we didn't sell so many books today
why don't you think more people came into the store
were you smiling at them like I told you
were you very polite right
this is kind of dialogue I'm like imagining happening
here you have this poor young girl who
has has such a keen eye for the human condition
that she was able to peel me open like a fucking banana
and yet I imagine there's not a lot of like
I don't know like what does Annette want to do with her life
what is she interested in well
she's definitely interested in like reading books and talking about them
I don't think that she hates her job but
it does seem like she's nervous about like
what happens when when things aren't when it's not a good day
what happens when you know no one comes into the store
like I'm not I'm not convinced that Plaisance is sitting there
thinking like oh well
that's my fault
it's probably like oh well it's you know Annette didn't do her job or something
this sounds pretty appropriate to say
out on the damned cold as well
I get she's a trooper all right she looks like she can take it
but it's actually wearing her down
you know she's been biting her nail
god ugh I've told her not to do that it's such a disgusting habit
she'll get over it anxiety is a part of life
that's my fucking problem okay
no no it
anxiety is a part of life but not like this okay
little
like discussion on anxiety briefly
like anxiety has a function an emotional function
when someone comes in and says like I have anxiety
I'm not immediately like thinking
that they have a generalized anxiety disorder
anxiety is your body's alarm bell
like to tell you to pay attention to something right
there is an amount of anxiety that's appropriate for you
if I was standing out in the cold all day
and I was worried about losing my job
I would experience anxiety
if I just went through a breakup
none of these are classified as a disorder
when it becomes a disorder is
when you're feeling anxious when you shouldn't
when there is not a clear link between
a source of anxiety and you feeling it temporarily
so like
while she's standing out there working
sure maybe she feels anxious
but if she's going up into her room and it's quiet
and she's sitting alone in her bed at night
and there is nothing that should be making her anxious
and that's when she's biting her nails
now we have a problem right
now the anxiety is starting to infect parts of her life
where it is not appropriate
it's extremely sad that her mom doesn't seem to recognize this
she'll get over it anxiety is a part of life yeah well
what that tells me is
that someone didn't teach you how to deal with anxiety
and you think that the way you are like that
you're just calling stubbornness resilience
and you think that the only way to get through it is just to endure it
rather than actually like
I don't know providing her with like a better way
a part of hers too clearly
yeah
I don't think she can do anything about it
she can if she has enough willpower
this is what's called growing pains
life isn't easy life doesn't give breaks
okay now I fucking hate her okay
yeah no this is bad mom territory
willpower alone is not enough to change a negative behavioral pattern
I've already broken that down with the whole competing mental states thing
that motivation is a very linear way to describe action potential
and it's very limited and
like oh well have you tried not being sad idiot like
that's how this sounds the way she's talking about this
come on ma'am it's obvious she can't do anything about it
you are placing an unnecessary burden on a young child
what you're doing is wrong even I know that
and I usually don't know anything
here is another amazing point in our characters narrative right
like this time it is again someone else that we're interacting with
once more I feel like this right here this line of dialog
what you're doing is wrong even I know that
and I usually don't know anything
is compelling us to question like
maybe we're not a complete failure as a person right
my view of myself is suddenly less and less of a mystery
because I'm able to tell that
even though I'm a fucking idiot
and I make lots of bad decisions
even I can tell that this is not appropriate for a child
and if I can accept that
I can't be a complete failure right
I love this I am loving this
and and we are very unashamed as well about saying that as well
that's perfect
she stands stiff and severe silently fuming
ten or so seconds pass without change
this is the second boss fight of the game
this is a person coming to terms with a new reality
one where they are wrong
it's not easy
no it isn't no
it isn't cause that's what's happening to me all the time
oh no
hold on I need to invite her inside and apologise
she must be freezing out there
somehow this feels uh ingenuine
there I don't know what to say to you
my husband he tries to teach me business lessons
I have what my mother called a dull mind
all this stress
wait a second did that actually work
did that actually work
Annette healed us
and we were able to heal her and her mom
it sounds like both the husband and the mother
treat her the way she treats Annette
what
you're like Annette to your husband and your mother
this is like this is like a fucking Raphael
look I know he's Harry
Harry's the cop Raphael was the original fake persona
this is the therapist this is the therapist coming out
get him
you're like annette to your husband and your mother
oh well my mother was horrible of course
absolutely perverse energies around that person
but my husband
my husband is completely different of course
okay I'm we're peeling back here
this is a generational issue of course
good on her you know
I said I said bad mom territory before
but anyone who's willing to you know
make mistakes and known up to them like that's growth
that's character development right there
she's she's not a terrible mom she's a troubled human
is this husband and Annette's father
yes my husband is a successful entrepreneur east of the river
if only he were more involved in the business we're running up here
no matter
soon we'll both be off for Grand Couron
Grand Couron what is that
it's a proper place to live
one of the most peaceful neighborhoods east of Jamrock
you may know it for its massive housing projects
most of the buildings are empty at the moment
it's a great opportunity to get ahead of the crowds
better times ahead for sure
and your husband's also involved (with the bookshop)
he made the initial investment
since then he's been what you might call silent partner
wow okay
so here's the dynamic as well right like
husband made the investment
she is left to uphold the household essentially
but doing so alone probably provokes a lot of anxiety for her as well
she's probably internalized a lot of
like the same kinds of critiques her mother gave her
which are falling down on Annette as well
is she an only child where are her friends
yes I'm afraid so
a real treat she is
it would be nice if she had
no we couldn't have afforded more children really
not in this economy
true
very true also in real life
plenty of my friends have kids
and I'm gonna be honest sounds miserable in this economy
a glimmer of sadness blinks through the world crafted exterior
I look I came in hot on this one but
the poor clerk
it's always a clerk sad clerk
I want to help her now
where is your husband
where is he let me go talk to him
tell him to come home and be here for his family
of course yes this economy
she told me she doesn't go to school anymore
she's been too busy helping me here
so she studied at home this trimester
this is a temporary solution of course
ah and she
she doesn't get to go to school this is heartbreaking
okay I really want to do
a family session with all of them
it's so sad
I assure you
I of all people understand the importance of education
she will be back in school the moment the store takes off
and when is that going to happen
okay had something else in mind
the woman looks aloof
her features much softer
occasionally she glances at her daughter's silhouette
ah you can tell that she
she probably really does know what she's doing to her daughter
but
her daughter is a very good person and is very agreeable
and so doesn't show very openly the toll it takes on her
I know this is all super emotional and stuff
but where are the books on cockatoos
a book about cockatoos
there should be one upstairs
right next to the shelf of biographies
what if I want to buy
then why are you talking to me
everything is on the shelves to browse
don't you feel compelled to buy anything
see those shelves there go be drawn
What types of books do you have
everything is on the shelves take a look yourself
the shelves compel you don't they
she's attempted to mentally direct you towards the shelves
she only wants  you to buy the goods
she doesn't care about the books
do you even know what books you have for sale
truth be told  not really
my sister brings in most of the goods
I'm sure it's all very literary stuff with well written prose
but you don't learn about the important things in life from fabricated stories
wrong that's wrong
I have learned lots of important things about life  from this fabricated story
I've undergone more personal change in the 10
or so episodes of this series that I have made
in the last couple of weeks
than I have gotten from just real life things happening to me
like most of my recent character development in real life
is a direct result of playing this video game
less something that really happened to me
which is probably characteristic of lots of my life to be honest
where do you learn about important things
truth is available if you just know where to look
the truth is available if you just know where to look
and you have to open and free your mind to understand
okay I sympathize with you lady
but I find your personality also very grating
she smiles and nods seemingly relieved
farewell for now book peddler okay
let's get in that opinion on this
I'm sorry sir
I can't talk right now
i'm very busy with my homework
I have so much homework now
i'm very busy with my homework I have so much homework now
you just can't win
no for a nuts
what are you doing
maths it's really difficult like really
they say you need it to get rich
better than standing outside in the cold I guess
oh oh I found something while you were away
I thought this would fit you
like thanks for helping out not me the city I mean
like a detective does
she gives you a hat
almost exactly like one Dick Mullen wears on the covers
oh my gosh
where did you get
just what Dick Mullen would ask
I got it from behind the curtains
I'm not really supposed to go there
it's of a fedora
may be it's the hat Dick Mullen wears all the time
you look way more serious with that
right  I have to get back to my homework now before mum notices
man  this is hard
can I spend can I stop doing the murder thing
and just spend time with her and Frittte girl and Cuno
oh my god it really is cool
if anything this wide
rimmed hat looks even better than the hat Dick Mullen wears
Dick Mullen is stupid and not even real
you're real your brain is real
your real brain is inside the hat
and it's good for my encyclopedia it's ooh
that my bum hat was pretty good for my reaction speed though
trade it out oh fuck Yeah
put our duster back on as well now we look fucking cool
how helping kids how would that prevent crime
well it would probably prevent future crime
so we've just gone on a crazy little adventure this
I know that we haven't really done anything in the game
but psychologically a lot of things have happened
like what does this mean
what does this mean for our character to be recognized like this
that someone can actually idolize us even right
I think that
there's a part of us that's starting to understand a little more clearly like
what people think about us
this was a very eye opening experience
to see what kim's reaction and the mother's reaction
and Annette's reaction to us was
I think what we learned is that we actually have some convictions
right we actually do have some firmly held beliefs
that dictate some of our behavior
and we can notice that there is a link between like
it doesn't matter that we lack intelligence
our convictions are still
the same
hey good night seachelle thanks for stepping by
we've learned that we have some convictions right that
we care about microeconomics and the sad state of all clerk shop owners
and there is a direct link I think between
clarifying what our convictions are
this is another protective factor against shame right
the more convictions we invest in
the more we explore things
like I do care about  the emotional wellbeing of children
I do care about them being able to have the opportunity to go to school to learn
to have their family around
these are things I do not need to feel any sort of shame in
and the more I expressed those convictions
the more I was respected
so I would say that like respect
we were unsure about whether
we were respected by other people
and there is a link between conviction and respect
the more we live  a moral life
the more we show people that
we don't abuse our power
that we don't need to use authority
like we didn't need to yell at the mother
we just needed to empathize with her a little bit
not only did she open up to us
which makes us feel good about the kind of like police work we can do
but it also earns some respect from her and Kim and ourselves
our view of ourselves is changing more and more right
I think that this is trading places in some ways
getting interesting
there's a lot going on here right like and
I did this once before I don't think I'm gonna do it now
but there was a time where
I had it in mind to actually do two of these
like because Harry's life is also a mystery to himself
like his past life is an unknown right
so we could technically like go a layer deeper and say like well
the more we learn about him
what are the aspects of his life
that are starting to come into his awareness here right
like for example
the breakdown of his relationship
which he may have been in his blind spot right
is now becoming something he knows privately in his current life
and what is the intersection of that
so maybe we return to this at some point and
maybe we do another johari window later in the game
herry saying those things
because he knows that's what people say to be respected
or because he actually believes in those things
I think at this point
it's an actual belief
okay let's check out those cockatoo books
ohh what's right in this curtain
you see a set of tattered curtains blocking the way to another room
a strange cage-like trinket dangles from the curtains
excuse me officer
the back room is strictly for employees only
I'm doing police work
shopkeeper what's behind the curtains
why aren't you browsing the books
don't you feel *compelled* to look at the books
something shady's going around
the more she tries to draw you away from the curtains
the more alluring they become
examine
you see some kind of charm
an irregular polyhedron
assembled from bones sticks and straw
inside a disturbing fish-head
with empty eye sockets stares at you
that is curious
aside from poking at it suspiciously
there is nothing else to do with the fish-head charm at this time
the curtains remain shut before you
maybe we can sneak them open
I don't just want to like thrust them open
（选项）暂时不管那个窗帘
we've just earned her trust
lets check out that book
so they put a cockatoo mission in here just for kicks
turning into the middle of the streams
and seeing the diagrams and little red strings connecting everything is wild yeah
like I said long time viewers this is like
this is a pretty tame johari window actually
compared to like some of the other ones that I've done
but we also were working with very little right now
which is that we still don't know a lot about Harry
whereas like some of the other Johari windows
I've done into like 10 episodes of the show
these shelves are overburdened with books from the same series
you see the name Dick Mullen over and over
shopkeeper what's all this crime fiction
oh crime robberies murders
even *sexual* crimes
we're fortunate to have Dick Mullen and his stories to sort all that out
you're a police officer apparently
you should buy *all* of these
they really do teach a person how to be a proper detective
maybe I should actually do that let's look through
crime fiction is a disgrace
an asinine misrepresentation of the physical attributes
of the arduous everyday work of actual police officers
these books *greatly* overstate the excitement of police work
glossing over how long it takes
to actually follow up on leads and eliminate dead ends
I don't know it's been pretty exciting
furthermore they have NO IDEA
how hard it is to simply remove a body from a tree
let's be real that part was super fucking easy
because I just shot the motherfucker down first try
what's more they completely ignore
the psychological hardships of year after year
coming into contact with people during the worst days of their lives
not a single mention of all the stress this work creates upon the officer's *family*
detective fiction just doesn't tell the truth at all
now would you like a list of the books found on the shelf
where is this coming from this is odd to me
like this doesn't have a voice
whose opinion is this
at of all the dialogue options in the game
this is like just very
a blunt
it's interesting
I mean it just seems like commentary
like more so than anything my character would into it
you see Dick Mullen on the Job
Get Me Mullen
The Stalwart Adventures of Richard P. Mullen
Dick Mullen and the Murder in the Orchard
The Sordid Affair of Dick Mullen
it's an objective opinion
A Killing Is Declared Dick Mullen in the Murderhouse
The Final Case of Dick Mullen an obvious lie
Dick Mullen in the Clock Tower
The Ordeals of Dick Mullen
Dauntless Dick
Dick Mullen's Funeral Pyre
The Murder of Dick Mullen
he probably doesn't die
哦 不是的
turns out he faked it to solve a case
of course
yes
there's also The Dame Who Did It
Farewell My Mullen
faking death seems to be a common trope in the Mullen series
The Morbid Tales of Dick Mullen
A Dark Tide Turns
Tragedy Calls for Dick Mullen another one with fake death
and of course
Dick Mullen The Murderer
in order to catch a murderer
dick mullen must *become* the murderer
that's got to be some kind of foreshadowing here right
come on this is *not* the way real police solve crimes
the *real* police are some twenty kilometres away
sitting in an armoured motor carriage
come on Chester
tell the story again
what again man I tell that one at least once a month
it's not that interesting
the *fuck* it is and these guys haven't heard it
这段对话是从哪来的
you see Chester here
gosh why
one civilian looks on amazed the bald man reply
a very fucking dangerous case ain't that right Chester
they almost got you that time
yeah sure came close
all right so I was tailing this guy called Francis the Shoe
the inside of the motor carriage is thick with cigarette smoke
outside it starts to rain
after all of this you still haven't found the answer to the one question that matters
who *is* Dick Mullen
who is he react
your attempt to grasp at the answer fails
妈的
it seems very close by
pulsating just out of reach
whatever we don't need to being
to do all this book read in anyways
oh yeah that's true
one of the cops called me Dick Mullen to make fun of me
loving the series on YouTube so happy to catch your life
I'm happy you're here thank you
the plaque on the shelf reads Biographies of Famous People you see
you see no I don't give a fuck about that
I want the cockatoo book
this bookstore is not strictly about crime romance and biographies of famous people
there's also a wide range of paranatural literature
amidst the various books
you find one written by someone named Matthias W Dundas
it's about Wholeness Unity Balance
the point of the book and many others on this shelf
is to give people medicinal advice in situations
where they don't have access to paid health services
it serves platitudes
“那是怎么运作的呢”
while also telling everyone that traditional medicine
the kind people don't have access to
and which cost more than this book is garbage
and would only give you cancer anyway
without even curing your cold or anything
Wholeness Unity Balance
on the other hand can basically take care of anything
though it is important to note
when it's up to your mind to heal yourself
then it's because of your mind that you're *ill* in the first place
then it's because of your mind that you're ill in the first place
no
no no no
it's your own fault if you're ill got it
the book features chapters on topics such as
how to find magnesium
镁 我确实很需要这玩意
it even lists plants you can harvest magnesium from
how to continue drinking
if you're an alcoholic who has destroyed his liver
and there's even a chapter
on the ancient Seraise tradition of using duck gold ladder preservatives
to treat and prevent sexually transmitted diseases
pre- and post-factum apply
nothing worth buying
this is just mundane garbage what's even paranatural about this
我也是这么想的
fucking 97 percent chance find something truly otherworldly
the throbbing in your head increases
with every passing moment you gaze at this shelf
suddenly as if out of nowhere
a small green book becomes apparent
the title of it reads Medicinal Purposes of the Pale
“灰域是什么”
the book contains very little explanation on the matter
this knowledge seems to be taken for granted
what's this book about
the book contains descriptions of various pseudo-scientific therapies
alternative medicines and folk remedies
involving *the pale* also known as *le territoire*
for example it recommends vigorously swatting one's naked body
with a venik or hand broom made from
the leafy twigs of a young birch tree from the near-pale
even better if you can find someone else
preferably a large man dressed in nothing but a towel
to thresh you while you're spread naked and helpless on a cool slab
that sounds painful
it is supposedly invigorating and good for the circulation
行吧  “还有别的吗”
it also recommends consuming distilled spirits
like vodka or whisky that have been aged in the pale
readers are instructed to cover these jars in a shallow hole
just inside the pale and leave them there for 30-60 days
depending on the potency desired
okay what does this pale aged liquor do
among other benefits
it is alleged to restore a damaged liver to perfect health
what that's got to be impossible
I should probably get my hands on some of that where what else is in there
for general health and well-being
readers are encouraged to take regular strolls through the pale
though a sidebar cautions readers to limit each stroll to less than an hour
these strolls promise to cleanse the mind of warriers and the body of toxins
especially if the perambulator performs this ritual in the nude
nudity figures prominently in a number of these prescriptions
this is exactly what you need
so this reminds me of going to like
I went to this museum in my town
a little Dutch town at the Netherlands
they had this museum of medicine
and it was like all kinds of old practices and medicine
and shit like that dating back like
centuries ago
fucking weird stuff
like reading some of the books and
seeing the diagrams and seeing the instruments and all of the weird shit
that we used to think about how the body works
was so fascinating and horrifying
really weird this is what that reminds me of
I don't know
I don't want to be the party-pooper
but this *pale territory* sounds sort of dangerous
maybe you shouldn't walk in it naked
“还有什么要注意的吗”
there's an entire section devoted to cures for men
who are struggling to perform their *marital obligations*
I certainly don't need that
you close the book
and return it to its place on the shelf
I guess we could buy the book
I don't see why not
we'll find another way to make money
indeed something about that book does seem to have spoken to you
well I hope it contains what you're looking for
where's that fucking Cockatoo book
several maps have been attached to a bulletin board hidden inside the alcove
they're held up by small pins
the board has come loose from one corner
the maps look old and faded
your eye catches a map of Inculinde
a map of Revachol and a map of Martinaise
yeah I do need to pay for my room
we'll figure it out we'll find another way to get money
oh shit wait I this is where I could buy maps isn't it
can I buy these maps
抱歉 警官
the map of Martinaise is the only one available
the other two are not for sale anymore
and besides you could scarcely afford them
they're quite valuable
though they might not look it
the map of Martinaise is 90 cents though
好吧 好便宜
that old thing
it's an out-of-date map of a tourist location
that never was nor came to be from
from when some *design-studio people* tried to spruce the place up
four or five years ago
they also renovated the horse-statue
set up those coin-operated viewers
and designed the new street lamps
oh there's fast travel that's extremely useful
they didn't get that far
I want to buy the map
oh
a shame the project never got going
would be nice if someone fixed Martinaise up
all these ruins are bad for business
I could just try to take the map
but I don't I don't
let's just buy the map
this is for Annette
I don't want to defame
the work that she has done
always good to be informed of your surroundings
the north coast of a verdant island
（选项：查看瑞瓦肖地图）
is shattered by the delta of a river
it is the River Esperance
countless bridges put the shards back together
connecting city blocks to river islands
*La Delta* says a great artificial heart in the centre
teeming with lifeforms and construction
fast travels broken okay
to the east rolling hillsides
Le Jardin Stella Maris
the suburbs of Saint-Batiste swallowed up into the megacity
they sound *rich* to you this is Revachol East
“那河流西边呢”
Couron it's somewhere to live not bad
then there's Jamrock it's *bad*
people shouldn't live there but they do
then Faubourg it's almost *as* bad and much larger
then Coal City it's the worst
it's so small you can't even see it on the map
“那马丁内斯呢”
no wait there it is
north of Jamrock
the strip of coast next to the Greater Revachol Industrial Harbour
it looks downright despondent
it's almost Coal City to be honest
no Coal City is worse
a charred limb
rain falls on its slick black streets
then there's the Burnt-Out Quarter in the heart of Jamrock
is it cold in this bookstore
or is it just *you*
Shivers this is the best fucking
just the most unique voice out of all of the different scales
（平心定气）不
this is somewhere to be
this is all you have
but it's still something
streets and sodium lights the sky the world
you're still alive
fuck volition
getting it's getting real
that's a great line
this is somewhere to be this is all you have
but it's still something
streets and sodium lights the sky of the world are still alive
another thing that this is touching on is this right here
this is becoming more and more
centralized to our character's view of himself right
and I think that was so well punctuated by that dream sequence
the line that sticks out to me is you've you've failed everyone
it's not just like you failed yourself
you failed who you used to be
you failed the police precinct
you failed your relationship
you failed Kim
this is like it told us that we failed every single person alive
and everyone who's ever lived as well
like that is such a deep level of
uncertainty about your worth to the world
and that your life is even worth protecting
everything we have done today despite not
again not really progressing the narrative of the game very much
has told me a very distinct psychological narrative
about what Harry is experiencing
what is so central about this fear of failing everyone
about how much shame and regret has been driving our negative behaviors
up until this point
we're starting to make better decisions
and I think it's because we're seeing evidence
that this is not something that is known to ourself anymore
we're not sure
we are not sure if this is known to ourselves anymore
we are starting to question if it is true right
we are moving it to the unknown
and in doing so
we start to wonder if we should feel the level of shame that we do
we're starting to wonder
we're starting to get more comfortable with the convictions that we have
we're starting to feel less worried that people see us as fragile
which is something to be exploited and manipulated
and more so that we're struggling
meaning that we're someone to be empathized with and actually helped
we are only aware of those opportunities
because we do not feel that we are this anymore
or we're starting to
I think that
if we feel we are so unworthy that we have failed every single living person
we don't feel like we deserve anyone's empathy
and we don't feel like our convictions matter
when we start to displace that
we're starting to
this is the healing taking place
all of these things start to move now in our view of ourself
and this completion of failure
I think this motion right here is the most important one
that failure is becoming an unknown
and our view of ourself is starting to develop
it's not known to other people quite yet but
it's starting to
grow a little bit
you're starting to find a hope after experiencing so much failure and loss exactly
we're finding hope
that there is a child in this world like Annette who
seems to have kept some of her humanity locked away
behind the hardships that she's gone through
we're finding that even someone like Frittte girl
who seemingly has no prospects
if put into a different environment
would probably excel right
we're finding that
even Annette's mother right
given a little guidance
was able to see that
she was putting the priority of the business over her own daughter
and her health and safety
like there is a little bit of hope coming through
and I also think that there was hope coming through
when we spoke with Kim at the end of the last day
which is
we talked about why are we doing this
why are we solving the crime
remember how I said it it's not always clear what our own intentions are
like our intentions are often
unknown
why are we working on this case is it to impress someone is it to
make up for something that we did wrong
is it
is it because
we feel like it will fill in the missing pieces like is it selfish
we're not sure
we are starting to develop awareness that somethings we do
not because they're for anyone but because we believe in them right
and that's kind of the dialogue that we had with Kim
which was like we're doing this because we believe in something
we believe it's the right thing to do
we believe that by putting some order to the chaos of this environment
potentially all of these people who are broken down Frittte girl
the guy in the pawn shop
Annette Annette's mother
even people like Joyce and Evrart
there is this little bit of them that feels like given different circumstances
they would
do different things with the skills that they have you know
potentially someone like Evrart wouldn't use his tactics for manipulation
but as like strong leadership for people
yeah I think that there's a little bit of like
we're seeing hope bleed through the cracks
a little bit in this environment and
I think that this whole chapter of our adventure
are starting to actually see the patterns of change here
now that I feel confident this is being worked on
maybe we are not a complete failure
maybe there are some convictions that we genuinely have
maybe everyone doesn't think that we're a fucking loser and
maybe there are some good qualities
maybe potentially more qualities that are good than bad
now I do actually feel ready to go look in the mirror
now I do feel like there is enough psychological work taking place that
seeing some hope in the world
and seeing ourselves actually able to make positive changes with Annette
and Annette's mom
and other people that we're helping
means that there's some protection
here
so I'm gonna do it
I'm gonna do it
I fuck you fuck all of you guys okay
I'm gonna I gonna lock you all up
Lena
you have been instrumental in my healing process
Garte you know what you as well
I'm ready
and Kim I think more than anyone else I have felt
has shown me what I was looking for
which is moments of guidance and support and loyalty
that don't feel consequential
like that he's doing them because he expects something from me
I feel like he's shown me
that some of it comes from genuine care for us
so
I think it's time
especially now that we've got a cool hat on that we got from Annette
like that genuinely boosts our characters confidence a lot in my head cannon
a mirror hangs on the wall
covered in steam
you cannot see yourself
just the outlines of a man
you have no memory of the face that awaits you there underneath the soft vapor
really
or recollection of the person you are the people in your life and even the world you're in
has drowned in a sea of blood alcohol
this was no mere night of drinking
it was a deluge of world ending proportions
as you slowly reach your hand towards the surface of the mirror
abort
you clearly have not thought this through
you won't like what you see there
and you will never unbecome it
that's okay
part of me understands that I won't like what I see
not being okay with that
means I'm afraid that this is what I will find to be true
but something has told me that this is no longer true right
I'm not a complete failure
and so I'm okay with discovering that there are parts of myself that I don't like
and starting to sort of make peace with them
especially how I look to other people
because everything I've shown to people around me has been
disgusting
it's been confrontational
it's been vulgar it's been desperate
it's been embarrassing
and despite all of that
Kim has stuck around me
people like Annette still see good in me they still give me things
people have still asked me for help people still want me around
and so there simply cannot be something
so affronting about my appearance
if all of those things are true
so now we have to look
you have no idea who this thing is do you
this is the face of a late stage alcoholic
too late
you clearly have rigomortis on your face
oh wait is that an expression
are you trying to make an expression with that face why
I have no idea why it's there it just is
please stop
it's horrible you're scaring yourself
oh my god you can't stop
it's like it's not even voluntary anymore
you have worn that grin into your face and now it won't come off
what does it even mean
what is the emotion you're trying to convey
it's insinuating that I'm vaguely sympathetic
I think I'm sort of pulling it off too
in a sad has-been kind of way there is some charm to it
I think it's more appropriate to say that
it is an expression of pain right
when I like
cover
this part of it up like the smile
it looks painful to me
it tells a very different story
when you only see this side of it
you are correct
there's a lot of things we can't do here yet
guess we'll let the mirror be for now
I guess we can try the tool right
we have chaincutters is that what we needed to use or
a mirror hangs on the bathroom wall
in it your face adorned with the expression
I think there was a item that gave us more Interfacing
yeah some gloves
a mirror hangs on the bathroom wall
in it your face adorned with the expression
okay guys
lucky tomatoes in the chat for Harry facing himself
we need some seriously lucky tomatoes here
okay 28 percent
I just don't know if it's doable
okay
we've got lucky tomatoes going
let's roll the dice
the chaincutters is slip out of your hands
as you attempt to twist the faucet into place
well you know one thing for sure you've probably never been a plumber
we didn't make it
I mean there's nothing wrong with trying these right
they're white checks
I can just try to use this
it belongs in the new the third decade of the current century
what
enough time had passed from the failure of the revolution
that for a fleeting moment
free market economy seemed like the ultimate uncontested way of life for our species
so with the chaincutters and the fucking gloves
I couldn't bust the sink off
but what I could do is use my brain power to
think my way through the problem with an eight percent check holy shit
encyclopedia two
and I rolled two sixes
that is the perfect roll that is literally the best roll
I could get fucking critical success
well I'm going to be honest that this doesn't really mean much to me
I didn't really understand it
it belongs in The New the third decade of the current century
Enough time had passed from the failure of Revolution that
for a fleeting moment
free market economy seemed like the ultimate
uncontested way of  life for our species
okay
that's my real reaction
Things were good
It was "smooth sailing"
People made gold-and-champagne-tinted interiors and facades to suit the times
calling this "The New Style"
But more importantly
disco happened
disco
For Revachol your city
that meant only one thing Guillaume Le Million
out of the dazzling swirl of Disco music in an open air
boite de nuit somewhere in a Revachol west
Guillaume's blonde mane appeared on the screen
he sang some bullshit then he made the expression
okay
how long ago was the there
There is a vast ocean of time between right now
and the expression looking good on you or anyone
two decades if the calendar is to be trusted
humanity has run aground in that time
it's a different world  now
the expression is a relic
so I adopted it why
everyone loved it
maybe you thought some of the stardust would rubber from you
maybe it did
either way it's all gone now
only the grimace remains
anything else like who am I
why did I become a cop
why did I drink myself into oblivion
you have some understanding of the near history of disco
plus the trivia you've picked up along the way
episodic memory however remains in the dark
it may never return you should prepare yourself for that
you have some understanding
episodic memory remains in the dark and may never return
something will always potentially be incomplete
about our view of ourselves right
like there's gonna be a part of our memory that lives
like somewhere in the unknown that is just a
we'll never get access to it right
can we develop a full picture of ourself without access to this
that's a good question
personally I do think so
I guess that's it then
it doesn't have to be
you can swoon over Guillaume
and the champagne cook smile whenever you want to
maybe some of the stardust will return
hmm man wait a second
I thought that was the eight percenter
I failed that one
yeah I think it was even lower than that
see if I can win this one I don't know
it's too Late Like an image on film
The Expression belongs to your primary motor cortex
it would take a minor neurological miracle for you to cease producing it
gotcha my chances went out for that one okay
well that is our
expression now
we've got a new thought we've almost internalized this one
so I'm curious to see where this ends up
wait a second wait a second wait a second
does that say minus one to authority for rigorous self-critique
what have I been saying this whole time dude
I totally didn't even realize that
I have been saying this whole analysis  that
trying to use authority to protect people from
like seeing how fragile we are
because we're afraid of being manipulated for our desires
was the result of shame and regret and all of these things
like it's this  the reason we've been acting out through authority
when we have started doing the self critique
maybe we're not a complete failure
what is our view of ourself
what should we apologize for
what are our good convictions
what does it mean to be vulnerable
and let people empathize with us
we no longer feel the shame
and we stop trying to appeal to authority
so the fact that like
the game also recognizes this
that being sorry lowers your points in authority like that's
that's some serious psychological synergy
god damn I did not even realize
that they just knew what they were doing they
that the people who made this game had
such a strong grasp on what seems like every angle of the human condition
psychological political
social and
biochemical as well
right and like the fact that there are game mechanics that demonstrate that
I mean it's fucking incredible
it doesn't really explain why having a hobo hat
gives me better reaction speed
but does it need to
does it need to is the question
I knew something was missing here
I didn't have my my handy flashlight out to inspect everything
and it was initially written by eight people that's incredible
disco elysium actually the best game ever made it may actually be
so I do think that that means
that our appearance right
has now traveled
no I guess our appearance would have been the blind spot
i'm running out of space here our appearance has now entered
the arena
and I would say that its connection is
closely related to this right here
the fact that we're struggling
because it's something that people can evidently see
and it's part of the addiction
it's part of what we look like as a cop
it's part of why someone like an Annette was able to sympathize with us
and like call out that
hey you look sober you look distinctly sober right like
so learning about our own appearance
that it's now something that can live in the arena
what does that do to our view of ourself again
it brings it this way
but it also allows other people to see
like the connection to right
like rigorous self critique
isn't just an internal thing it's an open thing
especially now that we know what we look like
so
a very interesting
Johari window for Mr Harry
it's definitely incomplete
and I feel like maybe what I will do is
freeze this
you know I can take the stuff away if I need to
but what I will probably do at some point
do you like
scrubbing me
another one of these
and on that one
when we learn more about
um Mr Duboa's past
we will do the double layered johari window
so will save that one
no hahaha it's gonna be intense
but okay I think that this is going to be
our stopping point for the evening
what a way to cap it off
with finally looking at ourselves in the mirrors with our cool cowboy hat
and learning so much about ourselves as well
this playthrough just continues to
blow my mind with
how naturally it unfolds
despite me taking forever to like play the game
like the game is happening
but the character development is
so apparent to me
despite they're not like
to me it's it's like a kind of implicit storytelling
where we are writing the narrative
that's happening where is implicit storytelling
would be like the game saying
Harry is discovering this about himself
it would be basically telling versus showing
so much of this game has been amazing for its implicit storytelling
the fact that looking in the mirror
is something we decided to do after we experienced
enough self security to go and do it
like that's not the game deciding
you wake up and you look in the mirror and you learn about this
no it's very implicit and reactive to us
that's what's so amazing about it to me
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it consider giving it a like and letting me
know what you thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a little bit
earlier if you support the channel
either through Twitch or Patreon
links to both of those and the community discord are in the description
thanks again and I will see you next time bye