okay
hello
and welcome to the beginning of
a special playthrough of
a game that I have been
kind of like talking about with my community
to play for a very long time
it is Disco Elysium
if you are just discovering the channel
based on this which is a good likelihood that you are
my name is Brady
I'm a therapist
and we are gonna be doing like kind of a long form
analysis of the game that we're gonna play
we'll probably play out the games in the future as well
and we tend to ask a lot of
questions kind of in the space of
okay so
let's imagine this character was my client
like what sort of things
do I think that they would be dealing with
what sort of approach would I use to help them
so that's kind of what we're gonna be getting into and
I also myself am interested in creative writing
I would say like
I'm an aspiring writer
I have a bit of an imposture syndrome around like
I don't know if I'd call myself an author or not
I did write a science fiction novel a couple years ago
it's finished
I didn't publish it
and I don't know if I will at this point
it's just so old
now that it would need like a full rewrite and
I still keep telling myself
to go back and rewrite it or write something new
and I know that that kind of parallels Disco Elysium as like
this is not your average game writing like
there's a big focus on prose from what I can tell
I don't know anything about the story
I actually don't even really know anything about the setting
the only things I really know about it is that it has
a lot of acclaim a lot of for its like creative
aspects for its like prosaic dialogue and narration
and that it's kind of a CRPG
I like CRPGs I'm a fan of Baldurs Gate and
Divinity series
I played original sin 2 a couple years ago
fantastic game
I'm currently playing through Boulders Gate 3
really enjoyed pillars of eternity as well
so
those kinds of games I'm really into and
we have tried to play games on stream before but
just by the nature of like
discussing things from a therapeutic perspective
they can go quite long
so I'm gonna be trying to keep my thoughts a little more
focused and concise
but yeah I hope you enjoy what you see here today
we're gonna be uploading this
kind of periodically and if you want to come
check out the stream
see it live you're welcome to do so as well
so yeah let's do it
let's get into it
let's go I'm ready
oh there it is
got my little Brady box in the corner there
hey Brady I haven't seen you live in quite a while
looking forward to you playing this amazing game
thank you I'm extremely excited to dive into this
so I've got the like streamer mode on
so we may be missing out on some of the original music
but that's just that's the nature of what we got to do
hi Bertie you look so handsome today Kraith
you slay me Kraith it's so good to see you
I haven't seen you in ages in here
they want to move the camera to the top left
okay let's do that
and let's move the chat box here
hey king Yan
yeah we're we're finally getting to it
I've been promising that we'd be do we'd do this for
the fucking year now
okay
let's do it
select an archetype
oh it's a very Jungian and psychology
sort of thing
all right
the thinker extremely intelligent very bad with people
most interesting facts comes up with original ideas
okay
sensitive very psychological and magnetic personality but unstable
okay I think this
this might be me right here
physical extremely physical interacts with the world through his body
gets things done but dumb as a rock this probably not me
I don't get anything done with my body
I would say that no
bad with people is definitely not me
because by the nature of being a therapist
you have to be able to read people pretty well
any bets for how long the character creation will get
well do I go with an archetype or do I create my own
I mean this archetype kind of speaks to me
sensitive type
I don't know if I'd say my personality is
exactly magnetic but
wouldn't do a create on the 1st
or some people are saying create your own
there's no need
yeah let's just go as sensitive it speaks to me
I'm ready to lose my mind here
the furies are at home in the mirror
it is their address
even in the clearest water if deep enough can drown
okay let's go
there is nothing
only warm primordial blackness
your conscience ferments in it
no larger than a single grain of malt
you don't have to do anything anymore
my ancient reptilian brain I love that
ever
never
simply keep on non existing
this is like speaking to my fucking life right now
an inordinate amount of time passes
it is utterly void of struggle
no ex wives are contained within it
this is great
yes it is
you got it sweet brother
nothing upon nothing upon nothing
oh man the narration is phenomenal
how about you cough up some of that sweeter blue feeling let's go
coming right up sir smooth passage
expand my little box here a little bit
feeling a little too con-
a little too like claustrophobic in the void
oh we've got a little bit of French here Alons-y
let's go
I mean I have to go with the French
alright Nothingtown to Fuck-All-Borough
return trip to the
do you want me to upgrade that to a one way trip sir
sing me the song of death
the song of death is sweet and endless
but what is this
somewhere in the sore bloated man meat around you
a sensation
okay
yeah
this is this is pretty good I don't know what I would
have to say therapeutically for someone who is
nonexisting just yet
so we'll dive into that later
like a fly to the ointment
your conscience sticks to it
the limbed and headed machine of pain
an undignified suffering is firing up again
it wants to walk the desert
hurting longing dancing to disco music
hmm
you can take it you're a champion
some of my things seems to be cut off there
there's a head attached to my neck and I'm in it
Jeez that
sensation
take me back to the formless disembodied nothing
I'm feeling decisive
I'm feeling decisively attached to my
nothingness take me back there
the stench of liquor rises from your mouth
and with it an ungodly headache
cut off my head it's trying to murder the rest of me
Jesus Christ
a fiery streak penetrates your skull
trying to force your eyes open
it's a sound a clarion call from hell
let's go
let's fucking go
I'm ready for this to get really really weird
relatable
okay
see what we got here
I'm gonna take some pants
gotta get some pants on
you hear a jingle
keys are clinking in the pocket of your flarecut pants
it says whirling-in-rags on the aluminium keyring
there is a single key on the ring
the No. 1 is etched on it
it should open the door
okay
my guy is very
observational
take a look at that bottle there
Johnny Disco
empty bottle checks out
whole time to tie that
okay
let's get a scope on that shoe
it's just one shoe
just go with the left shoe
what we got here
kind of music is jamming
get that jacket on
got a tie on the on the fan there
this fan has two chainful switches
one ends in a tiny fan the other in a light bulb
a truly horrific necktie has somehow attached itself
to one of the blades or
has it been consigned there as punishment
you feel as though this creature is your friend
and wants to reattach itself to your neck
so that you may continue your adventures together
in this strange world
okay
we're gonna go for the tie
you reach out to grab the tie but what is this
diffuse radiating chest pain
doom comes over you
that's my only friend right now that tie
this is bad
feels like sharp stones grinding in your
chest and keeping you from moving
all right my dude's got some problems so far
for quite a long time
still ongoing
now is a good time to start worrying
finally the pressure recedes
you find yourself covered in cold
sweat and trying not to move
hoping it will keep you from dying
so what this immediately makes me think of
is the difference
and I guess the connection
like with the
like the nervous system
this is something I actually talk about
kind of often and in my work because actually a lot of
counseling that I do is
in the addiction space
one thing I'm always trying to get across to people
is that like
when you are of sound mind you make good decisions
right but as soon as your
bodily systems are disregulated for example
if you're feeling pain in your chest if you're feeling
confused about where you are if you're disoriented
if you're feeling isolated like
any number of negative things
introduced to your nervous system will like
really impact your decision making
and so like
you may not put a decision on your personality and say
yeah I would do that
but we see
people make decisions
that are not always in their best interest
the limbic system was one of the voices at the start
yeah I was picking up on that I'm like okay
that opening monologue actually really was
pointing at like
there is a fear of your own body
getting across here like
the mind wants something
I want to pull down this tie
but my body cannot keep up
like I am I am reaching out for this thing
which I am going to call
my only friend in the universe right now
this fucking tie
and it hurts me
physically
I cannot just muscle my body into doing what I want
and that fear of your own body is
something we all feel and is terrifying right
like the whole narration about
I'm in my head and I wanted
to cut it off from the rest of my body or whatever
like
that theme of
the fear of not being in control of what your
automatic systems do and tell you you can't do is
really real for me
I'm a person who likes to be in a lot of control
we'll unpack that later
but I know that I can't just demand my body do things
sometimes it really rejects my decision making
okay
let's try the light bulb
a terrible mistake
turn the lights off immediately
you can practically feel the photons burn in a hole
you see what I mean
like you're not in a good decision making
space you're like ah wog
that's another part of this right
and your autonomic nervous system is is your eyes dilate right
you're not in control of that
you cannot tell your eyes to dilate
you cannot tell your heart beat to raise or decrease
you can do things to yourself that
cause that reaction you can
pull on the light switch and
and blast your retinos
you can go from a dark room to a light room
or you can go jogging and
you know change your heart rate but like
you you can't directly influence
it's just a little hangover induced photosensitivity
don't overreact
okay it feels like
the games speaking directly to me
okay let's let's turn the light off
the lights are off
let's just leave I don't need the tie
I'm gonna leave the tie behind
what do we got here broken window
the window stands broken in its frame
cold wind blows in
visual calculus
this is a white check you may retry it okay
42 percent chance to succeed
the tie is my best friend what
being friends with him has brought me immeasurable pain
what do you mean assisted them
fuck
how would you do that
what are you even trying to do
why is this game like calling out me like this
I I am trying to meet its intellect and
it is vastly outpacing me right now
the morning light hurts your eyes
its hazy but you see the ocean and some war-torn buildings
fuck this I don't give a shit where I am
I don't care anyways fuck that tie
maybe I'll come back for it when my eyes have adjusted
see here I am
separate from the character
trying to figure out my environment
let's look in the mirror
what do I imagine will happen
he's going to be disgusted with himself
a mirror hangs above a bent and broken sink
in a fierce discharge of masculine energy
someone has ripped half the faucet off
hot water sprays from the base
and steam covers the mirror
you cannot see yourself
just the outline of a man
suddenly you realize you have no memory of the face
that awaits you there
underneath the soft vapor
you know what
doesn't matter
not gonna wipe the mirror down
I'm not in a solid state of mind here okay
my parasympathetic nervous system is absolutely distraught
so parasympathetic system is the one that is like
trying to cause the body to be at rest
like it's you know
it's trying to counter the sympathetic system
which is all about like
being very active
so it's your fighter flight
it's the thing that tells you you're in danger and
everything around me is in danger
like the environments fucked up
I don't know how I got here
I'm in pain making small adjustments
to my body like nearly kills me
I can't even get my best friend down from the fan like
my sympathetic nervous system is completely
in charge and it's disregulated
meaning I don't want to add any stress to that
what we got up here it's a shirt
let's go with the shirt
see if I can find my other shoe
give myself a heart attack with my own face
not yet see show
maybe maybe in a little bit I'll do that
oh okay
a little bit out of my stupor now
my immediate reaction is to go to talk to the woman
let's do it
hello Officer
officer
the young woman raises a cigarette to her lips
how is this game like literally in my brain it's like
the dialogue is literally the thoughts I have
there's only one solution to this
you're a businessman
gotta be a businessman
why'd you call me officer
because you're a police officer sir
are you sure whoa how would you be
I am yes
unless you've been feeding us a set of very well
rehearsed lies all this time
I could be
you've been here for three days
on official police business no or less
and what business
couldn't say
in truth so far
mostly drinking
checks out
I'm gonna role play a little bit here and assume that
I don't I don't want my guy to be
too forward with his self awareness right
if I'm going with like the
psychological type I'm not gonna be like
too self critical
Let her know that I want her physically I don't think so
I kind of want to do it just for the meme but I also
I don't know if it would be fitting of my character
she wouldn't know
I'm just gonna leave
of course
be careful officer
they don't like the police around here
she looks back at you a light glinting off her eyes
goodbye
hmm okay
that was as awkward of an exchange
chance gone
is there like a really good line that she says
if you say that
it's March the year is 51
okay
I don't know if it would be in a
good psychological spirit to immediately try to
thrust myself into an attachment relationship
with a stranger
okay I wanted to check that out before I leave
where's my other shoe
I would like to make fuck with you
you should pick that fat juicy cigarette butt from the tray
light it up and smoke the living shit out of it
holy shit okay this is actually like his nervous system
you can even see the diagram like literally
this is capturing exactly what the body tells the brain
like in addiction essentially like
right now his
his two nervous systems the
well there's central and the peripheral but
within the peripheral system there's that like
parasympathetic and
sympathetic and they are fighting with each other like
he's introduced drugs or something into the system and
right now his
sympathetic side the one that wants to stay active is like
get up your in danger your brain hurts go do something
maybe go fuck someone
right that's what it's telling him
but his other side the parasympathetic is like
slow down
take a walk go to bed like
stop trying to push me harder than
than I can keep up
and then his sympathetic side is actually like
smoke that cigarette okay
you're feeling down this will wake you up
smoke the living shit out of it
have a drug yeah keep this party going
the living shit
your mesolympic reward pathway does not mince words
who knows what you are
a monster a murderer the gnome of Jeroma
you feel like a smoker
especially when you look at that juicy
succulent seductive cigarette stub
still smouldering deliciously
yeah
how very astute of you
this renders it ineffectual
you should look for a whole cigarette
an entire pack
strike that a carton
make sure they're all healthy and able bodied
then smoke them all
how about I just go
fucking pocket the whole drug store at this point or
you could not do that
no one is making you
this is fucking good this is like literally
what I imagined the inner dialogue
of your body to be having
like the electrochemical part
the the different nervous systems is like
I demand resources
I demand you keep fucking up this system
it's the only way I know how to thrive
but his volition like his
the part of him that is
almost invasive at this point of like
sound mind is like wait
maybe you shouldn't do that
I'll think about it
good
thinking about yummy cigarettes in the mouth is the
best this is great
make sure you think about juicy sticks of tobacco
all the time
it doesn't count if it's not all the time
this is literally the inner narration of addiction
and when you're done
thinking about them
graduate to getting them
man I may actually need to like implement some of
this games like dialogue into some of my classes
I literally work in addiction
this is like so good for explaining to people how
the different parts of the body and the mind
are in competition
with one another for what your priorities are
smoking them gives massive bonuses
what kind of bonuses we talking
I need to get my hands on some cigarettes and
smoke them for those massive bonuses
this
game is reading my mind
find a pack put it in your hand
equip it in the held slot
and the smokes will do the rest
all right
well it looks like we're looking for some cigs
doesn't seem like I have any cigs at the moment
what did that say
is this my motivation on my motorics
I don't move my body very well
maybe if I had some smokes I could
let's scope the scope the apartment
the door is closed
this door can only be opened with a key or from the inside
okay let's leave it
look at my real life
I don't just go banging on any door that I see
Trompe le Monde
uh I don't know what tomp means but Lemont is the world
good point about the window and the missing shoe
something on the table
what is it
oh some money maybe I can get some cigarettes with it
scope out my environment a little more here
hey there's the shoe
all right we're fully equipped now
some briny wind there's salt in there
there they both are
two identical shoes
both copiously green and indiscriminately snakeskin
reunited on your feet
these do not look like normal cop shoes
I mean not much is normal about my dude
good they're balanced comfy
feels like the only good thing about you right now
Jeez
not quite fully equipped
smell of the sea makes me dizzy
well and that's the other
thing about the nervous system is like
anything you introduced to it like
imagine my
sympathetic side which is
about staying active and responding to threats
if I smoke a bunch of meth okay
that's the side of my nervous system
that's gonna be like
really disregulated
but even small shit like a cup of coffee or
you know going on a jog like
it's gonna impact your decision making even
just in a minor way
summer door closed for the winter
maybe we will get a chance to sing on that later
you should totally sink karaoke here
the first chance you get
your emotions need to be expressed
people need to know your vast oceanic soul
okay this is getting weird this game is like
this is like reading my mind
my soul is puny
my soul's cubic content is obscured by the hangover
of course
at this point
precise measurements of your soul
can only be performed from the outside
it needs to be heard
through a PA system
by other people whether they like it or not
says your adrenaline gland
violently express yourself
you have not stumbled on the right lamentation
but it's out there
it will come to you
you will wreak havoc with it don't worry
they'll really get a gauge of my soul with that
serves them rights
wipe that smirk off their face with your sad tragic song
yeah give fuck
I'll show you my cubic content
you have to find something tragic to sing first though
this is my quest now what is this game
great
I just saw I need some cigarettes and I need a way to
blast my miserable soul to as many people and
solicit it to their unwanting ears
water cooler
what is this
healing item
where do I find my healing items
is coffee a healing item
that's
too real in my life
don't know where it went
let's talk to this gentleman
a man in his late 20s stands behind the counter
inspecting a stuffed seabird
as you approach he gives you a sideways glance
then looks down again
that was distain in his eyes
even now he's purposely ignoring you
interesting I like that the
coding of empathy here is not
like what we commonly think about it as
which is like
relating to someone in an emotional way
empathy is just your ability to read other people's
emotions including negative ones like distain
let's look at the stuffed bird let's go scope on that
a competent work of taxidermy
the white and brown seabird
lies among piles of coasters
and drying mugs
one of its wings broken
the man is trying to mend it
looks like the bird was ripped off the shield
that was used to mount it
most likely on a wall
something about it makes you feel bitter
what happened to the bird
your body is over there
man in the bomberjack is tapping his foot on the floor
why don't you go and talk to him
okay
I don't like this deflection
I want to know what happened to the bird
I'm a cop I talk to whoever I please
he pretends not to hear you
concentrating on the bird instead
let's redirect
no I'm not the bartender I'm the cafeteria manager
I'll let him think he's in charge of this exchange
oh no you're a hero a real hero cop
so I'm not only a cop I'm also a hero
I'm gonna feign ignorance to his sarcastic wit
yes you are a real decorated hero
what did you not do
first you took the body down then you solved the murder
then you didn't trash my hostel room
maybe you even negotiated the strike
guessing I didn't do any of those things
I'm not going to confirm or deny whether I know that
so I'm just going to go with
again a redirection no
it's not
he raises his shoulders like about to say something
you're right
it's not
he has no respect for you person
this man sees himself as a law abiden citizen
and for you a representative of that law
he tries to avoid outright conflict
I feel like we won that exchange
I feel like that was a victory
in my book
Monday all right
who's the who's the gentleman in the bomber jacket
well let's get a scope on this wheelchair lady first
cryptozoologist
you shouldn't keep your colleague waiting
okay she's got a there's a mystery in her voice
a bespectacled man in an orange bomber jacket
is tapping his foot on the floor
as you approach
he narrows his eyes and extends his hand in greeting
if an assault were launched on this building right now
if the windows came crashing down
and the whole world descended upon you
this man would hurl himself in death's way to save you
you are sure of this but why
to be honest
the why doesn't matter
let's shake this man's hand hello
I'm Kim Kitsuragi
lieutenant precinct 57
you must be from the 41st
you realize he's waiting for your name
this is your chance to come up with a really good name
for yourself get creative
conceptualize
all right
Raphael Ambrosius Costeau
I was going to get creative
well it's a pretty cool name
want to come up as a douche if I call myself that
no it's very very cool
but maybe just a bit too ostentatious
I'm gonna go with the double superlatives
it's very very cool
no it's not Rafael Ambrosius Costeau is one classy name
for one classic cop say it
I don't know why the game treats this
obvious win as a fail
it's a good observation
this is a complete W for me
yes well
he doesn't even process what you just said
it looks like we had a little scheduling error on Sunday
Saturday too actually
have you had time to talk to the manager here
there must be some kind of misunderstanding
you're taking me for someone else
yeah
if you don't mind we should talk to him again
ask him for a rundown of the area
now that I'm here as well
I understand the scene is out back right
it also wouldn't hurt to assure him
the police are finally here
in full force I mean
have you mapped out the initial interviews
um
I haven't
okay we'll have time for that
after we take a look at the coroner's case
a little bit of honesty goes a long way
I could sense it when I shook this man's hand
and I and I detected that he would give his life for me
that he's someone I should be honest with
all of the time
except for that time
I just tried to lie to him and make up a cool name
but ultimately the game made up a cooler name for me
anyways
have you removed the dead body from the tree
I'm just gonna go with him
so the body is still in the tree
it's the first time you detect a weariness in the lieutenant's voice
it's obvious
he would have preferred for the body to no longer be in the tree
and a stooped Observation Rafael
where it has been hanging for seven days straight
we should go there as soon as we are done talking to the owner
I can't remember anything
what were we supposed to do again
let's let's clarify this point
where do we just go with it
no that would be dishonest
I can't tell if I want to be honest
then we go out back and take the body down
all right
to you officer
if you're about to embark on an investigation
shouldn't you have a badge
well I should have a badge and some cigarettes probably
you mean you don't have a badge
losing your identification card is a serious matter
my vehicle has a shortwave
you can use it to report your badge missing
I advise you to try to locate it as quickly as possible
but getting the body down should still take precedence
lieutenant Kitsuragi is now in your party
you can talk to him whenever
by interacting with him
okay well I've made a new friend at least
hey besage shmack
thank you so much for subbing with prime my friend um
you also get access to all of the stuff in the
Eurobrady archive through doing so
you just have to link your Twitch with
discord and you'll get access to that discord channel
and you'll find all of these streams
much earlier there and
a bunch of like
reaction stuff without any of the editing
so thank you
oh you already have
perfect well for anyone watching who does
so that's what you got
it's a little easier when people sub through Patreon because
there's some instructions but
I haven't figured out a good way to
inform people who might sub on Twitch
maybe I should just put something in the
about section or whatever
okay I'm not an union member
are there any siggy buds lying around
maybe
this guy's got some cigarettes
I could use me as smoke
a man is sleeping
I just watched the lighthouse by the way
if you guys have seen that
maybe we'll talk about the lighthouse at some point
but he says that I could use me a smoke
A man is sleeping at the table
wearing mud-caked boots and rolled down overalls
the back of his shirt reads
Wild Pines
encircled by a logo with a tree
on the counter rolled out of his open hand
you see a blister pack of headache medicine
I'm gonna take those pills
the man does not mind you probably need them more than he does
you've just picked up some magnesium
this item is stored in the bottom left corner of the screen
above your character portrait
use magnesium to heal your morale
if you have morale damage
morale damage okay
no idea
looks like he works for Wild Lions
the logistics company who owns and operates the harbour
possibly because there's a strike going on in the harbour
there's not much to do aside from drinking and sleeping
let's try to wake him up
you gently shake his shoulder
I have failed everything I've tried
this man could probably
sleep soundly in a ship's engine room
whatever they don't fucking care about him anyways
okay
I had to talk to the manager again right
the man with unimpressive beard notices you approaching
he dropped the ledger he was holding
and turns to the lieutenant
I love how the addiction focused therapist wants to get addicted
look I'm trying to push this guy to his limits
and I want to demonstrate
look all I'm trying to do is give a public service announcement
okay drugs are bad for you
and they will do bad things to you
and you will do bad things to yourself and other people
when you're on them
so what better way to illustrate than that to
get my boy here on
the sigs
Mr Garte right
yes
I am Kim Kitsuragi from precinct 57
this is an interdistrict investigation
so joining me from precinct 41
he looks to you
realizing he still doesn't know your name
Raphael Ambrosia Casto
right now I know it took us a while to arrive at the scene
it also took a while to colors and reported dead body
it was you who plays the call yes
correct no I only just got here
it was probably Sylvie who called you
she usually works the bar here
I'm only temporarily taking over her duties
you're probably wandering in some
Grove of tag elders up north in candi
knee deep in snow
black Marvel with the lighthouse quote
fucking love that movie
not a coincidental parallel to make
he's got the dead seabird here
we're talking about stuff that has really good
pros prosaic dialogue and writing
and is about the inner misery of human experience
do you have our number
and the desperate clinging for
release
top 5 for sure yeah definitely
as a matter of fact I do
you said you just got here from where
what of Martinaise
no I live in Jamrock
I only sometimes come here to keep an eye on the place
this is just one of the many many cafeterias I manage
oh he's a multi hyphenet he's an enterprising man
but you still know your way around
yes in case we need directions
yes I know where some things are
but as I said I don't live here
I just used to work here
and I'm not going to start working here again
if that's what you think
I didn't imply that detective
I have everything you
no I'm
yes yes
he means do you have questions for me
like a police officer would
where exactly why we know the bodies in the tree
who killed I don't know who killed him
I'm not the police
that's your job
did you kill him
crazy of course I didn't kill him
I don't know you're looking
you're getting pretty frustrated
with that suddenly tense up
blood is being pushed to your muscles
you should hound him on this
hound him hard
yeah
fucking go for it
no I didn't I didn't
I don't appreciate this what is this
do I have to answer him
is this mandatory
it's the law
lieutenant stands motionless
his expression unreadable
what are you an idiot
I told you I haven't killed anyone
anyone have you killed someone else
then she ignores you
she went away because none of your business
okay find this building there's a courtyard
they hoisted him up on a tree there
that's easy see that door there
first you exit through that
then to your right
you should see a big hole in the fence
a really big one
you can get to the courtyard through there
no need for the keys
the hole is big
enough for the Franconigerian cavalry to fit through
does he want you to feel guilty of making that hole
it's implied in his voice
let's go
so I'm the hole-maker
not so fast you owe me 130 real
Savoir Faire I think it means to make a save in French
fair as like to do
and savoir save
pretty low chance
I slip away unnoticed I mean look 17 percent
that's good enough odds for me
I'm not a mathematician
but I think I've got a pretty good chance at slipping away
as you blow this joint
what the fuck
I completely worked
let's fucking go
let's blow this fucking joint
real mature man real mature
alright Raphael
let's fucking go what a start to our adventure
ah savoir means to know
sevoir fair is when you know how to do a know how
gotcha thank you for the clarification
I'm still a beginner
un débutant in French
let's fucking go that was
a great start to our adventure
okay we're looking for a fence
let's get a scope on that trash can first
bottles inside you should pick them up if you had a bag
are they empty bottles
look I know that my character is actually looking for
some tasty sigs so
is there like an information kiosk or something
this poste L'Aventurier
mail collection box has been heavily vandalized
with graffito
a closer inspection
reveals two bullet holes in the front
give the delivery box a pat
let's do it
I'm
gonna give more humanity to the delivery box than most
people in this place
seems happy
what the fuck is this interaction I love this
hey no worries Bionic ghost thanks for stepping by
some of the best moments
of the game come from failing checks
so don't be discouraged by
odds if you really want to do something
oh totally
each shit pig fucked by the CUNN
and saint G with the crown have been scribbled on it
Jenny is a whore and baise cette mailbox also
I feel you male collection box
the male collection box seemed cathartic thankfully even
so do you
you shudder then you swallow
this was a very human
exchange
and then suddenly you see it
over all the other graffitas
someone has using the tip of a very sharp knife
cut the words revachol forever
all right
I couldn't get the tie so the mailbox is my best friend
so apparently I
maybe I do need to go look in the mirror
I want to see what happens if I don't
before he stands a motorcarriage
the bodywork is covered in blue and white livery
bearing the number 57
vapor emanates from the large
engine on the back of the vehicle
it hasn't had time to cool off yet
in the cabin
you are welcomed by a set of steering levers
a radio microphone on a hook
a pull out toolbox under the seat
and the soft glow of the fuel preheater gauge
let's get Kim's opinion here
this is the Coupris Kineema
my motor carriage
you can use the toolbox and the radio if you'd like
motor carriage motor carriage
something bad with a motor carriage
a dark lump rises in your throat
okay but what is a motor carriage
do all the policemen in
RCM have such cool motor carriages
the Coupris MotorCorp does provide
most of our petrol vehicles yes
in the cabin you see a set of steering levers
a metallic drawer slides out from under the seat
and clicks into place
take what you need officer
it's going to be a long case
I'm not protective of my tools like some men are
Tim is a good guy
he's clearly a little protective of his tools
but what can he do
work is work
I'm thinking chain cutters
handles are long and sleek
snap snap though the cutters in your hand
probably gonna need to do some more work on
that fence over there
let's go with the flashlight
robust weatherproof and well made
police issue blue
lets you see things in the dark you would otherwise miss
let's take the pry bar
probably need to defend myself your hand
heavier than you'd think
yeah I'm really enjoying the mix of French
did he say it was like Franco-Nigerian
is that is this a like a
is that a setting
cold and heavy
like truth
you feel like you're reunited with truth once more
useful for opening all sorts of doors and lids
the pullout toolbox slides back into its nest
preheater gate casts the warm glow on the steering levers
and the radio on its hook
the frequency tabler lights up
and the green button labeled Prime Line
glows like a feline eye
and then you hear something
damn the writing is so good I
feel all the sensation of that
like a feline eye
love it
it's not a real world
it's a fictional universe
but you'll learn more history okay
the soft purr of electrical kittens
radio waves cast farm electrical kittens
what a Turner phrase you
through the static
this is precinct 57
hello lieutenant how may I assist you
hello Alice
please assist our colleague from the 41st precinct here
I'm putting him on
come in dispatch come in dispatch
this is Firewalker
this is officer Alice DeMettrie Precinct 57
how may I assist you
could you connect me to the 41st precinct
of course what is her number officer
did he get sylvie's number
her number is 005
received hold on officer
lieutenant kitsuragi
slowly begins to tap a little rhythm
with his right foot
officer I have sylvie malaiika on the line for you
yes hello
there she is
okay this is the police calling
I have some questions for you about
your last days at work
Sylvie I believe we've met before this is me
let's not reveal our identity
all right
hello officer
what can I do for you
you can hear resentment in her tone
she's not thrilled to be talking to you again
there is no resentment in her tone
she wants you to ask her out
oh man
no question about it
electrochemistry is
he's got an interesting view on the world
my dude's body
demands it
we already missed our chance with the
girl with the cigarette so
I don't know
conflicting thoughts yeah
do you want a cup of coffee
no I think that would be in poor taste
yeah I'm gonna try to
quell my urges
you mean why did I leave the bar
honestly I'm
not really comfortable discussing it with you sir
why aren't you comfortable discussing it with me
let's just say I left
because I needed to get away from someone
I won't push you on this no that doesn't sound like our guy
you know who
you think you hear a sliver of accusation in her words
is it me
don't be paranoid she's obviously talking about someone else
what the fuck
this game is in my brain
is it me
I really don't want to talk about this
let's just forget about this okay
maybe I don't know
I just know I have to take some time off right now
okay you are not helping me
please don't call me again bye
let's try out some empathy
yes you have obviously done something to upset her
at the whirling in rags
when she was still working there
you're mad at me right tell me what did I do
I'm not mad it's just
you were so drunk and so emotional all the time
and then
the skua thing thing happened
this made me want to quit
I was the one who made you want to quit
yes obviously
you were the worst client I've ever seen
and I have seen so many assholes in here
okay we're learning a little bit about ourselves here
I've had sailors fighting
union guys grabbing my ass kids stealing booze
once a guy was glued to the karaoke machine every night
for two months
but you
what did I do
you were worse than all of them
honestly you were getting boarded line aggressive
even about little things
like not turning down the volume at 3 am
I even liked one of those songs
you kept listening to on repeat
no more I I hate it now
okay
which song
we go on by the OO
I can't listen to it anymore
you've turned it into a parody
that's the song I'm gonna
sing later at the karaoke bar
then there was your room
your project
I tried to send the cleaner but you wouldn't let me
threatened to makes me understand
oh no I have no idea what you meant
and I don't want to know
and then you screamded something incomprehensible
about churches and the scent of apricots and aquariums
oh my God
that's not so bad
I'm sorry let's apologize again
I had to deal with your toilet
the one you
clogged with police documents
causing water damage downstairs in the kitchen
I won't even mention you waving your gun around
harassing customers
threatening to sing karaoke
threatening to kill yourself
wait police documents okay
we're actually getting somewhere here
the ones I had to rent out of your toilet
they're in the toilet
damn it I don't remember what I did to your damn papers
I don't remember every little thing I do
she's worried she might have accidentally done
something bad
then she remembers it's you
especially when there's a hurricane loose
it's your fault for losing them not mine
something in you wants to immediately forget about this
as if there was a reason you threw them away
no you really weren't
you were simply the worst
well you're the worst tavern wench I've ever seen Geez
don't you ever party
okay if I'm imagining
my guy at this point like
he's having these conflicting desires
and at one moment you
you do see people especially who are
let's say hungover or withdrawing or detoxing like
their emotional
mood can shift very drastically right and
while I have been pursuing a very
empathetic response here
my priority as a character is like finding out
more information and
she has reached her limit
she's not telling me anything new
so she's useless to me now
from my character's point of view
god I know I shouldn't have brought it up
just try not to call me again
and let's pretend it never happened
the stuffed bird the great skua
you threw it against the walls
fuck that bird
fuck that bird and I think you said it had been
giving you shit ever since you got there
bitch bird got what's coming to her
this doesn't sound anything like me I love birds
right
oh all sorts of things some disco rock too
which one would that be
sad
I think the one you mean is the smallest church  in Saint saens
butchered that right up
interesting you still have to find it however
all right that's enough of you sylvie
anything else I can have you with officer
uh I guess we can make a report
10-2 10-5
this is 41st come in over
a scrawny old man sits in a dusty cubicle
smoking with a large white rectangle sewn on his vest
in front of him is a box shaped apparatus
with an array of wires and antennas
the radio switchboard
god I love these illustrations
10-4 what's your status over
10-18 10-20 over
uh just talk human to me
state your message over
my badge is missing
10-9 repeat message over
10-4 message received
this is a very serious situation
I need to 10-22 the captain over
10-22 the captain
this sounds bad
bad and scary
like being called to the Edmaster's office in school
is it him
what does he want
says he lost his badge and needs to report it
he what he lost his badge
let's just let them sort it out
Dick fucking Mullen
who do you think
it's office Dick Mullen from the best seller Dick Mullen and the lost identity
Dick Mullen is not your name
it's the name of a fictional detective
who would not lose his badge
defend yourself
immediately
they laughing at you
yeah
let's just move on
level up
make a note here
that you're in the shoot of your misplaced badge over
okay see this the skills here is
they were hoping for an escalation
they were hoping
I would get involved and defend myself
and I'm just not about it
fuck me Mac come here you've got to hear this
Dick Mullen lost his badge
what's going
supercorp here lost his badge
he lost his what now
all right come on
he lost his goddamn fucking badge
10-9 come again I didn't get that over
new heights even for Captain Sober
ask him
ask him if he's lost his gun too
so this guy sucks
sergeant torson wants to know if you lost youe gun too over
check your pockets
check your holy fuck you don't know where it is due
no I don't I don't know what my gun is
it's gone your gun is most definitely gone
to be honest though I don't think I should have a gun
you get my question
we were wondering about your gun
Drama Medium convinced them that you didn't lose your
gun let's go for it
17 percent chance that did not steer me wrong last time
let's go for it
even before you can get the words out
everything gets scrambled in your brain
oh it's not like
I tried to convince them and they don't believe me
I literally couldn't say it
he says he didn't lose his gun
or his fun whatever that means
ask him to describe
it his gun not as fun
oh fuck these people
I want to be out of this conversation now
the fuck do you need a gun for
look at the pythons on your arms
you are a gun
let's go
the biggest one in the world
yeah
oh request a description huh
we'll give him one
describe the Blaasma Gun
for starters it's massive
got flared cooling vents along the front and
hydrogen flasks sticking out too
a regular goddamn murder weapon
you know how they are bang bang that sounds like me
he says it's just a regular gun
sounds like he's being deliberately vague
this scene is great what the fuck is happening
Detective Mullen has done it again
uhhh
where's my gun now
fuck off
dear God he locks his gun
oh my I can't
I hope I get revenge on these people later
this isn't really a laughing matter
Mack can faced the giant of koko nur by himself
but disco here made him piss his pants
oh I can't fuck he lost his
ask him if he still has his wiener
I'm not going to
ask him
sergant torson here is wondering if you are still
in possession of your genitalia over
now is a good time to say fuck and ass and so on
that'll make this all right
yeah I'm just gonna turn the radio off
I'm feeling too ashamed to continue this
the slience is almost deafening
after you flick off the switch
severing the connection
that did not go well
I guess the important thing is that
you followed protocol and reported your lost items
that's a great
positive reframing
did we need anything else here
oh no I don't think we need anything else
let's just keep going
I'll count that as a win
I do count that as a win I did the right thing
okay let's see what we got here we've got a
oh I've got my crowbar
got my flashlight
oh that's that's cool
probably don't need to be holding that though
I am gonna hold the crowbar though you never know
you never know
all right let's
check out what's behind that busted fence
oh there's a kid
I'll approach him with my crowbar in hand
cuno's got this
oh yeah napakymppi Cuno
oh I leveled up I forgot about that
police business
cuno get him right in the dick
don't get me in the dick
**** love it in the dick
the boy is sweating profusely
his eyes are like two black holes and his jaw is
twitching as if trying to break free from the
empire of his body
okay so he's on drugs
stop using slurs at my crime scene
yeah let's bring some dignity into this cruel world
shit coming up strong
throwing rocks
that sounds good
joyous you should hang out with this kid
and see what that juicy shit is all about
maybe oh maybe he's got some cigarettes or better
the kids on drugs
I told you the kids on drugs I know this
I'm a professional
cuno's riding it C
the rake cuno
he should throw the rake at him dude
don't throw the rake at me
does Cuno know what a rake is
Cuno is not a gardener
let's get kim involved let's see what he thinks
we shouldn't do anything
I don't tempt such forces you will see
okay Kim's feeling like we shouldn't get involved
so
ahh
you want to hang out fuck no
Cuno doesn't buy that shit
fucking entrapment shit
look
I have questions for you
entertain the Cuno
show me what you got
I entertain the Cuno
what you got huh
show me what you got
the body what do you know about it
shitload pig what's your question
don't tell the pig shit cuno
let's get Kim in
if I were to want to waste my time which I do not
I would ask them who he is
how we got there and the usual
you have no idea what the usual is
just after whatever comes to mind
do you know how who he was
cuno's fuck-gimp cuno uses the fuck-gimp for target practice
end of conversation
very strong
you should be this stoic
do you know how he got up
probably climbed Cuno was busy down the road when that shit went down
you hesrd Cuno
Cuno wasn't even in Martinaise
Cuno wasn't in Revachol
Cuno wasn't regional
I don't know some fucking
Mesque or I don't know some other place
Night City Cuno is in fucking Night City
Cuno gives this info out on a need to know basis
and you don't need to know
Cuno didn't smoke the gimp if that's what you meant
yeah
Cuno is smoking something though
right you're testing Cuno's patience here
I'm done with you Cuno
Cuno doesn't fucking care
look I if only I could be as opinionated as Cuno
ooh what do we got here
we got some
we got some suspicious looking dirt and footprints
there are several footprints in the mud
left by workboots
anywhere from 6 to 12 pairs have walked here
visual calculus my guy is really not
he's not very good at this kind of stuff
he can't even count the number of shoes really
let's try
maybe more than 12 no
all right
I'll take it
....back and forth in the mud
1 standard work boot steel reinforced toes number 46
I'll take it okay so 8 pairs of footprints this was a
this was a multi man crime
literally streamer luck
sometimes your chances increase if you
explore other dialogue first okay
2 standard work boot steel reinforced toes no 44
my yeah my guys like absolutely falling apart
except when it comes to like
really weird stuff
he's just extremely perceptive
...steel reinforced toes no 43
4 standard work boot no 45 or 46
5 another standard work boot steel reinforced toes no 44
oh they can they can decrease as well okay
six an aberration
light as air even pace
same make of boot but number 41
male or female
impossible to tell
could also have been an adolescent
the gait is undeveloped
Cuno could be involved
I'm pretty good at this ain't I yeah
you're not bad
it's as if the whole world darkens
everything else has a thin film of unimportance on it
and the tracks burn in the middle of it
in a strange beautiful way
7）the glowing...
I wonder if Kim thinks of my
because Kim
26 but the imprints are twice as deep as the others
the weight exceeds 200 kg
I get the vibe that Kim
thinks I'm very unimpressive
and that he just has to spend time
with me because of the duty
but I wonder what he thinks about my astute
observations now
and yet another standard work boot number 44
there's an aberration in the pattern of the sole however
the right sole is smoother more worn
I'm definitely gonna ask him
I really want to impress
him and I want him to think that I'm cool and
that I'm not a fucking mess
how many
what is so great if I just blew it
if I just did all of that observation and was like
fucking four hundred million
let's go
there's 8
I was pretty often I counted 20
that's why I'm the deputy and you're the lieutenant
way off Kim way off
yeah clean those glasses Kim
I never got the hang of it hyperopia
you need me
do you see anything out of the ordinary
okay wait I actually need to do something else
what did it say
I was more focused on how impressive
I was doing rather than the
actual content of what I was seeing
an aberration one so smoother than the other
interesting
let's name it the odd sole
the odd sole
Kim is you know what he is he's a wordsmith
he's he's the one who's really providing the
narrative context to our adventures
someone operating work bench with a pedal
like a joiner at the habor
or maybe a drummer
he regrets it the moment he says it
drummer that's stupid
no we don't want we want him to think we're cool
we don't want to
I want him
I want him to feel a little bit inadequate so that he
feels like
like he needs me in his life
but I don't want to push him away
this is a fine line
I'll just not I'll let him
I'll let that observation simmer in in the air
I don't know why I say that
we are not looking for a drummer
we are looking for a group of dockworkers
why'd you say it then Kim
what do you know that you're not telling me
the lieutenant clearly appreciates the chance
to clear up the drummer issue himself
perhaps it could be a driver
a driver would wear out their right shoe before the left
the accelerator is on the right
it's a little suspicious Kim
who are you protecting
I just nod thoughtfully
we should keep our eyes open around the traffic jam
see whether anyone strikes out as a potential suspect
seems prudent no
yes prudent
hmm
alright I'm a little suspicious of Kim now
a cop doing some manipulation
like it's not manipulation I'm doing detective
I'm detecting
impress him more
okay let's go
a woman or a kid
light step No. 41 what did I say about that
oh it actually doesn't go all the way up
okay that's fine
I don't think there's any way to be sure
lightstep
well there's probably not
oh it could be a kid it's probably fucking Cuno
okay how do you know
he knows it's hard to discern sex from a person's gait
Raphael he's a fucking genius
I'm just saying random things
while looking at holes in the mud
I have no no I can't be that honest I just do
understood anything else
okay Kim that's why I'm the
I'm the lead detective here
okay let's go last one heavy one 200 kilogram imprint
two hundred
could it be the combined weight of two people
one carrying the other who's tied up
let's say a heavily built worker
carrying a similarly built soon to be dead men
could be the combined weight of two people
one carrying the other who's tied up
what kind of observation is that
he might be right
200 kg of living weight is unlikely
I'll kilograms yeah that's pretty heavy
could have been an extremely obese person
one of them was carrying him over
possibly yes
how old do you think these tracks are
...7 days would feed the time frame provided to us by the caller
who reported the hanging
it is not impossible
I pulled last week's forecast for coastal Revachol
7 days below freezing
the day before
the day of his hanging was the last one day
okay solid information there
sub zero temperatures would preserve the
tracks in a good state
the commotion here could have taken place a week ago
what do you think happened here Kim
what do I think
a mob of people brought something heavy to the tree
one of them was carrying the victim
they shuffled around especially under the tree
hmm
then after hoisting him up
this stood in a semicircle facing his direction
at first glance this appears to be a lynching
indeed
they all stood in a row here and looked at the tree
that's fucked up
oh some solid detective work there Kim
okay so
I wanted to level up
well let's get a look at this character sheet here
wield raw intellectual power deduce the world okay
our intellect is really bad
our psyche though
to influence ourselves and others
okay so I'm thinking that we just railroad the PSYCHE
and just forget everything else
like all I want to do is influence other people
so that I don't need an intellect
I'm okay with where my physique is at
it's just barely enough to move me around
so I think I'm gonna go with psyche here
just going off gut feelings
there's an info button when you have a
skill highlighted
where am I where am I looking at
ah there we go
Inland Empire is the unfiltered wellspring of imagination
emotion and foreboding
it enables you to grope your way through invisible
dimensions of reality
gaining insight into that which
sight can't see
what's really going
what do these enigmatic riddles mean for the world fate
at high levels Inland Empire animates the inanimate
you'll have conversations with your clothing
conversations that may change
the course of the investigation
if you're not thrown in the looney bin first
with low inland empire you'll be a void of imagination
and character
and how will you shape the cosmos
good distribution though
low logic and calculus is rough
I do like the visual calculus
like I want to be able to just scope shit out
intuitively
reconstruct crime scenes
follow my gut yeah
charm men and women play the puppet master I'm pretty
I almost always I go for charisma
connect Station 41 no I don't give a shit about that
intimidate the public assert yourself
no intimidation
is a little too showy for me I want to be
deceptively convincing
work your mirror neurons
check that up
empathy
breaks into the souls of others and forces you to feel
what's inside
it enables you to notice social cues
others may miss
perhaps a hidden sadness you could coax out a little more
like we did with Sylvie
a strange joy from someone who should be bereaved
or a hidden resentment that
could return to harm you later
this seems like I have to go with this
this is like therapy
skill
any stat any low stat is not ideal
all skills have their uses
good thing you can modify them with gear
so our empathy is actually pretty decent
I think we need something in intellect
I can't be this dumb
practice the art of persuasion
aw that yeah
electrochemistry has been a good skill
maybe I should reward it it has been
where is that
electrochemistry see animal within you
the beast longing to be unleashed
to indulge and enjoy
enables you to take drugs with fewer negative side effects
it also enables you to better investigate lurid matters
if you need to understand a chemical breakdown
or talk to someone blasted out of their mind
understand sexual dynamics
electrochemistry is there to guide you
at high levels electrochemistry makes you a man of unrestrained  pleasure
an unrepentant lothario
who leers at people with a bottle of speed
and a plastic bendy straw in either hand
but with a low electrochemistry you'll be too innocent
to be effective
without a working knowledge of drugs and sex
the city will be difficult to understand
okay so it's intact there
I I can't be this stupid though
I think I have to go with persuasiveness
because that goes along with empathy
debate make intellectual discourse nitpick and win
enables you to break down arguments
and hear what people are really saying
I think I have to do this
if I'm roleplaying like a drugged out
failed therapist turned dirty cop
which I think is
what this playthrough is going to become
like I try to be a therapist
but
I was too like married to my own impulses and
the way I understand people is too chaotic
and I actually maybe I
understand them so well that I can't help but
exploit them
so to protect myself and everyone else from that I
uh switch to a career where I
where I have an immediate sense of authority
over everyone else
as a cop
and I throw my weight around that way
that sounds like a good
character profile
so I'm gonna go with rhetoric
let's level that up
how many
points do I actually have
just one
all right
could also save points for skill check
stats of passive rows too okay
all right so this was
a good way to just get started here
I'm going to pause my recording and then we'll decide
if we actually continue
but I want to be able to break these
recordings up into chunks
like I don't just want to upload like a
6 hour thing to YouTube
so yeah
this is going to be our first little chapter here
we've gotten a little bit of a grasp on who we are
where the fuck we are
what's happening
we've got Kim in the mix Cuno is there
he's an asset that we can rely on later
and I guess what we're going with is
failed therapist turned dirty cop
who is sort of on
the needle of whether or not he wants to be
an addict or not
so with that said I appreciate you
enjoying this first look at Disco Elysium and
we'll see where things go from there