hello
and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
on today's episode
we're going to address something kind of unavoidable in a game like this
which is what are some of the crossovers between politics and mental health
and kind of some personal struggles I have about integrating those two subjects
i'm sure there will be a lot of discussion about this in the comments
just note that this is all recorded previously
I think I'm gonna probably make a dedicated video
it's some point kind of like compiling my thoughts a little more
but yeah we get an early look at kind of where my mind is coming from on this
aside from that
we have a very special moment in this episode
which is finally we're going to reach the end of our first day as a detective
it's taken us a while
and we're going to take another look at how
Kim and I's relationship has been developing
over this very challenging day
and see if there's actually some things we've become quite close on
so all that's coming up I'm excited to get into it
let's do it
all right we
are gonna talk to Kim
we should think about calling it a day maybe
the nights are still miserably cold this time of year
I haven't paid the cafeteria manager for the damages yet
you should take care of that then
but I don't have the money
(let's) talk to him anyway
an officer of the RCM shouldn't be sleeping in the street
we'll figure something out
though he finds this situation frustrating
he is doing his best to not make you feel any worse than you already do
I respect that Kim
yeah his Kim has won a lot of points with me this
these chapters of our stream
okay let's see if we can reason with this gentleman
can I help you
but I don't have another option here
yes have you got it
can we come to some sort of arrangement
that arrangement include you pay me
what we already agreed
you owe me
Kim is about to say something
let him lets do that
I understand your predicament as the manager however
I feel I must remind you
that we are here to conduct an important investigation
that also affects your business
that's a good point put the squeeze on
forgive me for saying this
but your colleague seems more committed to drinking and
establishment sentence
he shrinks back a bit under the lieutenant severe gaze
I mean no offense it's really nothing personal
I just have to protect the interests of this establishment
kitty
hold on I still have my key you know
good luck trying to use it
he taps his foot on a against a metal box
that's installed in the back of the counter
all the locks have an electronic component
they have to be unlocked down here with a master key
before your guest key will open the lock
sorry my cat is chewing on the wires of this thing
all the locks have an electronic component
they have to be unlocked down here with a master key
before your guest will open the lock
I don't really want to break the door down but
this conversation isn't going anywhere is it
not until you bring me the money
come on man help me out
I might have something in my motor carriage
we can use when you're done here
I really didn't want to resort to this
the man is thinking
oh lieutenant
we're done here
yes have you got it
does that arrangement include you pay me
what we already agreed
you owe me
i'm an honest cop
i'll pay you back tomorrow
as a police officer you must understand
that I cannot take you at your word without evidence
shit
evidence being money
you can't stay here without money
what if I break the door down
oh wonderful try to do that
i'll have to call you an ambulance
shit
not until you bring me the money
okay
damn it
I might
I really didn't
oh lieutenant
okay let's go check it out
what disorder what I diagnose are detective with
I would diagnose him with alcohol use disorder severe
which the diagnostic code should be F1020
and I would also diagnose him with
either a chronic major depressive disorder or
persistent mood disorder
I would not give him borderline personality disorder no
he does not have not in
the range of things that we have done
nor anything that I have told him to do
represent like a borderline case to me
no DSM-5-TR right now until they updated again
borderline would be like severe attachment issues
putting people on pedestals
taking things very personally
like I would never stop asking him questions
seeking his approval his validation at the same time
like while we're doing that we are looking for earnest ways to self reflect
and that's something that takes a lot of work
in a borderline case to get to
so I would not he does not have a boardline personality disorder
I don't actually see any like personality stuff
like personality disorders are a
it's not just like
like you can overcome depression right like you can
do a lot of work on personality disorders
but it's like your lens
through you see the whole world through
and it's a failure to cope with things
in a healthy and productive way
but to a point that like
it just needs a lot of intervention
and what I'm finding is that the character we're playing as
will be able to overcome his issues
through lots of self reflection
earnest conversation
discovery of his past self
and integration of the positive parts
and acceptance of the negative parts
like I find that he will be able to do a lot of healing experientially
indulging in self harming behaviors watch out yeah
that's true
self destructive mean we don't know
if he's been self harming like
explicitly
but for example
right like I would see
the behavior of someone with BPD in that conversation with Gart
not submitting to the idea
that I will go find another way to do this you know
that is consistent with a moral responsible like ethical code
moral code social code
I would just be
lot more persistent and confrontational
what about the amnesia ah
I mean
my dude just
I don't know he's lost his memories
I don't really know a lot about amnesia or anything
hey Abydos welcome to the stream
okay let's check out what's in kim's motor vehicle here
inside you see a set of steering levers a radio microphone
a pullout toolbox
and the soft glow of the fuel preheater cage
I have something here we could sell
look in the back in the suspect transport enclosure
transport enclosure regular people just call it the cage
I think it's some kind of schizophrenia
these voices and hearing objects sound abnormal too personalized
so it would not be schizophrenia because
for it to be any kind of schizophrenia
schizoeffective schizoid personality
like the kinds of hallucinations
when you're diagnosing that you have to ask the person
like do you hear voices
and they might say yes
and you might say do you hear these
voices like out in the world
or are they in your own mind
if they're in their own mind
this is not a hallucination right
these may be intrusive thinking
but like that's not a hallucination
those are your own thoughts and he has personified these thoughts
I don't know if that's a diagetic thing like
if he if we were to talk to the detective
would he say yes I hear volition
or would is that just something the game calls it
so no it wouldn't be anything schizo typal in that sense
he is aware their internalizations
he acknowledges he's personified the tie
yeah we haven't heard much from the tie
I guess that would be a hallucination but yeah
we haven't heard the tie speak
do you think the BDI would be helpful
a BDI would be is always a good idea
I think that he's depressed for sure
okay he's got something in the suspect transport enclosure
let's look
the cage at the back of the motor carriage
looks rather uncomfortable
four shiny hubcaps are stacked against the seat
the silver edges sparkle in the dark
well but for example
when we hear inland empire and it like talks from
somewhere is that in his own mind
I guess actually there is something to be said
for like when we heard the corpse talking
this could be a hallucination
we didn't really get to investigate like more
that could be a schizophrenic thing yeah
I don't know that's not really like my
wheelhouse
so I could be wrong on some of that stuff
but you can also have hallucinations
and not be like diagnostically
ah schizophrenic
right like I've hallucinated things before under stress
which our character is very much under frequently
four shiny hubcats are stacked against the seats
I confiscated this for a little while back
we can take them to the pawn shop down by the matines canal
okay so there is a pawnshop
what are those things
they're spinner hubcaps
frivolous things you put on your wheels
when the wheels come to a stop
the caps keep on spinning
there's no real use for them it's just for vanity
okay
I like how he does the spinning motion with his hands
that's a nice little bit of characterization
a vanity he wouldn't mind
what do you mean you confiscated them
a couple weeks ago I stopped a young man
for going slower than the speed of traffic
turns out he was some coalition official's son and high
so you took his spinners
I took them and arrested him for driving under the influence
so kim's got a he's got a flexible side to him as well
hmm
I would have confiscated them too they're mesmerized
that they are I was going to take them into evidence
but they weren't necessary for conviction
he never asked for them back
um did you want to put these spinners on your machine
no no
that would be silly I just I don't know why I kept them
it doesn't matter I couldn't put them on this MC anyway
a cup with spinners that would be outrageous
yes outrageously cool
he flashes a smile barely visible in the dark
there's a little bit of that fun personality hiding in there
ah
ah this is this is
my heart is breathing
I'm sorry you have to sell them because of me
that's so fitting for us
and I feel like is an arriving at a genuine point in our relationship right
I know that there's a lot of people who have been sort of confused
why I wasn't like immediately sold on Kim
not Brady the human
I have liked him just fine from the beginning
but like my character I've been saying that he
that we're not trusting him
because I'm legitimately waiting for like
real moments where this is put to the test where like
I'm asking myself like does
who benefits but not in like a conspiracy sort of way
but like does he benefit from
is he doing this just because he
this is about the case and we need somewhere to stay for tonight
or like is he actually showing genuine interest in my well being
and this time I feel like he is
and he's and I'm picking up on that like he's willing to put this
he flexed his own morality to get these things
because there was something in him that enjoyed them
and he's willing to give them up for me like
I'm able to perceive that as the character now
in a way I don't think my character would have perceived that at all
yeah he doesn't have to do this he doesn't have to do it this way
and based on like the narrative of I just
gave back the pendant to Lena
like I am now primed after that experience as the character
to recognize that people do not part ways with things of value easily
when the trade is purely emotional right
like Lena cares about me she was willing to do that
Kim must care about me if he's willing to do this
they're not like heirlooms to him but it it was something that he
collected
flexed his own you know professionalism to get them
and now that he is giving them up for me for this is quite in passion
I feel it's only right that we apologize to him for this
as I said they're useless anyway
I should have remembered I have these earlier
but thank you
okay
we're becoming closer
there is a path forward for Kim and I
and I think that he's okay with this as well
it's doing just as much good for him to do this for me
I don't think I need to deny this the way I felt with Lena
you said something about a pawnshop
yes there's one 100 metres south of here
I think it's called Roy's Nest or something
if I'm not mistaken it should be open late
items that can be pawned at Bird's Nest Roy's appear in your inventory
under the items tab
you can pawn these items when talking to Roy
thanks I appreciate your help
the lieutenant nods as you take the spinners
thank you Kim
see like
here's another thing guys you know
the game has like such a compelling way of telling a story
and I want to engage with that as much as possible
and for me I would have found it less compelling
to follow the initial impression that a esprit de corps gave me
that like we're immediately buddies
I think it is so much more interesting to know that
we struggled to reach a point of understanding with each other
that there are ignorances and prejudices and
stupid impulsive behaviors that I have chased
that Kim has not abandoned me by the end of the day
and that the final act he's making for me is to like
give me somewhere to rest
the fact that I have put him through all of this and that he has seen me
try to show bravado by
like how fucking pathetic is it that my character
is so desperate to feel okay about himself
that he was like trying to show his authority to a child to Cuno
what does that tell you about how broken I am as a person
and that since then I have been looking for more sufficient outlets
healthier ones
because I realized in that moment how pathetic that is
not only did I not succeed in making Cuno think that I was cool
but I also showed a side of myself that is not the one I want Kim to hold on to
and so I have tried different things
you know I revaluated my sense of authority
I actually went back to Garte even after giving him the slip
to make good on what I owe him
and to look for earnest alternative means to provide him
with what I what he justly deserves
I have tried displays of violence
displays of intellectual power plays
and I've also chased you know
narcotic impulses
and throughout that Kim has not abandoned me
and in fact he has only shown me more empathy
it started when I failed to catch the coin toss
and he just picked it up and gave it back to me
and it leads me here to giving up something that
has the potential to make his world the slightest bit more enjoyable
and that he's willing to trade that for
my personal security
that is a show of genuine compassion
and it is something that my character desperately resonates with right now
I am so glad to have fought for these things though
than to just like yes we're best friends from the beginning
I think that's just not as interesting as a narrative
do you have other psychologists on discord as well
uh yes
my good friend uh Edgar
is on the channel psychiatrists he's also on twitch
you should go check him out he's on Twitch and YouTube psyculturists
I'm gonna link it
surprisingly he's not live right now
here is his channel
on your discord well
psychiatrists is on my discord
oh he's been sick dang
psychiatrists aka Ed is my in real life Kim
legitimately
let's do this
let's go pawn this thing we'll do our debrief
and I think that's where we'll end the stream
because that's a nice little narrative tie up
and then we have completed our first day
so I think he said goes south of here correct
this is weird because I thought I had a map of the city at first
and then now I don't have one
kind of odd
well let's just investigate
there we go in here that way down the road
got some trash
I don't
door I saw what door
oh this one okay
let's check out that trash first what do we got
fingerless gloves come in handy
let's inspect this
make sure it's safe
okay let's go in
what do we got
some kind of machine cash register okay
mostly military wear
a bust of a woman the plaque simply says DEI
in the dark a film projector is whirring away
you see rows of toy soldiers
guarding the rest of the trinkets displayed on the table
some on horseback others in rags
others yet in bright blue uniforms
all are stern and unyielding in their duty
try to find something pretty and cool here
then use it to win her back
okay and then empire is coming in with
something kind of contradictory
because it's been pretty avoidant of my past
but I guess what I'm seeing is
something else
I definitely have some sort of relationship that I feel resentment towards
I'm gonna have to ask it to clarify
yes buy something nice a figurine
big men on big horses clad in lamella armor and carrion flintlocks
the kind that would mow down a line of enemy soldiers in the blink of an eye
frankenigerian knights
I used to be very serious about these guys
a long long time ago
so it seems like this is like
my intuition about what Kim thinks
because it's chimed in a lot recently on that
that's how you understand cop culture
not just Kim but other cops
so cop shivers that makes sense
let's check out the uniforms
they‘re not all blue these figurines also wear gold coats and caps
complimented by orange trousers
they are variously posed wielding swords and rifles with bayonets
wait this looks like a Rene
the old guy who was playing petanque
let's just ask a question
which ones
ah those yes they are
I find the paint job a bit gaudy
but children like the bright colors indiscriminately
inspect the figurine
this set of soldiers isn't meant to look impressive
a few have rifles but most of them carry pistols
some even shovels and tall sticks
are these even soldiers
you're probably talking about the revolutionaries yes
yes--they are soldiers revolutionary soldiers
I think their poverty has been exaggerated for effect
when you place them next to the royalist
it doesn't seem like they could possibly win
these replies
I don't know I'm not really understanding
what this is talking about
you're probably talking about the revolutionaries
they are soldiers
their podger poverty has been exaggerated for effect
so I don't know is he suggesting they're like propaganda or something
okay yeah I must be like
again guys sometimes I'm just gonna like choose responses and
I don't know
sometimes I just choose them
and I'm not really thinking about like what they mean that much
I like that it gives me this option I respect this
I can't comment I don't know what this is supposed to rip
I don't like either set very much to be honest
but there are many parents among my customers
when you get four options they're usually the different systems
that's what I mean I'm like this is so out of my depth
this kind of stuff like I
just want to talk about like
people and feelings and emotions and
man when I wade into any sort of like other subjects
I reveal myself to be a fool in them
he seems to have his own take on the conflict played out in perpetuity by these toys
might be interesting to find out what it is
let's do this try to find something cool
everything you pick out seems
faded chipped and sad somehow
most of them are just broken toys
okay maybe we can try again some other time
any the anime figs yeah that'd be great
what's this
we're getting reports of
*normal* *reasonable* *temperate* political opinions
somewhere in Martinaise…
I don't want to engage with this
I'm sorry I know that this game is political
I don't want to
it's like legitimately terrifies me I do not want to talk about this stuff
must have been a false alarm then
not not engaging with it no
I'm not interested
it's like half the game
please understand that this is not an exhaustive like
commentary on this game or
like I'm not analyzing everything
you know like I just want... just don't want to do that
I'm just a therapist
I'm not able to like give smart commentary on that stuff
I know that there's a line that crosses over with like
my character is
developing a sense of himself
and like maybe a political ideology aligns with that
but like I find him
you know much like myself like
I am ignorant of these things
and what they brought or what the broader things represent
so like me
my fear is that like I end up pursuing a political path
that I find at the end I totally don't align with
I don't know if I'm a centrist
I genuinely don't know
you know I spend my days talking to people about their feelings
I do not engage with this stuff in real life
it makes me like it's too heavy for me in that area
I just centrist
look if this is not the playthrough for you I understand
whoever is out there watching this that really wants the hardcore political stuff
I'm just a therapy guy
sorry I look I am sorry I really am the sorry cop
how do I FEEL about politics
they make me anxious
do you want me to do this
okay do you want me to fucking do this right now
my behavior is deflecting
it's avoiding
it's minimizing
it's rejecting
uh it's apologizing
it's explaining
it's intellectualizing yeah
I don't know what else what am I doing right now
I'm hiding
I'm um
I'm pretending
I am
yeah apologizing
I'm doing a lot of this stuff okay
and what am I feeling
I'm feeling anxious
I'm feeling
fear
like
inadequate to comment on this
I'm feeling I don't know like shame shame for not knowing it
yes I'm feeling well resistance is the behavior yeah
sure I'm feeling like
I'm feeling in some ways tired like
I'm tired of
like not knowing this
and like the thoughts that I'm having are like
I don't want to talk about this
this isn't what I know
they're gonna think I'm stupid
I'm gonna say something wrong
you know I'm gonna offend someone
someone's gonna stop watching because It's not interesting
I'm not interesting
I wish I was more interesting like
how does it make me feel
it makes me feel bad it makes me feel stupid
but like guys I just don't want to fucking talk about politics
I don't know anything about it
let me distract you with my knowledge of therapy
what else can I do
am I turning into Kim a little bit
I just said no to the no politics politic option
look you know I have gotten rather comfortable with the phrase like
I don't know enough about that to have a strong opinion on it
maybe that's like I don't know week or something
like someone out there is saying well why don't you just learn
why don't you take an investment in learning
like I mean sure it'd be cool to understand this stuff but like
I don't know
the only thing I see resulting in like
if I were to pick a political system
and only for the sake of feeling less inadequate
what am I doing
I'm like diving deeper into an ideology just to avoid a feeling of inadequacy
and I immediately alienate anyone who does not subscribe to that identity
so yes maybe I want to be centrist
because I feel like picking an ideology just makes me...
it's just given me a false sense of inclusion
and maybe like I am not so inadequate
but I know what it results in
it results in like animosity from everyone else
it results in like how could you think like that
that's stupid
I don't want to get into that of that
like I'm a helping profession that's what therapy is
political discussion is like
it's all combative to me
I'm not interested in it
(chat)we'll try this session at another time yeah
what did I tell you what did I tell you at the very beginning
this is one part livestream one part self therapy
and I have already earnestly reflected on
many of my own unknown internal biases
and
it been very displeased with some of the discoveries
but that's why you know
it's important to be open about this stuff
like I will just be honest with you and tell you that
you know talking about politics makes me feel really shitty
because I don't know that much about it
and I will embarrass myself if I talk about them
and I already have like a huge insecurity about like
being an impostor
you could just role play as a certain ideology
it does not need to be based on your personal opinion well
well I'm already having kind of a hard time like
getting across that a lot of the decisions
I'm making are just role play and not personal
but I don't know it's tricky waters to wait into
typical Martinaise streetlight sits among assorted floor and table lamps
you got me in the anxiety goldilocks it's true
street light is that a street light
yes officer
as you see it's in perfect working order
let's let our gaze run over
the light pole has been carefully cut
and the wiring has been redone and attached to a standard indoor plug
the light buses fakely but persistently
it was brought to me to be altered
we are not here to investigate the theft of city property
you have to admit it's rather clever what he's done with it
I mean it's kind of cool I'm not gonna say it's not cool
but we don't need it right now let's talk to him
if you don't mind please put the flashlight away
some of us have photonic sensitivities
oh my god he actually responded to me having the flashlight out
I love that
I was I was rather like expecting it to come up in
he's actually like waving his arms around as well
I was hoping it would come up in the in a scene
where I'm like interrogating someone
I mean that's kind of what I'm doing right now
what have you got to hide
no this is my thing
how can the game know that I've been doing this the whole time
okay sorry
I do appreciate it
we're sorry cop
not above apologizing
let's put the flashlight away
we have enough self awareness to know that it is off putting
and we have no reason to be
confrontation with this gentleman
it's not often that I see officers from the RCM in my pawnshop
I do really hope you don't just disregard the political stuff
in this game though
because it ties together with psychological issues
and character flaws with a political ideology
it corresponds with both the player and the other characters
you'll get an incomplete picture if you don't
at least take it into account
I just don't really agree
I have never once ever in my life as a therapist in any session
ever in real life and real practice
come to the conclusion
that the way someone feels about something
is a result of their political ideology
never that has never like I have never been in that kind of dialogue
where someone's like yeah you know I feel really bad
when
when I'm talking to my friends
I hope that they listen to me
but when they start talking I kind of tune out you know
and they feel really bad about that
like where would I pull out the idea that
how does this make you not a communist
you know like
it's never happened
and even when I'm talking about
like those things that I talked about the social determinants
that is the extent I will talk about politics okay
and this is my task for you okay
this is homework
for chat and YouTube
you decide what political system I have
because I don't know what I would call it
but like
social determinants of health SDOH
they are anything non medical that has an influence on...
mental health okay so like
there is a genetic component to mental health
there is a genetic component to certain disorders
there is a genetic component to addiction
there are
developmental things to consider
was there any substance use
while the individual's parents were pregnant with them
any delayed birth complications
any delayed milestones
like walking talking going to the bathroom party training
any delayed milestones in terms of you know development of like
preoperational thought
cognitive things right
like these are all
medical determinations of health
emotions thoughts behaviors etc
social determinants of health are for example
like access to health care
access to education
what sort of like resources does a person have to
become educated about things right
those have an impact on mental health
because if someone does not grow up with access to education
like let's say Frittte girl okay
she is someone who has clearly has the aptitude
for intelligent discourse about things like technology
right like if she had access to education
she would not be stuck in a dead end job
working against tons of the non social determinants of health
that make her fucking miserable
now could she pay for school on a Frittte salary no
so you know look I lived in
Denmark for a number of years
and I went there from the United States
and the things that I encountered there you know as a young 17 year old
were very interesting to me right
like I ended up going to school with people
and I would find that like other 17 year olds had their own apartments
and I was like how does that work and and they would tell me
well you know like the the government's giving me a stipend
because I'm going to school like I'm getting an education so it's like
they're giving me a stipend to encourage me to continue that education
and I'm not paying for the education the education is free
and for that reason I'm able to like have my own apartment
and those are social determinants
because I found that these individuals of 17 years old
were far more independent than myself
I found that their self-esteem was accelerated
by having this kind of early freedom and responsibility
and that they were primed to deal with issues like financial management
what are safe boundaries to set with people about having them over
how should you regulate your schedule better
your sleeping your dieting going to school yourself
these are all social determinants
the government provided them with free education
they provided them with a means to take care of themselves
and these accelerated virtues
that I find many adults well past the ages seventeen
have not had the means to develop in the United States
in fact much of my job is spent
working with people who have never had the kind of opportunity
to develop those very simple foundational life skills
people of thirty years old people of sixty years old
and they have decades of inbuilt shame
because they don't know how to wash their clothes properly
they don't know how to cook a healthy meal
this has had severe impacts on their mental health
it has resulted in
deeply maladaptive behaviors like
dependence on substances to cope with inadequacy
homelessness
a struggle to maintain healthy relationships
all of these things right these are social determinants
so yes I have political opinions
and they are informed by real world experiences
and they're informed by seeing alternatives to the political system that I live in
and being shocked and very disheartened by
how some of those systems wrap around mental health right
so like that's the extent of my opinion you know
people's lives are
affected by these things
but I don't give a fuck what the system is called
I don't like I genuinely couldn't distinguish like
the ideologies of communism versus free market capitalism like
I don't know capitalism is
I do not have the language to discuss this subject like I
yes I just want to help people
and I know that part of that job is being informed about how
at the top of the chain a political system influences mental health
I feel like I've demonstrated I am aware of these things
but again they just don't come up in my work
for the person who does not know how to wash their clothes at age sixty
I am not working with them on like
so how should we change your ideological opinions to change the political system
that's what social workers do right
social workers are people who are a lot more involved in that kind of advocacy
I treat the behavioral symptoms
and I treat the emotional outcomes
which are informed by a
distant understanding of political systems
so
yeah like look I this is why
this is why I like didn't want to talk about it because
it like it makes me it
I don't find that the discussions it stimulates are really what I'm after
when I'm talking about psychology
my interest is in showing people interesting ways to think about their own lives and
maybe learning a technique or two to improve their day to day you know
I just don't have the the goal of like
pushing narratives forward about bigger ideas like that
like that's for someone else
that's for someone else who is more equipped more of research more studied
I've compiled my personal experiences into like a framework
that helps me do my job for a certain kind of person
but I don't have the
capability or interest really in like
developing that narrative here on this space
I hope that explains where I'm coming from
I don't know if it does
but yeah hopefully it does a little bit
I know there's a lot of comments here
so don't get mad at me if I um
don't engage with the political side of this game
I have my reasons and they're just not really what I'm trying to do with this platform
this is a therapy show
that's why I find fun I don't find politics fun
I find them to be grounds for arguments
or even if not arguments just like
disagreement
I'm misunderstanding the game's angle
okay well
I don't care
I don't care like I'm gonna play it
how I want to and can you know
I think you're going to be fine generally
the political stuff that's relevant to the personal analysis
tends to be how your personal issues and beliefs
can affect your political and world beliefs well
like at the risk of going on another tangent
schemas are you know
another way I might formulate the ideas around core beliefs
and some of them are uh you know we have schemas about the self
about other people and about the world
and that's where those would come into play right
like one of my schemas about the world
is that education should be free
I don't give a fuck what political system that makes me
it's just a fundamental belief I have based on the absolute tragedy
that I have personally witnessed and deal with every day
of people who have had not had access to that means
and I see no justifiable economic reason
in the United States
for that not to be a reality
and as I have said that
I have probably lost a portion of the audience who thinks I'm a fucking idiot
uh because that's just not how the economy works
but that's why I don't fucking talk about this
because that's just not what I'm interested in and I don't care okay
I'm gonna continue playing the game because I'm gonna like I don't know
it's just not benefiting me
what can I do for you
this courtesy is not insincere but he prefers being alone with his projector
just watching the movement of light across the walls of the show
I am very interested in the fact that he's in this dimly lit room
his pupils are very dilated most likely
because that's what happens when you're in a dark room
your peoples dilate to capture more light
and here I came in like with my fucking flashlight
and it he responded to that
they fucking thought of everything
sorry I feel like I'm interrupting you sorry cop
let's ask him if he had any trouble lately
I haven't had any problems myself
though some of my customers have complained
about inconsistent law enforcement
who are your customers usually
good question Kim
all kinds of people come through here
locals travelers people looking for a deal
people looking for a keepsake
people who are terminally bored
interesting perspective friend
as you can see
I have a wide selection of goods for everyone to choose from
look around typical vacuous consumers objects
see like that's
I'm just gonna follow the game here
quite the collection I *may* have something to add to it
it keeps me entertained
as attention is drawn once more
to the play of light and shadow on the walls behind you
entertained he might be high
if he is on what
hmm
I guess there's no harm in asking
okay he definitely *is* high
whatever it is you've probably done it and many other things besides
I can't cut through the jumble of sensations to get to the answer
a guarded man like him wouldn't tell you if you asked out loud
okay
that's fine let's not judge
let's ask him if he carries any weapons
maybe mine has passed through these parts
someone else came here earlier today asking the same question
I promptly sold her the gun you pawned a couple days back
I pawned my own gun shit
what *sold*
the lieutenant shifts from one foot to another alert
I fucking told you guys that I
i'm pretty sure I claimed much earlier that
I wanted to stop being a cop before this
and that I may have done something purposefully
to remove myself of the burden of my own memories
let's investigate that
you are
you were adamant about getting rid of it officer
said you were undeserving of a service weapon of the Revachol citizens militia
I knew it fucking knew it
and I don't like keeping guns around the shop for long
off-the-charts photon emissions the unhealthy kind
this does expand my view of the character because
consider it like this
the person I was before was not in the possession
of the kind of virtues that we are developing now
virtues of an interest in self discovery and apology
of connecting to people of responding to gratitude and empathy
like with Lena and Kim so far
my character may not have felt that he was deserving
or even capable of being a cop
because without possession of those virtues
he could not stop himself from taking advantage of his authority
which again would fit into the ideology of like everything is authority
but we are starting to like ourselves a little bit more
we are starting to find there is virtue and apology and connecting to others
and we are building upon ourselves
a small tower of helpful core beliefs
and so we may feel slightly more comfortable being in the role of
someone who can help others and provide some kind of structure to the world
this is fascinating to me I love everything about this
he's not telling you the whole story it seems he's trying to spare you
I want to know more though tell me the whole thing
you weren't quiet yourself officer
what was I like
you were very distraught
you said the gun was a threat to your life and
that you can't *trust* yourself with it tonight
and that you need the money
man that's fucking sad
it's sad but also so
if I am working with someone who discovered this about themselves
their instinct maybe to feel like just as I did like that's really sad you know
but a meaningful interpretation of this
could not leave out the fact that
even when he was indisposed of his own self empathy and
was fearful of you know not being able to like be safe
like he's a danger to himself or others
there was a
there was something in there that made a good decision
right it's resulted in a lot of problems but
like there was a self preservation instinct of
you were trying to protect your own life
there was something you cared about it
that you didn't trust that
if you pushed any further into that depression
that you would have gone too far
like there is something about self empathy there
when I said that I don't normally buy firearms
you put the gun barrel in your mouth and sort of sucked on it
then I agreed to take it
yeah that's heartbreaking
you sucked on a gun good
very normal
I'm so sorry you had to see me in that state
we don't have to talk about it any further
look how much empathy I'm displaying here to see that
not only this is exactly what I meant about
the apology not being purely transactional
and why it's a good thing that he is apologetic here
he is not looking for forgiveness he is genuinely sorry
not just for the way this makes him feel but he is telling
he is able to tell how
upset it made Roy as well
like that it was not fair to him
in a very displacement sort of way
I brought to you emotions that you were not deserving of
empathy towards himself and to Roy
we don't have to talk about it anymore
that statement is not for us
it's for Roy
like we can tell this is making him uncomfortable
and we're also burdening him
like we don't want him to feel pressured to tell us
about the horrible state we were in
you know
if I witnessed a close friend do something
that I knew they were going to regret
you can bet that while I'm telling them I'm gonna try to soften up like
yeah you really did that
you know
because I don't want to harm their own self image
it's a hard thing to do and
our guy is invested in Roy not developing that same thing
like this is really human to say this
no apologies necessary officer
was the buyer a policeman too
she didn't seem like a policeman
although she kept referring to herself as a Pig
which was odd
I found her interest in the gun a bit
obsessive but I was just happy to get rid of it
and of her
truth be told she was terrifying
right so let me get this right
you sold your sidearm issued by the citizens militia
and now a civilian is running around the streets of Martinaise with it
miraculously
his face does not reveal what's happening inside
I'm so glad I have empathy as a trait here
there's only one explanation she must be one of my rabid fans
maybe she's a vigilante
I don't like it either
I'm sorry I'm sorry I sold my dad
yeah it's not good
I do hope we manage to clean this mess up somehow
while also keeping our focus on the murder investigation
this mess he means your mess
man
any idea where I can find this buyer
my apologies officer
but I have no idea where she was coming from
or where she went
a needle in a haystack
there is nothing you can do about it right now
you'll just have to hope Evrart wasn't lying
and the union can track her down in time
let's ask him about Evrart
maybe shady looking guys came in here yesterday
looking like they're just taken off their Wild Pines overalls
they asked if I have a police weapon to sell
I told them I already sold it
so those guys have no fucking clue where my gun is those liars
they went their way it was a trip
but you know
all sorts of people come here
asking for all sorts of things
maybe Claire really is tracking down your gun
at least now I know how I lost my sidearm
let's talk about something else
um
you might be able to investigation
I doubt it But I can try and answer any questions you may have
know anything about the hanging
I do my best to keep my distance from all manner of butchery
bad for business bad for everyone
I like a good neutral stance
no one likes to see what you have to see every day
no no they don't okay
the pawnbroker's gaze is already fixed on the dancing colors
there's something I'd like to sell
we'd like to sell these hubcaps
yeah we actually did talk to Claire already
Roy takes the hubcaps from the Lieutenant and inspects them
the spinners appear iridescent in the dancing light of his pawnshop
yes these are very very good
did you defraud some foreign prints for them
jumper mesque banger
no matter I'll give you 200 real
Fucking finally we got some cash and we can have a good sleep
no one was defrauded or gent I assure you
the lieutenant explains
as the pawnbroker opens the register and counts the cash
of course I meant no offense
200 real for you officer
delight for doing business with you do come again
thank you
here is the 100 real you need for your bill do not waste it
the windfall is a small consolation
anything else you're thinking of selling
uh I don't think I have anything else to sale
another time perhaps
okay let's leave
all right let's go to bed
and we'll debrief with Kim and then
we will call it an evening
and that'll be our nice little narrative wrap up for the time
my cat is also demanding my attention
what
all around you rain falls on the great city of Revachol
rain drips from the eaves and floods the gutters
washing the filth away
the spring Thor must be here the snow is melting
looking up at the sky cold water dripping from your hat
what do I see
grey sky like great battleships
clouds colliding with one another
rain falls down on the world
how does it feel
humid your coat shields you from the rain
while the city shivers around you
what's in the west
sheets of rain over the water
a flight of stairs leading into the ocean
wave after wave washing the coast of Martinaise
with its motorboats and gently swaying reeds
the ruins of a half sunken sea fort
crumble on an inlet
beyond the bay of Revachol ghosts rise into the sky
shivers as prose as like
like a sweet dessert
who are you ghost
the skyscrapers of LA Delta the financial district
faint golden light seeps from the office windows
will you ever go there
will I
no you are just one of the hundreds of thousands
who watch them rise across the bay from Martinaise every day
urban coastline
rain drip it off Etonite covered roofs
cinderblocks left over from half finished construction
a defunct research and development building
once seized by revolutionaries
an old wooden church stands on stilts above the water
and beyond that
Coal City end of all lines
run your fingers through your dampened hair
your hair is an oily mess
flecked with ash from neighboring coal plants
smoke stacks rise somewhere in the distance
God's beautiful
what's in the east
the great gates of the industrial harbor are locked
a chill runs down your back
you shatter like an animal trying to shake water from its side
shake them again
his trauma lives in the body
um
sometimes you can see people who have experienced lots of trauma
have a certain kind of shiver to them
like their body is
still in a perpetual reaction to a car accident
and
some therapeutic styles are very much about learning to
release some of that tension
it's powerful to see
let's shake those shoulders
you shudder looking down at your feet
dirty rainwater runs veins into the plaza snow
two green snakeskin shoes stand at attention
of the mosaic paving of the plaza
Cape side apartments
tower blocks crowd one another
4.46 millimeter bullets still lodged in their war torn stone walls
hallways collapsed from the mortar hits of a war that was lost long ago
clotheslines go to waste in the rain
radios play
and closer to here
a yard rain falls onto the roof of a woodshed
the lingering odour of decomposition mixes with that of damp soil
what's in the south
a traffic jam
rain thrumming on the roofs of motor vehicles
inside drivers watch water streaming down their windshields
the statue of a king shudders he too is cold
the canal bridge has been raised
what's on the other side
the road ascends a raised motorway loops above the ghetto
beneath its concrete columns a sea of rooftops
woodwork and tar stretches northward
four story buildings as far as the rain can fall
the snows melt in Jamrock
why am I not there
to be in Martinaise where no one goes
at the runoff point of a long forgotten canal
in the whitest part of town
in the shadow of the day the revolution failed
God damn that's
God this writing just hits
standing in the rain
looking north where Jamrock Rock City stretches inland
my God
shudder look further
in the rain swept distance
above the rooftops of Jamrock
a repurpose silk mill stands perched above the motorway exit
precinct 41 hunches in the rain
your vision blurs you wipe your face with your hand
the rain stings your eyes making you look up and blink
Whats above
coalition aerostatics hang like apparitions under the cloud cover
way up there where rain forms rotors flutter silently
your sight clears
collapsed storm drains old sewage systems flooded with rain water
hidden weapon caches from the revolution
doors leading down to loroyam
the catacombs to which for three centuries
they delivered the blue blooded dead
motherfucker I love that
this rain will not let up anytime soon
at least we are dressed for it
let's keep moving
okay let's go in
let's complete our first day
we've been through a lot
we've been through so much
can I help you
so about that money I owe
yes have you got it
I have it
here it is sorry for the trouble
I hope I give
I hope I have an apology in every dialogue now
great thank you officer that's all I wanted
payment for services rendered
if you continue to stay here
I just ask that you please pay your nightly bill in advance starting tomorrow
okay he's not sorry about his behavior for your sake
now that you have money
he really wants to make sure you're not angry with him
the electronic lock to your room has been disabled till 9pm tomorrow
please pray for each night in advance starting tomorrow
20 real per night
we can swing that there's enough trash in Martinaise for that
I'll take your room here too
oh Kim
you want to be roomies
of course always happy to have offices from the RCM as guests
anything else I can do for you
so here's the thing I do not want my character to drink
but I believe that that would be part of his
like he's been through so much
and I think that he would still have a hard time
not considering a drink a reward at this point right
a thesis I have been trying to get across is that like
addiction hijacks your rational decision making and it
we get mixed up in our priority structures and our behaviors and
just the same way that I was talking about we develop
like complicated misattributions of emotions with behavior
our guys still has a strong relationship between relief reward and alcoholism
so we're also going to drink
because that is probably our belief
do I have a shaker in my hand
is this is this a shaker
he sounds irritated
you sound irritated why all I want is a drink
am I wearing a little bowtie
am I wearing a bowtie and doing this
am I smiling
do you see me smiling and shaking my little shaker
I mean I thought he was a bartender
do you know why
that's right I'm the cafeteria manager
what you want is a goddamn drink
how is that so hard to understand
you know what the impact of rejection is stronger than
than the impulse to drink from my guy right now as a sorry cop
I I abandon I'm going to abandon the
the desire to drink because I am
too ashamed to ask further
like what
goodbye
oh the bartender quit because of me that's pretty bad
okay let's go to bed
so how do I do my debrief with Kim
this is the door to the room you redecorated
just a moment you had some questions earlier I believe
and besides we should discuss our progress on the investigation
let's go out to the balcony
all right let's go
it's time
we've made it through a day
the lieutenant is silent for a moment he listens to the traffic hum  then
where shall we begin we should talk about the investigation
first and foremost
but I also remember you wanting to discuss the RCM
I didn't know you smoked Kim
I have a cigarette every night
when I go over my notes it's something of a ritual
hmm okay
he looks so devastatingly cool with that cigarette
cigarette is a great idea I think I'm going to have one
your call detective
again I only have exactly one every night
look we've got to have a smoke with Kim
okay we
we're starting to develop a solemn relationship with him
and in fact I would say that like
maybe seeing that Kim only smokes one cigarette a day
as we are starting to see him
as someone who is not only a good cop but is also a good person
maybe it is possible to live this life be a cop
have good morals make good decisions
have empathy and be disciplined enough
not to chase every impulse that we have
so what better way to connect with him
the city trembles with its remaining lights
people are rushing home running away from home
smoking sleeping singing in the shower
edges of dining tables hands aprons flicker through windows
before the lights go out
how did you get so cool Kim
you mean this this isn't cool
it's an unnecessary trial of will and unhealthy
keeping the habit within the parameters he's given himself
takes a lot of focus
it would be easy to simply quit
what did I just say
fuckin' volition is speaking my language I knew it
I knew that it would be like
a demonstration of discipline to our guy
right then the debris
it's been a long an eventful day
it has we have been through so much
how do you think today went
we performed a cursory initial inspection of the victim's body
then you shot the body down
which was quite a shot
it was cool wasn't it Kim
I was inspired by your confidence in me
I think that's that's honest
what is true right now is that I was inspired by kim's confidence
I admit I wasn't sure whether I should give you the gun
but I'm glad I did
your shot enabled us to perform a field autopsy on the victim
we found some things we can really work with
this is the moment that I have been waiting for
I have been waiting to hear his thoughts on all that has transpired
and to not just give me the report
but like to connect to me as a human you know
and I can see that that's not something Kim finds
like the easiest time doing either
but when he does boy does he
I still feel like we missed something
but it's up to the boys in processing now
we did perform a thorough search on the crime scene
that's great
I would say it was a little too thorough in my case
now as for interviews
my list of people to talk to here in Martinaise I mean
the initial interviews yes well we talked to some people
including Evrart Claire
a daunting adversary if there ever was one
he wasn't particularly forthcoming with useful information however
i'm a little intimidated by him honestly
he has stuff on me
well we will have to work through that
Claire also helped you
how should I say
remember your name
that's a relief
I don't know how I feel about my name
we're getting honest here
that's normal
it's best not to give it too much thought
Kim is sounding very much like my therapist now
we tried to interview the Wild Pines rep
but she asked us to do something for her first
fine so be it
okay
I have a feeling Joyce knows how dangerous this situation really is
we have to get her to talk to us
above although today was exhausting
what´s with all the *running*
you run a lot
is that a standard precinct 41 practice
I have a really good theory about why you're running so fast son
just you wait until we get up tomorrow
because our sympathetic nervous system is completely deregulated by addiction
I don't like to waste time
my mind moves fast
I don't know why I do the things I do
I genuinely don't
it's impressive
especially for a man your age
and in those heels
nice shoes by the way
I like the green
goes with the orange
thank you Kim
so what are our powers exactly the RCM
they're quite limited actually
the power officers of the Revachol Citizens Militia exercise most *frequently*
is imposing fines of up to 1000 reál for offences
in accordance with an interdepartmental schedule
why not more
the RCM's primary role is to ensure safety
we are not really supposed to play any part in the economic structure of Ravachol
see
Kim doesn't want me to get involved in politics either
wouldn't that be an easy power to abuse
yes although indirectly
as citizens can always request records from their local station
officers of the RCM have been known
to take bribes of less than the prescribed fine amount
it undermines trust in the RCM
so we're allowed to basically find people for things up to 1000
so
maybe we can get some money that way
but it does undermine their trust in us
okay what else
we can arrest people  of course
but rather than bringing someone in directly
it's preferable to serve a *station call* slip
it prevents confusion and overcrowding
how can you be sure the arrestee will show up
you can't
those who don't show up become fugitives though
and have fewer legal rights when they are eventually caught
it's about power projection
thus far they seem to mostly show up
when power calls you you come
but power itself is a fragile trick of perception
man authorities get away with words
what if someone resists
we are permitted to use whatever force we deem necessary
even lethal
what happens to the people we convict
we don't convict
we arrest and send them to Coalition Government courts
in Couron and La Delta
the prosecution works off our testimonies
and records which is why it's paramount to keep them
wait so if I kill someone while on duty...
you have to supply compelling evidence
for why it was necessary to use lethal force
in these cases your partner is usually your witness
*not* a good position to be in, by the way
internal affairs handles these cases thoroughly
by cross examining you for inconsistencies
it is hard to *cover* for anyone
which is for the best
have you ever killed anyone Kim
yes
the last time was four years ago
he says it matter-of-factly and moves on
have I killed anyone
that's an improbability
perhaps even impossibility
of course you've killed people
it's somewhere down there
melting in all the drink
I don't know if I really want to know
there's a lot of insecurity still in this process of like reintegration
think a part of me would want to
know everything
so that I can narrate to myself that I
I put as much honest effort into this as I can
but I would also feel like
what good is knowing that going to do for me
if I already feel that it is wrong to do so again
Precinct 41 is known for...
a higher-than-average rate of police violence
he's not judging you
he's respectfully acknowledging the difficulty of working in your precinct
authority with the rare empathetic take that he's not judging me
who makes all the rules
the Coalition Government and the Moralintern more broadly
the RCM was formed by the Coalition Government
to restore order in the International Zone after the Revolution
so we did
now we attempt to maintain that order
no more no less
or perhaps it is better to say we were allowed to form
it's a point of contention
whether the citizens of Revachol
or the Coalition Government founded the RCM
I don't have an opinion
silence
a great comment to such a conundrum
the Moralintern what is
the Moralist International are the world's largest political organization
you know who they are
they have been running this place after the Revolution failed
okay
if I didn't know how would you describe them
they are a union of center-left and center-right parties across the Reál Belt
our Coalition Government is just one of its many projects
they also run the ICP EPIS
most inter-governmental organizations in the world
oh jees
what do you think of them
Moralintern are a fact
I try not to have opinions on facts
until they change
and it doesn't look like that's about to happen
it is more than that
there's some kind of affection in him
the better not to ask
the lieutenant breathes out a chestnut-scented cloud cigarett smoke
and looks at the city he sworn to guard
what do they believe in
they are Dolorians
they believe they continue the humanist project
set forth by her innocence Dolores Dei four centuries ago
others say they're just technocrats
who was Dolores Dei
a historic figure
the author of the modern age
you will have to look elsewhere for opinions
the subject of humanism is too abstract for me
okay can I just say
Kim is so real for that comment
this I connect so deeply with this
there's something that I have been trying to explain myself
they are subjects that are too abstracts for me like
you will have to look elsewhere for opinions
the subject of humanism is too abstract for me
substitute humanism and politics for me please
you you will have to look elsewhere for opinions
the subject of politics is too abstract from me
I fucking love this comment like for real
thank you Kim
for you she is something painful
though it's hard to say why
what is their *symbol*
interesting question
it's a blue forget-me-not
their moto is love compassion self-discipline
I think you can gauge what they *want* you to think of them from that
have fun being confronted with politics for the rest of the game
no
I'm not going to engage with it
I'm not really interested in it
nor do I have anything of value to say about it
something ominous
something even a little feminine but in a *strict* manner
I like that I like that Kim as a feminine side
do you
no not really
on second thought I don't have an opinion yeah
my kind of police officer
ah okay I am starting to develop the crush on Kim
but it's only because we fought for it that I know it's real
the lights of the orphan district are reflected in his glasses
the red and golden orbs of the motorway sliding like pearls on a string
from east to west as Revachol commutes back to the suburbs
tomorrow is Tuesday
Monday is over
what an intimate moment to share with him
Kim won over Brady by being anti-politics
should have seen this coming
who would have guessed
Kim will embrace Brady's approach even if chat won't
see the game has has brought me validation
Kim has given me clearance to not have an opinion
because having an opinion makes me feel bad about this subject
and it only invites raw tense emotions from others
which I am not prepared to deal with in my vulnerable state
say nothing
just look into the sweet night with the sweet boy
the dying lights of the city shimmer below
slowly like luminous clouds
they pass on his lenses
the lieutenant looks at his slim cigarette
contemplating the next drag
this *soldier* is the highlight of the day for me he thinks
this little stick right here
they really don't like us here
and the mouth on that kid Cuno
it's different inland
in Jamrock and the GRIH
why *are* they like this
what's my school of thought in psychology
I'll talk about that later
it's our fault for leaving this place to the dogs
to the union to the company
not daring to come here more often
it's like I told you -- this place is an orphan
fallen between the cracks
what did I say
what did I say about the kids
I find that I am more and more right about my initial assumptions further we go
and in Jamrock and the GRIH
we run the city
west of the river is RCM land
it's incredibly hard
human beings are ...
but we are in control and it's worth it
the organization works
our systems work
if they didn't the city would disintegrate
night captain Ptolemy Pryce steps into the yard
a piebald horse waits by the motor carriage
chewing oats out of an oatbag
seagulls fly overhead
the sky is black
captain Pryce wears a black suit and a standard patrol coat
as he mounts the horse to head home
rows of houses on either side hunching over the sidewalks
and precinct 41 with its dome roof growing distant
around him the streets are silent
a kid on the corner waves at the captain as he takes the turn on Perdition and Main
the horse neighs
the captain nods back
there is something here
a young child seeing perhaps
life isn't going to be miserable when I become an adult
thanks kid he thinks  he's grateful
I hope our investigation will help improve the situation here
at least do some *good*
but I wouldn't count on any drastic changes in our lifetimes
thank you for this
yeah it's getting very cold now let's go
okay I'm a little smitten now
okay
now what we will do is go to sleep
and then we'll end this little chapter of our adventure
everyone falls for Kim no exceptions
I was never against it
but I genuinely did not think it was earned narratively psychologically
from where we started
we started in this room
not as an empty slate okay
like someone who is a blank slate
does not like
does not do the kinds of things that we saw from my character right like
in the beginning all that we were chasing were impulses right
violent tendencies
substance related tendencies
simple...
gratification structures like getting money
being able to buy something
being able to buy something that can give us a small sense of relief
winning confrontations with people
like that's what it was all built on
because those are like the quick paths to building self esteem
but they are the wrong paths to building self esteem right
this entire time I've been trying to demonstrate something
just about like
we do not always do what is in our best interest
just because the thought to do so is available to us
you know
the thought to be close to Kim
has been available to us from the very beginning
but that does not mean that we pursue it freely
just like we don't in real life ever
it takes time
it takes trial and error it takes pushing boundaries
it takes realizing what people's clear intentions are
and it takes like realizing that
although it is effortful it is hard
it's not easy work to do the right thing or to be the right person
it is worth it
when we have someone who reflects that it is worth it
next to us
so I do think it was inevitable but not for free
so for that reason I'm glad that we developed
we're starting to develop a relationship with Kim
that feels very earned
with that said
we pause at the doorway
we glance towards the mirror on the far end of the room
and we consider looking into it
and we decide  not yet
the bed is cold and not particularly inviting
but it's yours
the sheets look awful
doesn't matter
crawl in
the sheets feel at once coarse and clammy against your skin
the bed sags beneath your weight as you stretch out
and finally close your eyes
and then
and then sleep doesn't come
why
maybe it's the beds fault
rollovers
a little better
colors scenes and half-formed phrases still litter your mind
part of you is still trying to solve the case isn't it
who killed him
something to do with
what was it that  the lieutenant said
union
and it's gone again
your thoughts lost between the slowing brain waves
no more thoughts fall asleep
your breathing steadies
a great silence washes over you
until your eyelids twitch in your sleep and images...
images start forming
well is this like a dream state
oh it's a disco
oh fuck
do you remember the scent of your childhood
what *is* this
what it says on the can harry
answer the question
I remember nothing
do you remember your wife's hand on your face
I left
I believe that we left
oh no funky baby you *stayed*
it was the rest of you that left
or you just stood there
with one hand on the bottle and the other on your dick
watching it go
tell me
where are your friends
human beings have friends Harry-boy
where the hell are yours
shit
this is this is
it's dark
I think this is more true to make character
they were only cramping your *descent into the abyss*
now they're gone
three times gone and never coming back
all of it
you failed
you failed me
you faild Elysium
what is Elysium
everything
the pale and the isolas
on the surface
the outer magnetosphere
burning furious truth
a thousand years of written history
you really dropped the bow Harry
four point six billion people
and you failed every single one of them
you really fucked up
oh my god
I've talked to you before
something tells me we have been here before
no Harry
you were just talking to yourself
that's all you ever do
even in your dreams
and the act is wearing thin
the spots of the disco ball fade around you
you'll be back in those cold snake skins in no time
sweating up the bed
stinky boy
I can come back from this
you're not coming back from shit
thrashing around in that high conductivity stay of yours
bumping into things and acting like a *clown*
who are you kidding
i'm trying to solve trying to solve this case
it's the one thing I have in my life that gives me a clear objective
because everything else is an open fucking road
and I do not know how to navigate it
you're trying to what
I can't hear you
this is just a word dream now
jumbled up garbage
the pictures are gone the bed rises to meet you
a thin sleep like state
more glass then velvet *grinding* in your head
so-something is wrong
sleep shouldn't be this bad
this dry
this un-nourishing
there's something wrong with your thoughts
some kind of new type of hangover
there is definitely something wrong with our thoughts
oh yes party boy
and it's worse than the one before
just think of the shit you saw
here it comes too so soon already
a silent alarm goes off in your head
like clockwork barely let you sleep at all
time to get those clothes on Harry
time to go to work in the shit factory
well there's a lot there
good going buddy
what the hell was that
oh just a dream
you have ones like that all the time
you feel even worse this morning than you did last night
what is going on with me
you mean why are you so tired
too tired and down to even think
it is worrying isn't it
you can't be a detective like this
detectives need to be able to  think
why is this happening
it's just that your heart has finally pumped all the *speed*
out of your system buster
time to get some more
don't do that
stay strong
the hangover will wear off
you don't need to keep doing this to yourself
okay so what I find interesting is that volition...
is shiming in more often to counter electrochemistry
um and half light as well like I said though
volition in our real life
the self-interest mechanism is very hard to listen to
takes a lot of effort
we're going to try to not do drugs
we never wanted to do them
this has not been a
like this has not been a play through about
taking drugs for their benefits
there's been a play through about the dangers of addiction
and how they hijacked our moral priorities
so this is the thought
the thought can be anything it can even be in our best interest
and we may still result in a behavior of relapse
which is probably what we'll end up doing
are you sure
ready to live as this pathetic shell of yourself for days
basically a week
let's be honest two weeks maybe three
you won't make it
half the town will be dead by then
you will be fired
that's a lie
I can do this without the speed
half the town won't be dead
part of me thinks that
again like you can have a very virtuous thought like this
and still result in a
behavior that is against self interest
but what is fresh in my mind right now is
the conversation I had with Kim
that is starting to shape some of my core beliefs to
even if it's not true
I can still believe that
like I'm not catastrophizing
catastrophizing is like when
when you go to the extreme level of consequences for even small issues
which is definitely a habit of our detective here
but we're going to try to not do that
that's a lie I can do this without the speed
suit yourself slow sad shell-man
see how you do without your spark
we're going to see
okay
again
we'll look at the mirror
we'll think about it
and we'll move off
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it consider giving it a like
and letting me know what you thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a little bit earlier if you support the channel
either through Twitch or Patreon
links to both of those and the community discord are in the description
thanks again and I will see you next time
bye