hello
and welcome back to our therapist plays Disco Elysium
let's play if you're new here
hello my name is Brady
I'm a therapist
and we're doing kind of like a long forum
psychoanalysis of our main character
and all of the people that we meet in
our twisted weird journey through Revachol in Disco Elysium
so on today's episode we're kind of getting
deeper into the analysis
and actually kind of targeting our companion Kim
who at least in my play through
and the way I'm sort of role playing this character
we don't have like the most trusting relationship with yet and
kind of getting into the psychology of like
what does it mean to
want to trust someone
but not be sure if you can yet
and how does
someone who has a lot of like prior trauma
like our main character does
actually evaluate whether or not someone
who promises to be there on your side
is actually trustworthy in what they say
so today I'm going to give you
kind of a mix of psychological theory behind this idea
and also
how I would actually address something like this
in practice as a therapist
so with that is
let's continue
so
what do I need to do
I need to ask okay I need to solve this murder
I gotta be honest like the
the murder is like the lowest priority thing
to my character right now
I genuinely believe that if I'm this character
the murder is just a vehicle
to discover more about who I was
and in that process
reckoning with the idea that I may have done something
to myself to try to forget that person
and here I'm spending a lot of time
trying to figure that out
I could go do
I can go do the autopsy
I have the gloves and I have the form
maybe I should do that
the size of it to do list
I know I'm just collecting tasks
jam mystery
I kind of want to go see the body
let's do the autopsy real quick
I have all the ingredients I need
let's see what happens
maybe it will tell us something provide us information
the rotting man lies on his side
with his eyes looking straight through you
the belt is still around his neck
his body is supplying and open to intrusion by autopsy
Let's do it
the lieutenant adjusts his glasses and takes a deep breath
what is a *field autopsy*
come on officer
you know what a field autopsy is
you've done a hundred of them
let's get in there
there truly is a time for everything
even for yellow gardening gloves
however they are lacking hygienically
I suggest you *get in there* in limited capacity
I mean when I need you to
until then I should handle physical contact
and you should take notes
okay
I'm agreeable to this
this is collaborative
we're setting clear roles for each other that's okay
I don't need to be in control all the time
that's right
you *knew* it because you inspected your ledger
the lieutenant is relieved you know the protocol
okay a little bit of trust building
"open your ledger at the field autopsy form"
let's follow this
the dead man stares in silence as you crack open the Ledger
the bright red paper is covered in boxes and lists
describing the condition of his skin and organs
in three parts
okay
above those
an eleven field info form needs filling out first
it begins with
"assistant"
the corpse is indifferent to your scribblings
just lies there
the next box says
"coroner's case number"
KK57
dash
dot
write it down
N/A next
N/A
roughly 50
the corpse looks ageless like meat on a hook
teeming with opportunistic microorganisms
letting out of foul-smelling diamine compound
your eyes turn watery
Mondial
the pudgy mess of curdled meat
looks neither *Mondial* nor anything other
fucky-fucky
forgot she was there
male
pigs gonna have sex
all right I'll
nor does he look male
with his pregnant belly and indistinguishable face
we're still going with March 4th 51
what else
nine *body identified by* is non applicable
*10 case number* is the same as the coroner's case
KK57-0503-0815
listens motionless
with the cargo belt still around his neck
"evidence of treatment"
none at least not after the initial examination
a strange word *treatment*
"what exactly *is* treatment anyway"
interfering with the body's position or wounds postmortem
I mean I did hit him with a crowbar
aren't you a *cop*
you're leaving a weak impression here
say something sure handed
oh shit I'm losing I'm losing respect again
it's okay to be unsure
my mental states are in competition once again okay
is it okay to be unsure
I mean I've pretty much been that this entire time
and Kim hasn't abandoned me yet
in fact there's some security in it
he could have been
what if he was dead before they hanged him
they'd *have* to have incapacitated and carried him over
this men was more than a match
foreign trained dockworkers
your central nervous system recognizes this gesture
it's the *stations of the breath*
ecclesiastic religious in nature
a holdout from pre-dolorian burial rites
it takes him two seconds to perform
then
somewhere in Jamrock North
a small wood shed behind Rozenkrantz Row
lieutenant Nick Feuerbach
puts his hand to the chest of a small corpse
no larger than a monkey
it's raining outside light drizzle
there is darkness in the shed
elsewhere yet an obese female sits in a wicker chair
her silhouette ball-like against the window
outside Grand Couron
the day is turning dim for Sergeant Mack Torson
hand extended he approaches
to make sure she is dead more than anything else
this game has such a way of painting a picture
it's gorgeous
the building is tall
seven stories wind-wrapped in solitude
most of the apartments are unoccupied
this was a suicide
the other an accident
the small one
and so all across Jamrock Coal City G.R.I.H
42 deceased persons found today
42 stations of breath
we should start to postmortem
the corpse cannot feel Kim's hand on his chest
it no longer meaningfully interacts with its surroundings
a thicket of boxes and lists on red copier paper
tries to answer "why"
"external examination summary"
let's do that
the deceased wears armoured boots and white briefs
the make of the briefs is babroudine I think
let's see
C it's happening
babroudine yes inexpensive
size M color white
the disappointment is palpable
the red haired thing was expecting something (more lurid)
the boots are ceramic
vitreous enamel
they're fused to his skin from blood flowing donward postmortem
removal of the boots is left for processing
I still want them
after the autopsy before the body is taken away
there will be a *window* of opportunity
after the lieutenant has gone to sleep
I hope this has helped you my liege
my liege
I like drama
drama is putting me in a position of authority
tattoos
the upper torso is covered in a single continuous tattoo
resembling a national patern
it reaches from the right shoulder to the heart
the ink is blue and white
the assistant has a colour photograph of the markings
to be added to the case files as document A1
the photo is taken on the scene using a Triggat Mini
the deceased has a cargo lashing belt around his neck
tied with a hangman's knot
colour yellow length 3 meters
there is a buckle on the other hand
well nourished athletically built measuring 1.80 meters
generally consistent with age about 50
preservation is good
ambient temperature below freezing
so if I'm imagining like psycho-dynamically
what is my character thinking as
he watches Kim do this right
I'm developing a framework for
what an effective cop looks like
and I am very quickly realizing that it's not me
like my character is stupid
look at how my intellect measures up like
there's no way I would be able to deduce any of that stuff
and so a character in this position
may start feeling like
both feelings of inferiority but also dependence on Kim
right
I'm gonna start feeling like okay well
there's a part of me that
trusts that as long as I'm with Kim
I don't need to learn these things
so there is some security and uncertainty
but at the same time I would also feel like
like empty of critical thought with Kim not around
body hair is light brown
distribution is consistent with age
the deceased had male pattern baldness
hair is combed back short
lividity is consistent with hanging
the head is congested
contrusions are present on the head chest and thighs
consistent with stones thrown postmortem low velocity
fucking low velocity
you think Cuno doesn't know what you're talking about
velocity was fucking Max
talking shit about Cuno's velocity
in addition
there are bitemarks on the face scalp and chest
consistent with predation
write it down but amend for high velocity
it's all for Cuno
well I'll find another way to please Cuno
small folding knife
with the other hand pulling on the belt
he starts cutting into the polyester
the stench is horrid
after a while it's obvious the material cannot be cut
there's too much of it
we need to remove the belt
so we can get to the ligature mark
you got just the right tool for that
oh yes I'm prepared
the handman lets out
a joints little bubble of rot from his nose
always good to think ahead
now
look at all this shit
I just collected all this shit
and I'm fully assembled the kit that I need to solve this crime
let's go
we need to cut the belt to see the lgature mark below
carefully with as much precision as you can
see my pig is gonna fuck his head off
no he ain't your pigs are boring fuck
hey I could I could submit to the Cuno this time
look for a good spot first
the belt is equally tight
around the whole circumference of his neck
swelling over the edges like white bread
rising from the yeast
I mean what do I lose if I say this
I might as well
gain some ground with Cuno while I'm here
you are this pig is Cuno's
yeah
being Cuno's pig has a steadying effect on your hand
go with the flow man
yes
yes I increased my chance since let's go
hey look
things work out when you submit to the Cuno
roll the fucking dice
after some deliberation
let's go
thank you Cuno
you squeeze the rubber handles together
sweat forming on your brow
the knot is slashed
another cut
and the belt falls apart like a flower bouquet
revealing the dead man's neck
and the dark red ligature mark around it
here's the thing okay
I don't have to actually believe that
all I know is that I was able to manipulate that kid
into giving me a self esteem boost
I don't have to actually believe I'm his pig
the rope rises to a point
leaving a gap in the ligature mark
the suspension point is in the back of the neck
as it ought to
this is where its grip on the curdled meat is gentlest
pulling up
haemorrhaging is observed on the skin
above and below the ligature mark
the mark is well pronounced
consistent with a drop from 1 or 1.5 meters
write it down
normal contour
abdomen is protuberant pelvis intact genitalia
now it's gonna happen C
Cuno
this is clearly what they've been waiting for
ever since the autopsy began
the lieutenant is trying to make it as boring as possible
and look
Kim is gonna miss out on his Cuno bonus okay
you need to hype these kids up it will steady your hand
genitalia is male and unremarkable
no evidence of injury
let's get an inspection on them ourselves
the dead man's penis is average sized
congested from the downward collection of blood
the testicles are uneven in length hanging underneath
the genitalia is greenish
marbling is present around the crotch
way more descriptive than I needed
you should touch it
uh let's let's inquire further
ah yes your hunch before
we can have a semen analysis requested from processing
if that's what you meant
I'm trying to get a psychic read yeah let's uh
not you weren't officer
that would be preposterous
just write down
that we request a semen vegidal and anal fluids and analysis
the corpse with his pants down
does not have an opinion on the subject
all he has is genitals and a deathly odour
look if it entertains the Cuno
doesn't feel like anything
a cold spot under your gardening gloves
unremarkable and unalive
my pig's so fucking ill right now
see I told you
it's just all to win back favor with the Cuno
ya pig's pretty sick I gotta say
this wasn't necessary
what's going on here
why are you doing that
I I am detecting
yeah how can they not understand
I am trying to right my wrongs with Cuno
because he represents my fractured child self
and Kims as well
okay Cuno is the most important character in this whole fucking game
so far
like he represents the outcome of this society
like you want to talk about politics
you want to talk about the economy
you want to talk about mental health
okay well we could talk in circles about the abstract
connection between these things
but the result of all of these things being
broken is right here in front of us okay
it's a child born in this world
and the kinds of things that he has to deal with
in the worldview that he has
like he is the culmination of this entire society and
the way that people coalesce around ideas
like Cuno represents everything okay
what am I doing if I'm not trying to help him in some small way
the lieutenant is unaware of what's happening in your head
and why you're touching it
he merely expects you to write down his notes on the man's genitalia
so you can move on
write it down
back is symmetrical and intact
upper and lower extremities are intact
but asymmetrical
there are all combat injuries on the right hand thigh and hip
all roads lead to Cuno okay
if we're gonna do anything productive in this play through
we are going to heal Cuno
thus we will heal ourselves
bullets have bitten little pieces out of him
it must have been excruciating
especially the hip
before you is a temple of pain that knew little tenderness in life
in addition I see smaller residual scars
too numerous to count
covering about 30 percent of his skin
should I interpret that
we have a real museum here
battles wars
yeah well how would I know that
if I didn't make some physical contact of my own
last item hands
hands you say let's pick up that hand
his flesh is cold icy
pleased to meet you
where are you from and what's your name
my name is Raphael Ambrosius Costeau
I'm only fucking with you
I know where you're from
from Coppodocia
and your name
is Il Cobo
what can I do you for
Il Cobo di Coppodocia
are you a temple of pain and a stranger to tenderness
God damn
we've met before
I've touched your genitals
you get me Cobo
I feel like you were once for tenderness and kisses yourself
but then shit went south
and now you're ahead of even me on the pain front
we should do this more often
be close like this I mean
I agree
no sign of injury from struggling
were we expecting any
maybe I'm just not seeing them
honestly this tension is making it hard
for me to think at the moment
jot that down
that's all for the external
well done what next
external examination completes
let's do an eternal examination
central nervous system
I have nothing
do you have anything on this man's central nervous system
uh well I
would say that we're gonna see
lots of things in the autonomic nervous system out of regulation
you don't even have a joke
fuck my guys too stupid
muscoskeletal
church fluid is coming from the mouth
not injury related
eyes ans tongue protuberant
hyoid bone let's see
with his eyes almost closed
the lieutenant puts his hand on a dead man's throat
and begins to massage it gently
a rotting smell erupts from the mouth
purge fluid runs down his lips black and viscous
yeah jack that fucker off
the hyoid bone is fractured
the rest of the muscoskeletal system is intact
unremarkable
write it down
respiratory system
begins to pry open the dead man's jaws
he stops to exert more force both hands are used
oral cavity shows no lesions
the victim has received dental implants
possibly after a combat wound
mouth swollen
hemorrhaging present in mucosa of the lips and mouth
from here
it looks as though the clown faced man is screaming
the tendons of his jaw are torn apart
hyoid ripped from the force of the lieutenant's hands
let's get a scope on that guy's mouth
no scream
no sigh of relief rises from the darkness inside
it's humid there
sickly sweet air unlike anything living
you feel like throwing up straight in that mouth
I feel like throwing up in his mouth
no you don't you can keep it in
you can keep anything
yes yes I can
you manage to suppress the contractions
trying to empty your stomach
all it takes is concentration
through it you see nothing but more meat and darkness
there are ancient mysteries down there Cobo
ask me later
okay
hepatobiliary present in mucous
right it down
hepatobiliary N/A
are you hepatobiliary expert
no
neither am I
that's it
same for toxicology and serology N/A
alright
cardiovascular
the body exhibits lividity in the lower extremities
feet hands and neck
visually consistent with the hanging
just write down
digested semisolid food in stomach
voilà
let's keep the voilà
what's next on the list
description of injuries
we have bite marks
contrusions on the head and chest
and the ligatory Mark encircling in the neck
you'll need three fields
leave a fourth one too
all right let's check out those bite marks
head chest and scalp bite mark injuries
predation by birds has caused damage to the body
autontologies does not need to be consulted
write down your opinion
(and) your opinion officer
oh he's asking me my opinion
okay Kim
giving me control back here
fatal injury by seagulls
okay it's not a fatal injury then
that's right what's next
okay I feel that
(so) the scalp bleeds from a postmotem had injury
a stone
the injury does not have the rim of an early inflammatory response
a perpetrator on the scene has confessed to causing its postmortem
that's a lot of writing for my guy to do
has confessed to causing it at maximum velocity
look at that
even Kim is getting on board with the with the Cuno
look if you make Cuno happy things work out
coagulated blood sticks to his scalp and chest
where the countless stones have hit the dead man
beneath the description of injury two boxes
nonfatal
right
next
ligature mark
oh what's the fourth for
just in case
okay
(a)dark red the braided ligature mark encircling the neck
with a gap on the nape measuring
let's say 7 centimetres
the hyoid bone is fractured
the cervical column intact
I see hemorrhaging on the skin
above and below the ligature mark
depth of the mark 1 centimetre
no signs of clothing on the neck
what was that
sort of breakthrough
on this
breakthrough imminent
do I need to do anything for this
guess not
just wait
below the note two customary boxes wait to be ticked
the man's head jerks to the side
the ring around his neck is visible
that's it we have established cause of death
it's not much and it leaves much to be questioned
but it's a start
let's wrab this up
I pronounced this philodepsy over
let's do a deep breath
let's ask him how it went
well we established probable cause of death
some would say that's the goal of an autopsy
we requested a test to be run on the genitals that was de règle
the results should arrive in a couple of weeks if we are lucky
I will not hold my breath
we were comfortable with the list of injuries too
we described them all in detail
what is there to say
given the circumstances
it was a professional field autopsy
oh yeah well done master detective
maybe a drink is in order
maybe it is
now you see that worries me
you will die if you drink
you know that don't you
you are proving a useful detective
the organization would miss you
oh of such sweet words
coated and mistrust
please get yourself together
the lieutenant from Precinct 57 thinks
all right
we'll drink later we won't tell him
we won't invite him
we'll drink with Cuno
I need a copy of that autopsy form
then I will drive him to Faubourg (for processing)
there you go
he's thinking
did I miss something
perception legendary
you know I have to try this 3%
I can't resist it
let's see if I can ask him
shoot loonie roonie
love or communism
don't even I have to
you said love to kill you
but when you fell down you said it was communism
you're misquoting me Roonie
I said communism killed me
love
did me in
ancient mysteries
Gobo mi Lobo
in the gift horses mouth
tracts and wakes and waterways
ancient materials buried
but to where brother
just a small gulp away
my beloved gobo
a small gope away
he wants me to get drunk
the blue heart
blue
that's good shit
you'll love it
just press down
and fuck it open like you always do
oh my God
fuck it hard
copopo the clown
he means force it'll work
come back later coppo
amuse yourself with my frank manners
and my mementor mori features
if possible also see me in your dream
this is a perception check
okay perception has historically not gone very well for me
where is perception
it takes in the final detail of the physical world
you're going to miss out on everything with low levels
you can't arrest what you can't see
I have a pretty low level should I level it up before I try this
or should I just go for the 3 percente
I'll just go for the 3 percente fuck it
you run your hands over the victim's cold body
his limbs his torso with its swollen organs
maybe you should be more thorough
I wasn't actually that bad though
I was pretty close
let's check out
the genitals in his breeches
continue to be unnoteworthy
you see the penis of a dead man
if you've seen it once you've already got the picture
I mean
what's the harm in trying it again
there is no need
we have been through with the genitals
you know what Kim this actually isn't about you
you can't shake the feeling that
there are more secrets concealed in the flesh before(you)
yes yes there's more
okay well
we're in livor mortis here
he is disintegrating
we need to refrigerate the body
we want to conduct another examination
and we need to do it fast
if you want for this task to slowly become impossible
then yes
otherwise no
he's been hanging out far too long already
we need to ice him
not to mention the damage that
would be dealt to the force's reputation
by the corpse just rotting here(like this)
okay okay where do we find a fridge
(it would have to be)industrial in size
let's start by asking Garte at the whirling-in-rags
and the Frittte store down at the gates
if they don't know
but only if all else fails
maybe Cuno knows
you want a piece of the Cuno
want to get fucked
I would like a piece of the Cuno
only if all else fails
hurry
this is one task we cannot sideline
with every hour
whatever we are looking for will become (harder to find)
okay this is just become urgent
you'll be looking for clues in a pile of sludge and bones
yeah I can't check this one again
okay let's bag him
if you think so officer
I'm not going to object
I need a little help
for carrying him to the holding pen of my Kineema
I'll take it from there
there go those beautiful enamel boots
may they rest in processing
it's too late to take him into processing today
I'll take him first thing tomorrow
okay
well we missed our opportunity
that's all right
I'm over it
Ace's High
oh what is this
for the rest of the world
the Ace's High is just a cool Rivershore thing
politically neutral
in Revershol it still holds revolutionary connotations
also have you looked at Lieutenant Kitsuragi's clothes
he wears a bomber jacket
just like the ones worn by aerostatic brigades
and those cargo pants
could store tools for hot fixing your aerostatic
maybe you should ask him about this
could get some empathy could get some
some know how about the roots
looks like we're going to talk to Kim now
let's get Kim's opinion on where we're at with things
yes
want to talk about you
so this is where this is where my original thought
is probably gonna come into play right
like I've talked about how
it's hard to trust people when you are
someone who has historically not been cared for looked after
or sympathized with right
that's like where trust issues generally tend to
manifest in new relationships right
the reason I'm going around
with Kim is because we both have the same
job same objective
and he hasn't presented as immediately hostile to me
but that's almost even more
suspicious from my character's point of view because
someone who's immediately hostile
or immediately defensive like confirms my worldview
but Kim challenges it because he tells me he's on our side
and yet
I'm still wondering like why
why would you be on my side I've done nothing
I've done nothing to trade for that level of empathy
but here we are getting an opportunity to do that right
I now want to figure out what
what makes him
want to stand beside me
me
yes you
(I don't see how) my life is pertinent to the investigation
Kim your life is
the most important thing to this investigation okay
our relationship is the key to solving everything
work better together if we have more rapport hmm
that's a fair point
all right for the good of the investigation
what do you want to know
you don't look like other people around here
okay
I think there's something else I want to explain
before I continue with this dialog
pull up my whiteboard here
so I'm gonna give you a bit of an insight about
what the therapeutic line of questioning often looks like
and why this
the kind of dialogue that I'm gonna have with Kim
going forward is probably gonna be really important
so like
in the process of therapy right
we can imagine a
therapy session looking something like this let's say
and if this is over time
and this is like the amount of anxiety that someone has
this is gonna look pretty different person to person
but generally let's say we start a session off
and the person I'm talking to
has very low anxiety
they're talking about things
they're sharing personal history they're talking about
stressful events but
their anxiety is not very high
what they're essentially doing is like
speaking about things in a very intellectual way
they're saying yeah
my partner broke up with me
yeah I'm really upset you know that
there's racist people in the world I don't know right
they're talking but their anxiety is very low okay
this is not extremely productive for a therapy session right
we're essentially just having a conversation down here
there's a very different kind of therapy session
where I start asking questions
there's a lot of anxiety right
the person's anxiety immediately goes up
when I start asking like
how are you feeling today right
and so the difference between someone who is down here
and someone who is maybe up here right is
this I would call
intellectualizing
and this I would call being in a crisis
and so we have two very different like experiences and
sometimes you know the level of anxiety can kind of
fluctuate throughout a session
but the most beneficial psychological work
tends to happen in a space somewhere in the midst of
being in a crisis and intellectualizing right
and this is a space that I'm going to call like the
psychological work zone
essentially what I'm trying to do
is I'm trying to get someone to experience
a little bit of anxiety as they're talking about things
because
I don't just want you to tell me what was wrong
I want you to be feeling that wrong emotion
while you're talking about it because
that's where the processing happens
that's where we're actually able to identify
maybe displaced emotions
that's where we're able to identify
what's coming up for you when your
competing mental states are causing tension right
what we want is for someone to be in this zone
and so sometimes that does actually mean
like if I'm talking to someone and
they're just telling me
they're fine and they're doing okay and whatever
you're bored I'm bored
what I'm actually gonna try to do is
provoke you a little bit right
I'm actually gonna ask some questions that may like
confront your emotions and get you to feel
a little more tense right
I'm going to ask you something for example
like this question
you don't look like other people around here
I'm trying to get him to get in touch
with some of that resentment that we very rarely see from him
but we see when he talks to the racist lorry driver
right
so I'm going to try to provoke his anxiety this way
and it's very often that people will try to avoid
feeling that way and bring their own anxiety down
they might say well that doesn't bother me
it's not a big deal right
let's move on
so this may be
a process of trying to provoke and provoke and provoke
until we get somewhere where
the person is actually able to get in touch with that feeling
and say yeah
that really does bother me
okay now that you have the emotion in your hand and you're feeling it
let's talk about it now that it's present right
you're not doing this anymore you're feeling it right
that's kind of the goal of some of that work
when there is some resistance to feeling something
at the same time
I don't want to provoke them to a point where they
go into a crisis right because like
now I've pushed too hard and there's too much emotion
and this is actually the kind of person who
you know instead of provoking
I'm actually trying to console them and bring them down
right like I'm gonna try to dial back
the intensity of what we're talking about
and that's kind of how I explain things to people
why I am trying to get a reaction out of
the person I'm working with
it's not because I'm trying to piss them off
what I'm trying to do is to get them to feel
something they've become conditioned to avoid feeling right
like we have all kinds of mental defenses
this is one of them right displacement to avoid feeling things
and it's my job it's what I'm trained to do
to help you get into this zone where you can
experience a difficult emotion process it
work on it and then come back down
and at the same time
one of these is better than the other one
okay that's the real trick here
a lot of people might say well
intellectualizing sounds like the better one because
I mean this person has low anxiety right like that's
that's a good thing to
you know you know you don't have a lot of anxiety
that's good
no one wants to have a lot of anxiety
this person you know who's in a crisis maybe all over the map
but it's actually the opposite
I would actually much rather someone be in a crisis or
maybe like all over the place
because
that person has actually crossed through this zone right
the person who intellectualizes all the time
who spends all of their time not feeling any anxiety
but can talk at length about their anxiety like
they can say that they have this trauma they can say they're upset
they can tell you that they're very pissed off
but they're not  feeling it as they talk about it
they're speaking about it in this way
that person has never experienced
being in the zone
and at least the person who is in crisis
has passed through that critical area
and just needs to like kind of focus that ability right
what we want is for the person to learn how to
stabilize what they are feeling right
and spend enough time in this zone to where they can
they don't need to be provoked they can
reach this point process it and move on
without your guidance right
like my job as a therapist is to help
is to train you how to do this yourself basically
and so I always tell that to people like
we may think that intellectualizing is great
it's a great way to defend
against the uncomfortable feelings
but I would so much rather you be the person who is in a crisis
who does not know how to manage their emotions
because you've at least gotten close to what we're looking at
so I'm going to have a conversation with Kim now
and my goal is to
provoke him a little bit
and he's going to avoid that
he's going to try to
de-escalate the conversation and avoid getting to this point
not to say that I'm doing therapy on him
I kind of am but
I essentially want to get him to a point where
he's a little bit
defenseless against the very raw emotions
because not only is it gonna tell us something about him
it will probably
lead to him learning something about himself
as well right
you'll meet some characters you can't provoke
they have high defense well
I don't expect the lead detective to have the skills to do this with
where everyone right
like I think that
only now as we learn something about Kim
can we even start this process
right
it's all about figuring out when to dial up the intensity
to get people to talk about what you need to hear
yeah and and like
I will always
inform the person once we're here like okay
you know I said some things
that confronted you on that and you really felt them
what was that like right
I'll always dial it back
and we'll get to a point where we do talk about it
like in a less intense way
because I don't want
people to end the session feeling anxious
I want them to have experienced something
important psychologically and worked through it
and then to come
back down here right
you thought my character was an ex therapist
well he is right and
that's something I'm trying to infuse with
the character which is like
he knows how to do this stuff
he knows that
this is the way to get information from people
and he can't use his detective status against Kim
because
Kim sees right through it
so I'm gonna provoke him
I'm gonna try to get him to that
psychological work zone
where we find more about him
that's because I'm a half-Seolite or quarter
my father's father was from Seol
so was my grandmother
but from my mother's side
it's not an interesting topic
well how interesting
that as I say that
Kim
I tried to provoke you a little bit that you
retreat and you avoid and you withdraw okay
let's see what happens
it's a part of the world officer
a geopolitical entity and a geographic division
I told you it wouldn't be interesting
you're only making it sound uninteresting
I still want to know more about Seol
you're barking at the wrong tree
I don't speak a word of seolite
I've never met either one of my grandparents
and I've never been to Seol
I'm a regular Revacholiere
this is the moment where if I have the opportunity
I would come in here and say
what is it like for you to not be in touch with your culture
what is it like for you to not be able to speak the language
that is a part of your upbringing
that you've never met either or your grandparents
what is it like for you to
present yourself as someone who cares a lot about your culture
but to have no real foundations for that
you're not convincing me right like
these are some of the things that I might like
try to process with him here
I don't think that we're gonna get that dialogue option
but
hey Rex welcome
welcome to the street Rex so good to see you here
we gotta catch up soon
he's glad to shut down your question
yes okay empathy is coming in and
letting me know that we're on the right track
so where I think he is at right now is
I just pressed him and he avoided that
he's not quite at the edge of this right
I wonder if we're gonna be
able to push him a little bit more
oh it does say I've never been to Seol
and he seems almost proud of these things
well I think it's a false sense of pride
it's his way of avoiding that right because like
look how direct he gets with me when he says
you're barking up the wrong tree
and he says it's a part of the world officer like
we tend to add that ending on a statement like
it is what it is Brady
like we state someone's name when we are
trying to make it clear to them and we're frustrated
so like I think that him
he says I'm a regular Revacholiere
is his way of avoiding the fact that
he actually does care about
that he's not informed about his own culture
or that he's not as connected
so let's ask him about the bomber jacket now what
what this
it's just seasonal clothing
he zips up the collar
which is interesting
in his body language I would see that also like
he doesn't like that I'm observing this
he doesn't like the idea that I have
seen something about him that most people don't
where is this going
again avoidance right
not acknowledging my question
but trying as hard as he can to keep this as like
unemotional and uninsightful as possible
see Kim I have this place in my head
point to your head
where I develop new ideas and connections
interesting I think it's called a brain
okay and something happened in that brain
yes my brain suspects you have some kind of thing
with the Revolutionary Air Brigades
I do not have a thing with Revolutionary Air Brigades in particular
just air brigades okay
I wanted to become an aerostatic pilot
then I turned 10
and realized we no longer have an air force
okay
again I would ask him here at this point
as he's a little bit closer
he's feeling a little bit anxious
or he has the potential to get to the point where he's like
I wanted to become a pilot
and I realized that we no longer have one
I never got an opportunity to be the thing I want
or to be a revolutionary
or to contribute to my culture in the way that I would connect with
are you sure the revolutionary has gotten nothing to do with this
is this conversation that provocative
well it's not like
it's not supposed to sound like an argument
but just look at his responses
look at how avoidedant they are
look at how
short his responses are
and questioning of why I'm asking this
and he's trying to keep it mundane right
like he's shooting down my question
these are all signs of avoidance
avoidance of like digging deeper into something
good
he glances impatiently at his electrostatic wristwatch
see look anxiety is going up
tell me a secret about yourself
he does not like to get personal
no
I'm gonna ask again
your brain sends the signal to your lips
but they refuse the order
something is paralyzing them
you're pretty sure it has something to do with
the lieutenants eyebrow
the eyebrow is exercising psionic control over you
okay so we're getting a little anxious in our own line of questioning
what's happening to me
something the matter detective
this doesn't work if I'm also starting to feel anxious
this guy's got authority off the charts
with just the flick of his eyebrow is
able to make you is through
look at the way my character sees people
always organizing relationships in terms of authority
nothing you better hope he doesn't abuse his authority
there's a lot of it
he's one he we're not
we're not like psychologically equipped enough to get him here
that is why we were an ex therapist in this playthrough
there is just no way for us to
to get him there
but we did learn something
we did learn something about him and
we know the signs of avoidance for him
I'm just gonna silently scream
if the lieutenant were an
evil man who knows what sort of havocache break
fortunately he is a committed officer of the RCM
he'll only use his powers for the good of the investigation
but never to connect to another human
the lieutenant relaxes his eyeground
and you seem to regain control of yourself
that was tense
okay
you win this time Kim
that's correct
that makes him a binoclard
completely un-cop material if you say so yourself
yeah good thing for empathy
from my perspective though I think Kim
realized that we are so much more capable of digging into people
from a psyche perspective than the details like and
that's evident by like this is our character right
like these are the things we understand
we understand like innate motivation and mental health
we understand mind's ability to make metaphorical connections
we understand how to recognize and identify with emotions
we organize the world in terms of authority
we are able to intuit
different things through these two pathways
he knows we're fucking totally useless in this area
and that's where we sort of grind up against him but
we just showed him something that we're very powerful in
which is like getting him to feel uncomfortable
and that that's gonna be a valuable skill
for the rest of our investigation
yeah we're extremely stupid
like intellectual
okay we've already tried provoking him and it didn't work
I'm not gonna try it again this way
I'll wait
are they they're mostly just cumberson
you could use a good normal pair yourself
yeah I could fucking use some glasses
I couldn't even
spot the siggy in Tommy's hands right in front of me
do you ever talk with yourself
when you're thinking do you ever have conversations
I have no idea what you're talking about
so
does he have one of these systems
I guess is what we're wondering
chimes in with advice or warnings
when I need to think I just use my notebook
the lieutenant produces his small blue note
and idly thumbs through
a blue is from mystery
that's where his conversations with himself take place
you're super lucid yet psychedelic
you don't need office supplies to connect to your nervous system
you're special
I am special thank you electrochemistry
electrochemistry makes me feel good about myself
good let's change this subject
no response he just arches his brow
have you tried concentrating on something other than your personal affairs
there is a sudden harsh edge to his voice
like he's tired of hearing about your personal affairs
that's because Kim is the kind of person
who doesn't think that
being a good detective means knowing things
about yourself
because I find him to have an extreme lack of self insight
as evidenced by the exchange we just had
like I think that he
puts all of his thoughts in his notebook
and he doesn't engage with his own competing mental states
because he's afraid of what the fuck they would tell him to do
and that there's a part of him that is just as unhinged
if not more than we are
not a fan
what's wrong with personal fair
it's just the nature of lieutenancy
is that a mask you're wearing Kim
the RCM deploys a self style structure
called the Decomptage as its chain of command
every lieutenant is responsible for 2 sergeants and 8 officers
that means the average lieutenant has to deal with
quite a few personal affairs
even you know this
yeah
easy easy
encyclopedia
so why are you hiding Kim
why are you hiding
the fact that you have a personal life
can you help me
fine
we should get through this day first
off hours begin at 9 PM
if you are still having trouble then
I can give you an orientation
so what should I get
the case at hand
it can work miracles
oh so you pour everything into work
to avoid dealing with your personal affairs
interesting
really you look fine to me
I
have a lot of damage
the phycho-drama is unbecoming of an officer
wait what you
you're gonna call out
you're gonna call out my psyche my psycho drama
that's my whole thing
Kim it's all I got
sort of major brain damage has occurred
then you should consider seeking medical attention
you can use the radio in my Kineema to call your station's lazareth
was there anything else you wanted
you seem to be following me
fine just an observation
I don't want to tell him to fuck off
you have
a distinctive way of walking
if I were to walk in front of you
we would surely collide
what do you mean distinctive
I hope you don't take this the wrong way
it's just a collegial observation
in the 57th we call it the Jamrock Shuffle
officers from Jamrock's 41st Precinct tend to move a bit erratically
they say it's a scene clearing technique developed by one of your
lieutenants for gathering evidence
it's erratic yet thorough
prioritizes containers
why containers
containers contain I guess
I'm making assumptions
we should move on
passing along frivolous interdepartmental stereotypes
is not usually his oeuvre
he regrets bringing it up
why did you why did you say that Kim it was weird
OK
so
I feel like
we have done a lot and also accomplished nothing
from the time I left the dock
I don't know if I really
actually accomplished much of anything
I mean we did the autopsy and
I'm trying to get like
on team Cuno
we didn't investigate the union
I didn't even go talk to that person
we didn't find my badge
I still don't have any fucking cigarettes
I did get my tie back
I've done a lot of like
to me very important things
okay I'm piecing together my identity and I'm
I'm trying to figure out like
how should I be to survive in this world around me like
who do I need to like listen to who's trustworthy
what benefits do I have of interacting with Cuno
with Garte the bartender like
because at the very beginning of the game
I was just going around
talking to anybody and not really being very
like deliberate about it
and that wasn't very successful for me to be honest
yeah we didn't we didn't accomplish
much in terms of like the game systems but
this has been an important like task for me
to explore like the environments and myself in this environment
I feel like I did learn a lot about where my character
is coming from
and why he would be interested in learning about himself
I think the conversation with Lena
was really important for like
establishing a sense of like self empathy
sessing out the world
yeah
and now we know a little bit more about the person
that were campaigning with
maybe the real elysium was the friends we made along the way
could be very true
well
I think that this is where
it would be good to pause the play through again for now
I feel like this was a good stopping point
to sort of like reflect on what we learned
I realized that this is going to take a very long time
to like complete this game but
hey if it leads to interesting psychological discourse then
that is primarily what I'm going for here
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it consider giving it a like
and letting me know what you thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a little bit earlier
if you support the channel
either through Twitch or Patreon
links to both of those
and the community discord are in the description
thanks again and I will see you next time
bye