hello
and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
so on today's episode
we're getting deeper into our different character studies
and kind of breaking down like the psychological dynamics
in their dialogue and their relationships
and everything that represents terms of mental health
this time I give a lot of focus to two characters in particular
that we meet on our journey through Revachol
and one of them that
I give kind of like my deepest
psychoanalytical impressions yet
maybe also my
most unhinged character analysis thus far as well
but it is in service of
actually kind of discussing like some important things about
how the game depicts its world building and
what characters do we need to look at
and in terms of like if we look at the shape of their mental health
this will tell us a lot about
what it is like to live in this environment
with these political systems with these social tensions
like what is the result of that on the people
who are actually being brought up in this world
so emm there's a lot to get into
I'm excited to share so
let's jump back in
okay let's continue
so I think the last thing we were doing
is kind of investigating our relationship with kim here
I guess if it's a section of this that I missed
ah "cool for" I see what you mean
I thought it was something I had to click on
so let's check out Inland Empire
because that's our main skill and
I'm finding it very interesting that this was the
primary skill that I chose
especially because in the last stream
I found myself kind of disagreeing with its intrusions a little more
it says it's cool for dreamers paranatural investigators and mental creators
I don't know if i'd call myself paranatural
but I am an investigator
and I am a mental creator meaning that
I tend to make stuff in my brain
that's better than I can make it in reality
empathy is cool for judges of character interviewers interrogators
that's me as well
volition is cool for sane people
well-adjusted cops
the non-suicidal
that's kind of half of us right
authority is cool for leaders
experts of psychologIical warfare
and respect junkies
yes yes and yes
this one is cool for cops
cop aficionados
and pretend cops
I feel like that last one is us the pretend cop
suggestion is cool for diplomats charmers and sociopaths
who is a shivers cool for
city lovers the wisest of the streetwise the generally supernatural
well I do think that this has been a pretty relevant skill
to spec into because
like more so than anyone else
the...the city is a main character in this adventure
and so is our personal relationship with it right
oh is there is there a typo
oh yeah suicid*i*al
visual calculus for forensic scientists
actical fighters and math-minded people
that's why my guy is so bad at it
this one's cool for acrobatics thieves and unbearable show-offs
I find it more fascinating the stuff that
who it's cool for that I'm not good at
electrochemistry it's cool for high-fliers
party enthusiasts cops who need lightning
composure is cool for card players
military fetishists and cool people
well...cool people
I mean we're kind of trying to be cool
I don't think we're there yet though
okay something I desperately need to do is like
some of this shit
because last time we played for like three hours and
basically only completed one thing
so I'm going to
I'm going to pick this and go do it
following electrochemistry to try to find cigarettes
has only led me down paths of major distraction
this is like a passive quest
I'll find one when I find one
I'm also on a time limit wait what
are you serious
so I actually like
my play
the way I play this game is like harming my chances here
oh it's generous
okay I was about to freak out
because like I'm gonna play this very slowly
generally
they're still on day one okay
you see how reactive I was to that
I do not like being limited by time
it's one of my greatest fears in
gaming and in life
it's a couple of days okay
we've got to we've got to focus
there's too many things I have to do
enter the harbor and
seek an audience with the local debaudeur's union leader
Evrart Claier
you need to ask him about the murder in his district
okay that's what I gotta do
I gotta go to the harbor
I will not get distracted
on the way there
I’m not getting distracted by that sad lonely
bookish girl
oh what's this guy up to
I don't think i've talked to him yet
better watch your
better mouth your watch' around me boy
oh he's drunk
he's got a bag!
I seem to be able to get
I can collect trash with this bag
how do i
yes okay
now I can pick up trash
look how many bottles there are I can
ah fucking I'm
I'm so close to getting those cigs now
just you watch
I know I said I wasn't gonna get distracted but
but what I meant was
I'm gonna I'm not gonna get distracted by
low opportunity cost things
right now I have a high opportunity cost
because I now have a bag
to pick up tare which I learned as trash
some great tectonic forces correct the pavement
like an egg shell
that it has
there's there's something under there
look at all this fucking environmentalism I'm doing now
what are these guys doing
build a solid routine and stick to it that's all there is
it's quite the world view you've got there buddy
whining about your back
every time you bring out the measuring taple
emm maybe
let me increase the volume here
rene you're a man with a fork in a world of soup
please
let's just try to enjoy the game alright
he's speaking directly to me now
but the other one is eating a big sandwich
I'm trying to but you keep breaking my concentration
oh my god
you're old I can see that
we're both old
now stop grabbing your ass like it's a girl
these manly men are playing balls
this is a ball game
grab a ball and play it
don't ask questions
shoot first
ask questions never
emm I don't know
I'm very comfortable asking questions
especially after my character is starting to
open up a little bit more
no you got this
there's the ball
you're the game
these are intrusive thoughts
but I do have a very high chance of succeeding
I'm gonna observe them first
see
your munching and complaining have ruined my concentration
the man throws a metal ball towards a smaller wooden ball in the sand
ah *mon dieu*
the pain in my back is unbearable
I can't even say if it's in my back or hip anymore
feels like it's in both
he tries to measure the throw
I hope you pass out from it
you god damn jellyfish
men like you are the reason
this nation is sinking
standing tall and proud
he looks at his partner with disgust
shush ignore them
they don't know what they're doing
they're *old*
you are letting down yourself and the team
get in the damn game already
man
the physical instrument is
extremely demanding of me right now
I'm gonna ask it to clarify
does it matter what team
pick a team
any team
the blue team
you're letting them down
get in the game
and throw the god damn ball
so it is interesting that it's
trying to tap into my sense of physical shame right
which I can imagine from my character is probably quite high
especially because we haven't even looked at our own face
in the mirror yet
partially because I'm imagining we're afraid to perceive ourselves
but we're also very concerned
how other people are perceiving us right
that's a profile that I'm starting to develop about him
we were concerned about the way that cuno sees us
in fact we're like trying to rectify that as we speak
we're concerned very much about how kim sees us
we're sort of not sure where he stands
we were surprised
that lena the woman in the wheelchair
did not make very swift judgments of us
in fact she was kind of like
quite complimentary of us
so like other people's perceptions of raphael
are very important to him
which is why I imagine physical instrument
being so intrusive and like
think of the virtues it's trying to tap into
it said like
make a decision without hesitation right
like it's kind of building the association that
hesitation is attached to shamefulness
like that if you are indecisive
you are weak right
and as a therapist I like
pick up on those things as I'm talking to people
like let's say that my client was like
as soon as I saw the guy talking to my ex-girlfriend
I went up to him and I got in an argument right and
like that's something that I hear quite often
that's where I like dive into
and I'm like okay well
what about
being decisive has
gotten attached to the idea that that's a show of strength for you
and
is decisiveness more important than
making good moral decisions
and in a logical sense no it's not
but in an emotional sense
that's often what we're chasing
we're concerned about how to get rid of anxiety
and you know not feel like upset
rather than making the best all-around decisions
and so we chase things like shame
we chase things like anger
we chase
the more impulsive emotional reactions
I love that every single person who has played disco elysium
wanted in one way or another to impress kim or him
for him to like or respect them
yeah I can tell that
like he's someone that we are trying to impress and respect
but we're also trying to understand whether
he's just with us because he needs us
why are you so mean to me physical instrument?
eyes on the ball dinky winky!
look it's trying to shame me
it's trying to make me feel small and inadequate
I'll show it and them
wait wait
wait my
my my chances got worse
was it 72% before
okay that's fascinating
so when I was being decisive without hesitation
my chances were better
but when physical instrument came in to shame me
and make me feel inadequate
my chances have gotten worse
oh shit that's really interesting
that's very similar to when I was talking
I was doing the investigation or the autopsy
and I got like a boost from like Cuno
saying I was cool or whatever
okay this is fascinating to me in terms of like
the kinds of thoughts you have of the moment
will prime you for your like ability to act on them
it's a hype yourself type of thing yeah
so I've actually lowered my chances
I'm starting to feel like yeah I'm not gonna get involved
I mean is there any reason why I shouldn't
I'll show them how it's done I guess
I need to show myself that I'm capable here
here comes the shame
this felt wrong
wrong like touching your sister's breast
you threw your sister's breast
oh fuck
mon dieu*
good job officer
that was an excellent throw
I lost my respect
there are no two more harmful words
an athlete can hear than "good job"
and this was downright embarrassing
this is very consistent with my character so far
as any physical exertion we have been swiftly embarrassed
let's investigate that though why did feels so
your muscle memory knew what to do and went for it
but there were gaps
something about it was completely unnatural corrupted
your muscle memory knew what to do
and you went for it but there were gaps
yeah
gaps you tried to fill with *thinking*
we don't think in sports
we do
well if I'm trying to distance myself from
physical instrument and electrochemistry
then this is kind of a good outcome
it felt like you were going for a thrust or a lunge
there was definitely going to be jumping
maybe you scored a point but this is a *fiasco*
I thought something way more spectacular was going to happen
the throw is terrible and you know it
no need to mock me
I'll just be a little more earnest
what are you talking about
you just executed a pretty much perfect petanque throw
his tone is full of admiration
how are you ever
going to get the office's shit off your nose gaston
or even climb out of his ass
that's just how johnny ball game is extraordinary
I was going for something cool but I screwed it up like always
yeah that fits the narrative
that fits my character's construction of himself
the man in the uniform says nothing
his gaze is fixed on the horizon
maybe he identified with that little statement there
his merry partner is staring at the ground
like he's trying to see right through to the other side
the lieutenant is looing at you
his face is expressionless
do you know anything about the man hanged in the back
yard of whirling in rags
unfortunately I don't
unlike most of the locals
I have no qualms about assisting law enforcement
but this affair has passed me by completely
and most of the locals
in martinaise the union is the law
so can you really blame them
but you don't have a problem with cops
*cop* is a pejorative term
I don't have a problem with policemen
on the contrary
I admire the effort to bring oder to our streets
so again you don't know anything
if I knew I would not be afraid to tell you
I simply don't
I'm an old man not a coward
the daily business of the riff-raft
no longer concerns me
this is a man with a lot of past
but little present
and almost no future
Inland Empire coming in with the wisdom
let's uh let's ask him what they're doing here
yes
the terrain here provides an interesting variety to a familiar game
do you know what created it
fire from heavy artillery
okay it's a crater left by artillery fire but why
why what?
why was heavily artillery used
because that's what happens when communards hijack your country
execute your supreme leadership
and turn your capital into a slaughterhouse
you use *heavy ordnance* to clean up your home
okay so this guy has just been pushed
a little bit above his like safe zone in terms of anxiety and
he is starting to disclose
much more  information which is interesting
did you use artillery fire against them
sadly no
it was the foreigners who brought them to their knees
we fought valiantly
too valiantly
so valiantly we got licked
should've fought dirty
like they did with their suicide sex cult propaganda
and *mad anarchist women* strapped to shrapnel bombs
we didn't though and we lacked *caliber*
god bless him
but the suzerain's simply weren't big enough
why shell them here in martinese
good question
because the place is the damn beckhead
had to sofen the commies up first
the beachhead
yes the military-coordinated amphibious
landing to take back Revachol
he finds your lack of historic knowledge troubing
a sigh of mental deterioration in the proceeding generations
that is true
martinaise was used as one of the three footholds in revachol
during operation death blow in '08
the other two are off in stella maris and the delta
so there's a difference between like
informing me for some reason does not make him like excited right
if he was like a historian
and he was happy to inform people
he would not be in any way troubled by like catching me up to speed here
the frustration in his tone
though tells me something very different about
what this history means to him
and that other people don't know it
what it tells me is that he's very concerned that the
(the)effort and cost of life put into this task has not been remembered
or is not immediately recognizable by other people
and that makes it feel like it wasn't worth it
and so for him
he is displacing all of that like historical resentment
was what we fought for actually that meaningful
and he's displacing that into me as someone who is
ignorant of the struggle right
so it tells me a lot about him as a person
just in the way that he's saying it
I'll just kind of nod thoughtfully at this
this here is blood ground
where coalition boots first made landfall
and cleaned those rabid dogs out
most likely we're playing petanque on their mangled corpses
okay so it's not just because it's interesting to him
you got old rene going there
like he isn't angry enouth already
but that's a line of questioning that I would definitely use in therapy right
and I've done counseling with
people of all kinds of different ages and backgrounds
and for someone who may be a bit older
they have had a longer amount of time living to collect anger
that has not been put into something productive right
what I always kind of start with in that sense is like
what was it like to tell...
me raphael this information
what were you feeling?
I was feeling frustrated
I was feeling like it was pointless
I was remembering the confusion I felt about how
impactful my decisions were going to be making right
I was feeling scared at the ongoing decay of the society
and people's knowledge of how it started right
like he could tell me all of these things presumably
and my approach with him
would be to say that like well we can't change the past right
we can only change what that information means to us
and you have an opportunity here to inform someone
basically the problem that you're having
is that someone is uninformed about this
so maybe try to get them excited
and inform them in a productive way right
if the reason you're upset is people don't know this history then
share it with them
but when you do it from a place of frustration
not only does it
make you get in touch with that resentment
but it also drives the person listening
not to want to hear any more of it
which is why I'm kind of like as a character
okay well let's just move on then
because you don't seem very happy to be telling me this
so like the very situation that's causing you angst
can actually be the therapeutic solution too
it's just kind of how you approach it from your attitude
ah that explains all the war damage
damn right son
they laid the fire of hell on this city before they stormed it
and it worked too
the rest of the city got cleaned up
but Martinaise they keep as a monument
and now the union socialists are practically running the place
well it's your own damn fault
you we the coalition revachol
whoever you want to blame never finished the job
officially the party never surrendered
of course they still all influence
okay so there's some unfinished business as a part of this too
there's a lack of closure
you don't even begin to truly understand the players of the table
let alone the specific circumstances surrounding the
what do you think
that's how it should be
soft socialists paving the way for the *hard*working class to take over
foreign powers cleaned up our mess and now they rule us
this coalition seems quite capable actually
commies just don't understand how money works
*nothing *don't* think I just *do*
what do I think
what does my character think about this
he's seeing the world in terms of power dynamics and authority
and the more obscure the source of authority
the easier it is to point to it as the bad guy right
that's why we're often thinking of institutions corporations
like the man
like the more vague  the less specific the enemy
the easier it is to displace all of our issues onto
this is like a like kind of the racism angle
commies just don't understand how money works
I guess I'm going to go with that
no they don't
I'm sorry it had to be the coalition
after eight years of fighting rabbit commies
boiling cats for food and drinking piss in the mountains
cats what the fuck
I would have preferred if the right honorable king
Guillaume returned to Revachol
or even if that damn clown Frissel
had risen from the grave and led us
sadly that was not the case
this royal failure weighs heavily on him
instead all that is just
holy and beautiful inthe world was wiped away
and now it's neon signs with toothpasteads everywhere
foreign influence peddling garbage and
stupid music on the radio
this is just what the commies wanted
this was their plan all along
this is what they wanted to replace the role of the southerner with
okay so he's got royal allegiances
who was this Frissel
damn Frissel
he was the king we couldn't protect
the carabineers failed him
and the crown
he died in the hands of the *hoipolloi*
in a very public execution
you mentioned guillaume
a true king in both blood and mind
led revachol before frissel
he would have been better
but the damn commies drove him into exile
what exactly is a sousaraine?
sousaraine is the king
has everyone forgotten already
they've forgotten already
what did I just say
what did I just say about how
he is contributing to his own internal strive
by seeing it as a chore to inform me
of the thing that he is already angry I don't know
dude needs to look in a psychological mirror
soon they will forget everything him too
then he chooses anger over melancholy
see empathy knows
he is choosing
he is choosing to have this
not to feel this way but choosing to act on it this way
it's no use talking to you
you were still in daddy's balls when it happened
when we took our last stand against the fifth
and rode the cavalry straight into gunfire
8 percent
composure legendary
what is it about this old soldier that makes him stand so proud
I mean  it's a white check
I guess I don't have any reason not to try it right
let's give it a shot
all you observe
is a veteran refusing to let go of the past and his old uniform
this is not uncommon
this is the uniform of the royal carabineers
in service of frissel the first Guilaume*Le Lion*
and the valiant King Filippe the Fifth before him
don't you mean Frissel the Fun
I got used to it I know
I got so used to passing those early difficult checks
I succeeded like three times and that's all I get
now I just fail at everything
*you*do not speak his name craven!
although he was a clown
but he was *our* clown
ours to ridicule and to mourn
I don't think having a another point will make it difference
because I only score eight
I mean I also got a one on the dice roll
which is pretty dire
failure is good in this game
there's something he missed
you will get to it don't worry
okay I'll come back to it
wow you work hard
oh I do
oh yes you hustle
you're a provider
it's tough out there  but you keep it real and provide
what hard work do I do exactly
look at youself you're a human pedometer
you must have walked 200000 steps
down craked asphalt mosaic sand
and linoleum after you re-emerged
I guess that's true
that is the sign of a hustler who never gives up
the world is harsh and people are evil
you didn't make it that way and you won't let it break you
you *ride*
I'm not sure I ride
hey Adam Sandler a toe tickler 65
thank you for subscribing with prime I appreciate you
it's quite a name you've got there
I'm not sure I ride
oh you do
you make money you got gills
I don't make any money
meaning those black papers
with the faces of the innocence on them
you bring in the Franconegroes and the Solas
it ain't easy but you do it day in and day out
you didn't make the rules but you won't lose
you're a cop and a sprinter and a money printer
no I'm not
sevar fair is a liar
sure sure
and has it been easy
is life easy
no
have you *not* gone into cardiac arrest
are you *not* about to have an anxiety attack
or shoot yourself in the mouth
but you still hustle 24 seven ride or die
now ask yourself
are you rich
no I'm actually not
that's right
you work harder than anyone
you almost rode yourself to the grave
and you're still practically a hobo
why is that
is it because of that guard guy riding my ass?
the system is broken
there's a market for corrupt cops out there
but the immigrant cops have priced up
fucking taxes man
what does my character really think
part of me wants to think he doesn't have
the self-awareness to realize
that it's many of my own decisions and depression
I go with that
because of the taxes
G-man's got his jam-covered sticky-fingers in your pocket
stealing from you every time
you buy sell walk talk fart so much as sneeze
you're a liar savoir fair
every time you wipe your ass
they got their direct and their *indirect modes of taxation*:
sales tax excise duty extraction tax alimony
one tax that doesn't even have a name
plus there's the stuff *people in other countries* pay for
that makes them ask for more money from *you* here
total tax duties add up to
98% of all your money
no fucking way
I guess I'm a free market fundamentalist now
are you sure that seems like a pretty big number
this isn't helping me solve my money problem
it's only making me into a free market type
what is the difference between these two responses
this isn't helping me solve my money problem
I should be able to participate freely in the market right
I guess I could opt in
here you go  hustler
fight the righteous fight
free the people
keep it real
keep it street
keep foaming at the mouth *furiously* on the tax issue
okay
sometimes I can't tell if making a good role playing decision
will lead to me locking myself out of a good game mechanic
so I appreciate the help there
I'm not above like saying yes to stuff like that it's just
I like that the game gives me an option not to
but I wouldn't have realized that
gates me out of something I could be using
okay
looks like I can internalize that too
if you have a side bitch ideology cooking somewhere
don't sweat it
fighting indirect taxation for the Gossamer State
is compatible with *all* creeds
it's cool like that
you're a cool anarchist now
unless you don't want to be an anarchist
whatever
stuff this meal ticket in your eye-socket
and let's see if we can steal some *love* back
from the robber barons at the customs agency at the *banditos*
and the insulindian financial oversight and competition committee
geez
okay
looks like we're looking for a side hustle
we get minus two empathy for that though
fuck that
I don't want that
one thing that I recommend is think about your thoughts
that are directly tied to what your character might say
or can do in the future
that's true
well  but I don't want to lose my empathy
I mean  I guess I could turn it on and turn it off right
okay  I need to go to the docks
I've been distracted again
only while the research is going on
makes sense
oh  there's trash everywhere for me
I'm going to get so much cash from this
this is my side hustle right now
这条chat说得不对
ohh once I
am I stuck withe this once I complete it
I do not want that
I do not want to lose my empathy
what's going here
a sturdy metal door
guards the southwest entrance to the apartment building
it's locked
so it's going to knock
the door rattles against your knuckles
but there's no response
the door rattles again
but this time
you hear an elderly woman's voice calling out from inside
stop banging on the door
I'm not letting any more strangers inside
the empathy returns after I'm done internalizing
or I can forget the thought
okay
I will turn it on while I'm walking around then
but not while I'm in dialogue
who am I speaking to
it doesn't matter who I am
now go on get out of here
this is the police
the police
everyone knows the police don't come around *here*
oh  walking around doesn't progress the time okay
I mean
I just don't think I
it aligns with my character that much to be honest
I'm just going to leave it as it is
no  I already told you
I won't be responsible for any more strangers
getting into the building
go check the backyard door
maybe someone there will
Kim
let's get Kim involved
tell her to open this door
madam I assure you
we are real police officers
show him show her your badge
there is no reply
just faint sweeping sounds inside
okay
can't get in there
why does it keep giving me a notification
I mean I guess I can have my flashlight out
instead of
the crowbar
didn't that say to
investigate the dock or something
Kim move I need to pick up that trash
no  I don't want to talk to you right now
just trying to get that sweet tear
what's up here
garden house
chairs
there must be another way into the building
what is this guy
you see a young man on a balcony nursing a cigarette
his eyes have been following you for a while
he's got a cigarette he's got a cigarette in his portrait
not looking for any trouble  officer
despite his the cold  his shirt hangs on button on his frame
why are you whispering? it sounds like you're already in trouble
no trouble for me
I just want to know what's going on in here
yeah  why are you whispering that's suspicious
there's no trouble I'm just speaking in a lowered voice
I don't want to be seen talking to the gendarmerie if that's okay
I just want to finish my cigarette
how about you toss one of those bad boys down here
it's the god of cigarettes and youth
ask him if he's got anything to spare
he does already respect my authority here
maybe I can get one of them
apologies  but this is my last one
how is it your last one
everyone has said that to me
I'm starting to not to believe them
the god himself has denied you absolution
fuck!
why don't youtoss that one down
I’m not sure that's a good idea
I don't care
I need that cigarette from you
I’m not throwing anything
you're arrested
there's no way you catch that cigarette anyway
fuck
yes really
don't even try
you'll just embarrass yourself
I don't want to embarrass myself anymore
please don't do that to me
as you wish
okay  well  I need to talk to you anyways
is it really that important
I've been stonewalled at every chance to get a ciggy
like a nervous cat
he keeps stealing looks at the neighboring windows
all right  but make it quick
once I finish this cigarette  I have to run
yeah  your last one right
fucking liar
looks like you've got a good view of the Whirling's backyard
can you tell me anything about the hanging
I can *tell* that you finally got him down
thank you
it was quite a disturbing sight
even by Martinaise standards
what were you doing last sunday
yeah  investigate him  Kim
oh
you already asked me that didn't you
did you?
no  not you two
some more muscular type
wait  is there another cop involved
and when did you speak to this more muscular gentleman
last week I don't know look
he looks around the courtyard again
old patio chairs and dead house planters litter the scene
you didn't answer the question
what were you doing last sunday
yeah what were you up to
I had a friend over
it was my sunday friend
sunday friend
A  *Sunday friend*
how intriguing
makes sense
friends are nice on sunday
you don't have to work
you can just spend time with pals
watching rugby and drinking beer
I guess so
he doesn't reply
gesturing  no  with his cigarette
in the neighboring windows
you can see faint reflections of his silhouette
all from different angles
okay  let's get his name
my name my name is Martin Martinaise
are you fucking serious
Martin Martinaise
good local name
let's go with that
yeah he's lying
you're a liar
my rhetoric is the stupid part of my brain
no
we won't
I've been
now if you'll excuse me I really need to get going
minus one to bumming cigarette
wait what
I can convince him to s
because I didn't get a cigarette from him
I may not be able to pass this
I mean it's a 72% chance
I'll put it on my hobo charms
this is going to be easy
time to bring out your secret charm
tears and begging
show him your emotional side
throw yourself before his very feet like a dog
what
god damn it
why don't you give me the option to try for 17%
I'm sure I'll fucking succeed at that
how embarrassing
I got a three and a two on my dice roll
and then I didn't get a cigarette  so I
it's tragic
I was one point away
if I had just gotten that cigarette from him
if I had only gotten the ciggy  everything would be fine
this case would be solved
please don't go
I'll stop drinking
I'll take out the trash
what?
oh  there's an ex-relationship at play here for our character
that's how we're feeling
do you want me to cry
no for god's sake I don't want you to cry
yes
listen  I really have to go
oh  yeah
send me an extinguished cigarette
ah there it goes
wasted
you would have gotten at least a few good drags out of it
now electrochemistry is speaking to me
good luck with the investigation
you fucking
I hate this guy
I can't believe it
I never want to see him again
if I didn't ask for the cigarette  okay
he's gone
oh
my perception isn't that bad  Kim
this guy is constantly trying to undermine me
no point in running
tenements like these often have multiple exits
if he doesn't want to talk to us then
he'll know how to hide himself
so we just give up
he could be a witness
him or his *Sunday friend*
either way  we need to look into that *muscular type*
who's asking about our case
yeah  we do
there has to be a way of getting inside the building
let's go check out the door near the pier again
yeah  yeah
once we follow him in  we can ask around for his apartment
I should have listened kembadog
asking around can sometimes ruin my chances
okay
whatever
I don't want to smoke anyways
I don't care
I got bigger things to do
like pick up trash
I can wear this bum hat
let's check out the bum hat
it's not good for my rhetoric
where's my rhetoric
it's debating  nitpicking
it's already pretty short anyways
but my reaction speed
I mean I probably won't physically embarrass myself anymore
innocent situations can turn bad
when you're overly alert
that's a good point
at low levels though  you won't be the one shooting first
you won't be shooting at all
I don't know should I wear the bum hat?
get some good reaction speed
it's kind of cool
it does go with
with the gloves and the trash bag
okay we're going to wear it for a little while
let's check out those barrels
it's full of rainwater
it's down here
just a closed door
I thought that this said like
enter the harbor
is this not the harbor or is this the pier
what is this
palette
ah there's money
cash money
and I got some magnesium
okay
some sea birds
bullet holes
let's check out that trash can
maybe I can turn in some of my trash now for some money
and I can buy that cigarette
and maybe we'll find the harbor along the way
turn in some of this trash
the tare machine stands in the corner
a sign says one bottle equals 10 cents
your bottles clunk into the machine
one forty
and the money appears with a satisfying jingle
you're a richer man now
do you know what you should do with that money kiddo
you should buy more alcohol
enter the endless cycle of consumption
I need ciggies
you see several packaged raincoats fill a low shelf
no  I don't need a raincoat
that's what I need
welcome to Frittte
what's that magazine she's reading
what it's I guess
what's that magazine you're reading
this is pop stars
it's got like famous people in it
emh rich I got two real
looks like it also has something called police de la mode
featured on page 34
this speaks to you
forget about all that
what is this *fashion police* feature
I'm not even interested
I don't know why I asked about it
let's ask about what's on the cover here
it's where they rate different outfits famous people wear
it's kind of funny
they're kind of mean
it's about who's the most stylish
I bet your hat would take the prize
um no I don't like it
I hate it
we are not the fashion police
we're the real police
as much as my cat is enjoying looking out the window
it's blasting me with sunlight
what is this Frittte?
I don't know Frittte
a 7-to-11 grocery store
I think they think that the extra it makes it *funkier*
it doesn't
let's proceed I have some quetions for you
um okay
I’m not really supposed to be chatting to anyone but
can you tell me anything about the dead body
maybe she's seen something
I don't really know anything
I mean I know it's there
but I haven't seen it so
kitty  no
there's a whole patio back there
that you can look out the window in
why do you have to look out this one
can't see shit
I can't put a curtain up either because she'll tear it down
did you know the man who died
not really
does it mean you knew him a little?
no  I didn't know him at all
I’m starting to think that the Frittte Clerk is the key to all of this
how long has it been there
I don't know really *long*
here  I'm pointing my flashlight at something suspicious
my suspicious thing here is why aren't you
more interested in what's going on around you?
why are you escaping into the celebrity gossip
is it because you're so detached from the reality around you
is it because no one at home reflects or asks about your interests
is it because
you don't have strong social relationships
with any of your friends
maybe you don't have friends because
you come from a home
where you have to support most of the financial responsibilities
and the only way to do so is to work this job that you hate
and you have to talk to people like myself
is that why you're reading from this stupid magazine
and why are you giving me so much fucking lip
is that it
because that's the vibe I'm getting here
she's like 14
hey she could be the primary breadwinner for all we know
right now  she's the main obstacle between me and a cigarette
which is the main obstacle between me and this investigation
so let's figure this out
what do you think happened young lady
I don't know
stop saying um
it makes me sound like I'm an idiot just for asking
no need to worry
it's just standard procedure for us to ask around
if you here anything let us know okay
okay
thank you for your help
do you have a warehouse back there
I don't know maybe I don't really care what Frittte does
come on  give me something to work with here  please
she looks up from under her brow
fine Frittte doesn't have a warehouse
just a little backroom here okay
ok thank you you've finally given me something interesting
I should stop pointing the flashlight at you now
reality you mean what reality
economic reality or
yes tell me about the economic reality
watch me be so fucking bang on with this character
I don't really know anything I mean I'm 15
15 is an *excellent* time to learn about the economic reality
yeah  that's why I'm working my ass off in frick
so I guess like that's economic
why why is she doing that though
I have to know I want to know if I'm right
I don't know what about it
the Coalition what's that someone told me there is one
our government?
or do you mean something else
sorry  I really need to finish this article
ok she's getting a little anxious
she's trying to avoid my questions
we're in frittte
no I meant--where *are* we
on a larger scale
as mankind or as a nation
as mankind that's what I
here's the thing okay
if you don't have someone at home
asking you about your day or what you think about things
here is your opportunity young lady all right
like an adult someone with a cool flashlight hat gloves and coat
is asking you like your opinion about things
the fact that she's so like um I don't know
means that no one in her life is asking her things
can you imagine
she's going home and her mom or dad
or whoever is taking care of her
is not asking her
so young lady  what do you think about the world
why do you think we're making you
or asking you to work in this little shop
would you like to know about the economic state that we're in
like this girl has no real grounding
for why she's doing any of these things
because no one at home is engaging with her
she probably goes home and her parents are just as burnt out
by how fucked up their own lives are
that like they're not asking her anything
and so she's getting her stimulation
and her like the only thing that's showing her
a reflection of her own interests is a fucking magazine
why because it depicts things that are not in her environment
is this normal therapist behavior at a grocery store
well yes
internally internally
I I'm not like
I do want you to just imagine me going into the store
and just like
I don't know going on these sorts of rants
it's a good image
most insane disco elysium player
what if she's relatively happy and fulfilled at home
and just hates her job and is fed up with
kind of this kind of customer
I mean I guess that could be the case too
but I'm having a different kind of insight
I mean  imagine imagine your person
you're the person working in a place like this
what is she selling
she's selling alcohol cigarettes
like an old boat or something
like is any of this stuff was interesting to a teenager
nope
she's not even like a cool teenager
working at like
spencer's or hot topic or something
I don't know
what teenagers are into these days
I'm not one anymore
but like she doesn't even work in a place
where she understands the
the personal value of the things she's selling
so of course  she's fed up with it
she stands behind the counter and just like pedals the shit out
mostly things that are bad for you
and attracts the kinds of people who are
like chemically dependent on these things
and so she's going to get a lot of people like me and alcoholics
and people with short tempers
because they haven't smoked recently
like no wonder she hates her job
out of all the characters you do a deep dive on  you choose this girl
yeah  exactly
ok  who else but this young girl
it's the same thing I said about Kuno like
what's most fascinating to me
when I'm trying to understand world building
and like if we're talking economic systems and political systems
and the the like resentments that the veteran has
you have to look at the kids who live in this world
like they are the result of these problems
like the way that they view the world
the way they act in it
creates the culture around us
of course  they don't want to engage with it right
and it's all the more reason that if like
the gentleman we saw down at the waterfront
came in here and talked to the frittte clerk
like he's the person that he's thinking of
when he's yelling at us about how like you don't understand this stuff
seache you know me so well
watch I get to the plot relevant characters
and I completely breeze over them
you know that that's exactly what's going to happen
like something really important is going to happen
and I'm just going to be like  all right  whatever
let's talking through it for 10 minutes holding a flashlight
god damn
she's this is the most unhinged part of our playthrough so far
yeah  like she she's the character I’m most interested in
I want to get involved in her life
tell me what you think about mankind  sweetie
in a good place
look at her thinking
she's never been asked a question like this
I want your opinions on the world
I mean  science is doing great
and this radio computer thing seems to be kind of big
I don't know
so she's exposed to like
things that are of a modern nature
the fact that she brought up scientific things
does show that she has
some capacity to grapple with technological things
maybe she would rather be working in a lab right now
than standing at this checkout counter selling cigarettes
let's ask her about the revolution
when ordinary people take over the government and
um demands democracy
look she is intelligent
she knows things
what about the one we had here in Revachol
yeah  it happened like 50 years ago or so
sorry  I'm not very good at this
don't tell yourself that
don't ever tell yourself that
you know more than I do
and you have probably had a conversation with
the gentleman at the dock
and he told you you don't know anything about history
well  that's because
he just wants you to learn his history not THE history
what time is it
I don't know
look at the clock
it's right behind you on the wall
the clock shows the time at 10:09
the hands seem to be still
it's apparent the clock doesn't work
ok I'm not going to bother you with this anymore
but you have you have given me a lot to think about  young lady
and I hope the world finds you in the...
with more opportunities as your life progresses
cool
she is cool I like her
I want to be her friend and give her more opportunities
now  let's see if she'll sell me a cigarette
if she's the kind of
a colorful diplay of cigarettes and
alcohol bottles lined the shop wall
inviting you closer
ok Frittte girl is going to win like maximum points
if she gives me a cigarette as well like
like most important character in the game right now
she holds the key
there in that dark green glass all in vain
the great flowing river of warmth
wine alcohol beer alcohol love alcohol
this is not a good place for a recovering addict
we know that but he's not self-aware enough
let's just take it in
I'm obliged to inform you that both
alcohol and cigarettes damage your health
but I guess you already know that
ok that's true she does
look at her being so concerned with my well-being
she's got a good empathetic spine here
don't ask don't look don't do anything here
just go away
get back to work
ignoring that
know this--you will never finish your alcohol quest
if you don't buy beautiful alcohol
I'm so close I need 80 coins
it gives me intellect
that's what I'm missing
I have been missing intellect this whole time
fuck volition it doesn't want me to finish my quests
um he pale age vodka is special  I guess
it's stored in pale for a couple of years  which makes it
super expensive and super strong
ok well consuming the stuff due to my body
I mean I already said it'd hurt you
I don't know what else they do
substances give powerful bonuses to your main stats
at the cost of damage to your health or morale
cigarettes raise your intellect while damaging your health
alcohol raises physique while damaging your morale
well all I need to do is pack myself up with magnesium
and I should like even out the alcoholism
so I'm going to do that
use medication like noseaphed and magnesium
to counteract the negative effects of substances
note  consuming substances can
have unforeseen consequences for you
I don't know
it sounds like magnesium is a pretty swift
cure for the alcohol and that will increase my physique
so I'm going to be back
I will be back  frittte girl I need some more bottles
bottles first  then I will get the cigarettes
and then I will be smart enough to continue the quest okay
Kim can wait
what is this money
there's money on the ground
I'm so close now
there's got to be more bottles around here
what is tommy up to
tommy have any bottles
oh  there's got to be bottles in here
this is a bar after all
I fucking I I'm telling you guys
this case is going to blow wide open
the second I get those cigarettes in my hands
any bottles no bottles
bunch of bottles in my room can I pick those ones up
are they non-interactable
this is what I feared
they're the non-interactable type of bottles
ok
that was a fruitless little venture
the headline of this stream is
substance abuse counselor
desperately tries to find narcotics
I'm not interacting with anything unless it is a piece of trash
is that a piece of trash
physical instrument  a tank top
and it comes with no downsides
fucking let's go
oh  but
conceptualization
I think I can I'm going to swap this on
physical instrumentI could use that
no no no I don't care about any of that shit
I just need bottles
bottles
money  there's fucking money just laying on the ground
yes
it's time
it's time guys
okay
a colorful display of cigarettes and
alcohol bottles lined the shop wall
inviting you closer
again I'm obliged to inform you that
both alcohol and cigarettes damage your health
yeah  frittte clerk
well you didn't get the secret knowledge that I have
which is that they come with lasting benefits as well
here you go Mister
I've got them
I have got them!
fucking finally it has only taken me nearly a dozen hours
to get to the point
fuck you you wouldn't give me a cigarette
even tommy  the man
the homie wouldn't give me a cigarette
in fact I'm going to smoke my first one right in front of him
look he's still smoking it
ok it's been hours since we last talked
meaning that wasn't really your last cigarette
was it  tommy?
I'll fucking show you
before I only got four cigarettes
how long do they last
let's go with it smoke it up
oh wait  I have to put away
how do I use it?
there it is
a brave little army in your pocket
the first smokes platoon
twenty brave souls standing in salute
ready to step into fire for you sir
pull one out
you picked the best one
this soldier is fat and succulent
what are you waiting for
light up re-become yourself
yes
oh yes *bratan* please light up
you *need* a trooper between your lips right now
calm your shit down
go to pleasure land
become a *genius*
that's my tie
the necktie
it talks
necktie chan
wait a second
so you're telling me that lighting up a cigarette was
finally the thing that woke my best buddy up
well  fucking light it up then
it's a load of this rock and roll cop here people
johnny thunder cop fishes a cheap lighter out of his pants
with a flick of the thumb this fire
a primal satisfaction
here we go
drip that bad boy in flame and breathe it in
thick warm smoke gets sucked down into your lungs
intellect raised
you feel a warm nostalgia fill your head body and soul
a nostalgia for yourself the man you were in your youth
johnny thunder cop is back
and he's chill as balls
johnny thunder cop okay
in the bottom right corner of the screen
there's a cigarettes button
cigarettes gives plus one to intellect skills
logic rhetoric conceptualization
visual calculus encyclopedia and drama
this is good before a white check
but damages your health
okay
so I think I should clarify
I am very anti-smoking
especially in my professional work
I don't smoke
and in fact I very adamantly discourage it from people
especially those who are
trying to recover from another substance
because not only is there a lot of comorbidity
between like
using substances and that sort of thing
but what I perceive is that
if you're trying to quit using one substance
we're not just talking about the physical like
implications of that like trying to
trying to get your body re-stabilized
from not being dependent on that substance
but it's also a behavioral thinglike
you're trying to learn not to chase impulses
you're trying to learn how to
re-establish your body's sense of patience
about how to not reward yourself with stimulation
or curb your appetite by using tobacco or all of these things
there's all kinds of behavioral and psychological implications
to continuing to smoke while you're using or stopping use
then again there's also people who say that
harm reduction is the way to go
and that one thing at a time
don't try to quit this drug while also quitting cigarettes
it'll make it harderbut
but I'm of the perspective that
continuing to have a vice for smoking
actually makes it harder to quit the other thing
because you're not working on the impulsive behaviors
at the same time
just for clarity
my excitement for this is that if I pure role playing perspective
professionally speaking
you can ask my coworkers
I'm the most anti-smoking person that you'd find
maybe this is my escapism
I think smoking is garbage
a therapist's playthrough wouldn't be as good
if you didn't turn the MC into a train wreck
anyhow getting him clean sober and sane would be boring
well that's true
look I'm going off of what I expect my character
to actually be stuggleing with
there is something to be said for
we're trying to reclaim our past memories
some memories live in physical sensation right
smell especially
if smoking a cigarette is going to help him
figure out more about himself
then that's probably something he would do
but yes don't pick up smoking
it's terrible for you
thank you for watching my video
if you enjoyed it consider giving it a like
and letting me know what you thought of it in the comments
you can subscribe to catch the next video here
or you can see things a little bit earlier if
you support the channel either through twitch or patreon
links to both of those and the community discord are in the description
thanks again  and I will see you next time
bye