okay let's talk about why we make bad decisions
so if you're like me then you've probably been in that situation where it's the end of the day or it's the morning and you're thinking like okay I'm gonna make a solid plan for myself
today I'm gonna be disciplined
I'm gonna come home from work and I'm gonna get all these errands done and I'm gonna treat myself really well
I'm gonna make a nice healthy proper meal
I'm gonna go to the gym afterwards
I'm gonna exercise and then maybe when I come home I'll like start reading a book or something
I'll do something a little different something that makes me feel like I'm gonna advance my life in a new positive direction
and this is our real life volition and it's there to lead you on your way to making good life decisions
but this doesn't always work out that way
sometimes you get to the end of the day and you realize that you haven't been very disciplined at all
a lot of those errands are still incomplete or like half - started
we didn't end up going to the gym and instead of making a proper meal we've ordered some definitely not healthy takeout food
and instead of reading that book maybe you end up watching a show you've already seen and we've not advanced our life in a positive meaningful direction in any way at all
what is happening here
why would we ignore the voice of volition that's telling us to do all of these beneficial positive things
well it could be a lot of things honestly and definitely having like a mental health diagnosis is going to amplify this problem a lot more
but even for the average person this happens like pretty often
I mean it certainly happens to me
so what I wanted to share with you today is a framework for understanding why this problem happens and what we can actually do about it
this is a real problem that actually comes up in my work as a therapist kind of often
and I have really enjoyed seeing it demonstrated so clearly and given such a unique role within the structure of a game like disco elysium has
so okay there is a reason that we do not always follow the voice of volition and go through with our good intentions
and it has to do with something called psychological friction
so in this context friction is any force either internal or external which opposes a behavioral change
so what do we know about like regular friction right
if I am standing on an ice rink and I move my body weight around a little bit I'm gonna start sliding around on the ice
there's not a lot of friction between me and the surface that's under me