hello and welcome to another episode in my therapist plays disco leesium analysis series
so this time I wanted to share something that I learned about a particular character in the game and also some things that I learned about myself in the course of uploading this series
so just for context if you're just coming into this now the way I'm kind of playing through the game is from like the perspective of being a therapist and trying to provide as much commentary as I can on different angles of mental health that are depicted in the game
there's a lot more going on than just that at disco leesium but I'm really just I'm not the person to comment on like complicated political stuff
and one of the most important dynamics in the game is the one that you have with your partner kim kitsuragi
and I recognize that like as the player we're going to be a lot more aware of kim's qualities than my character the detective will
and so in my role play of him I have sort of been exploring the subject of someone who is coming from a background of trauma which we still don't know a lot about raphael from where I'm at in the game
but a lot of his issues with the way he views authority and relationships and his struggles with substance abuse kind of indicate that there may be some of that background present
so I've been kind of approaching a lot of the dialogue with kim from this perspective that like we tend to have an initial first impression about someone that we may want to trust them but if we're someone who has a lot of trust issues we may sort of like test that relationship over time
we may kind of see where the real boundaries are
and from my character's perspective he's kind of been trying to see like does kim stick around with me because he needs me to complete this case
or are the qualities that we immediately picked up on that he is earnest and trustworthy and a very honest character at heart
are those things going to last when we make ourselves very difficult to be around basically
I'm definitely going to ask him
I really want to impress him and I want him to think that I'm cool and that I'm not a f * * * ing mess
I've been kind of trying to demonstrate that like some of the closest relationships you can have are ones that have really been put through that test and have outlasted that period of like if I push this person far enough are they still going to stick with me
assai the lieutenant where is his nose in his notebook
see there's another thing that I'm not sure about kim