hello and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
on today's episode we're going to address something kind of unavoidable in a game like this which is what are some of the crossovers between politics and mental health and kind of some personal struggles I have about integrating those two subjects
I'm sure there will be a lot of discussion about this in the comments
you know that this is all recorded previously
I think I'm going to probably make a dedicated video at some point kind of like compiling my thoughts a little more but yeah we get an early look at kind of where my mind is coming from on this
aside from that we have a very special moment in this episode which is finally we're going to reach the end of our first day as a detective
it's taken us a while and we're going to take another look at how kiminai's relationship has been developing over this very challenging day and see if there's actually some things that we'd become quite close on
so all that's coming up
I'm excited to get into it
let's do it
alrighty we are going to talk to kim
we should think about calling it today maybe
the nights are still miserably cold this time of year
I haven't paid the cafeteria manager for the damages yet
I should take care of that then
I don't have the money
I'm stuck to him anyway
an office of the rcm shouldn't be sleeping in the street
we'll figure something out
though he finds this situation frustrating he is doing his best to not make you feel any worse than you already do
I respect that kim
he's kim is what a lot of points with me these chapters of our stream
okay let's see if we can reason with this gentleman
can I help you
but I don't have another option here
yes have you got it
can we come to some sort of arrangement
is that arrangement include you paying me what we already agreed you owe me
kim is about to say something
let him
let's do that
I understand your predicament as the manager
however I feel I must remind you that we are here to conduct an important investigation that also affects your business
that's good point
put the squeeze on him
forgive me for saying this but your colleagues seems more committed to drinking and he stops me in sentence
he shrinks back a bit under the lieutenant severe gaze
I mean no effects
it's really nothing personal
I just have to protect the interests of this establishment
no kiddie