hello and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
so on today's episode we're getting deeper into our different character studies and kind of breaking down like the psychological dynamics in their dialogue and the relationships and everything that represents in terms of mental health
this time I give a lot of focus to two characters in particular that we meet on our journey through revisheil and one of them that I give kind of like my deepest
psychoanalytical impressions yet maybe also my most unhinged character analysis as far as well
but it is in service of actually kind of discussing like some important things about how the game depicts its world building and what characters do we need to look at
in terms of like if we look at the shape of their mental health this will tell us a lot about what it is like to live in this environment with these political systems with these social tensions
like what is the result of that on the people who are actually being brought up in this world
so there's a lot to get into
I'm excited to share
so let's jump back in
okay
let's continue
so I think the last thing we were doing is kind of investigating our relationship with kim here
I guess if it's a section of this that I missed
cool for I see what you mean
I thought it was something I had to click on
so let's check out inland empire because that's our main skill and I'm finding it very interesting that this was the primary skill that I chose
especially because in the last stream I found myself kind of disagreeing with its intrusions a little more
it says it's cool for dreamers paronatural investigators and mental creators
I don't know if I'd call myself paronatural but I am an investigator and I am a mental creator meaning that I tend to make stuff in my brain that's better than I can make it in reality
empathy is cool for judges of character interviewers and interrogators
yeah that's me as well
this is a volition is cool for sane people well adjusted cops the non suicidal
it's kind of half of us right
empathy is cool for leaders experts of psychological warfare and respect junkies
okay
yes yes and yes
this one is cool for cops cop - efficient autos and pretend cops