hello and welcome to my therapist plays disco elicium analysis series
on today's episode we are meeting
what has become another one of my absolute favorite characters that we've met so far
so we're going to be talking a lot with a net and her mother today learning more about the economic reality of being a child who has to work out in the cold all day
and in that dialogue we're also going to be continuing to build our own character profile sort of continuing the analysis using the jahari window that we started in the last episode
there's a lot of emotions to dig into and discuss in today's episode including some that may come up when we finally face ourselves
so that's where we're at
I'm excited to continue so let's jump back in
okay
what shall we do next
I guess we can go enter the door behind the greenhouse
let's go do that
it's in the yard basement door
is that back there
yeah it's more useful on counseling
what does this girl up to
it's been a while since we've checked in
she is way too positive
oh it's snowing
what is this crime
it's about murders or burglaries or things like that and the work of a policeman or a private detective who's trying to solve a crime and catch the criminals
I need to know what crime is
it's that bad point here
crime is what we were solving before this conversation began
why would anyone want to read a crime
they fight it to people I guess
they get to imagine dangerous things and it's kind of like a puzzle where you can guess who the criminal is or how the good guys are going to catch him
I'm a policeman myself by the way
I don't look much like a policeman
I know
well what does a cop look like then
didn't mean to offend sir
sorry sir
it's just that you don't look like dick mullin
she points to a book cover
I wish you can see strapping vespertine officer
he stems grinly over the body of a dead woman
you know nobody actually looks like the guy in the picture
it's not your body that's important in police work
it's your head