hello and welcome back to our therapist plays disco elicium
let's play
if you're new here
hello my name is brady
I'm a therapist and we're doing kind of like a long forum psycho analysis of our main character and all the people that we meet in our twisted weird journey through revishol in disco elicium
so on today's episode we're kind of getting deeper into the analysis and actually kind of targeting our companion kim who at least in my playthrough and the way I'm sort of roleplaying this character
we don't have like the most trusting relationship with yet and kind of getting into the psychology of like what does it mean to want to trust someone but not be sure if you can yet
and how does someone who has a lot of like prior trauma like our main character does actually evaluate whether or not someone who promises to be there on your side is actually trustworthy in what they say
so today I'm gonna give you kind of a mix of psychological theory behind this idea and also how I would actually address something like this in practice as a therapist
so that said let's continue
okay so what do I need to do
I need to ask
I need to solve this murder
I got to be honest like the the murder is like the lowest priority thing to my character right now
I genuinely believe that if I'm this character
the murder is just a vehicle to discover more about who I was and in that process reckoning with the idea that I may have done something to myself to try to forget that person and here I'm spending a lot of time trying to figure that out
I could go do
oh I can go
do the autopsy
I have the gloves and I have the form
maybe I should do that
I'm just collecting tasks jam mystery
I kind of want to go see the body
let's do the autopsy real quick
I have all the ingredients I need
let's see what happens
maybe it'll tell us something provide us information
the rotting man lies on his side with his eyes looking straight through you
the belt is still around his neck
his body is supine and open to intrusion by autopsy
it's a good turn of