hello and welcome to my therapist plays disco lissium analysis series
so on today's episode the plot sign we are going to see if we can establish our authority with tidus the union boss
we're going to see if we can get a little closer to a confession from him on who exactly was involved with the murder in march of mays
and over on the analysis side we're going to be taking a deep dive into the rigorous self - critique thought
now that we finally internalize this one it opens the door for a lot of discussion on harry's sense of self
and kind of digging into the question of is he actually a good person
and if he's not let's see think that it's possible to become one
this one's a little bit heavier on the analysis but it's pretty exciting to finally peel back more layers of our character
so let's jump in
any predictions on where the story will go or who's the killer
I kind of had the idea that we would be somewhat involved in the killing like because we are so uninitiated to our own past
I don't think that we did it like would have hung him up like that but I sort of have the suspicion that the dock workers are kind of like a red hairing
I just don't buy it
that's what we're leading but that could be wrong
I am notoriously bad at predicting the plot of anything ever
like when you have already probably noticed this but like when politics or the plot are part of the dialogue my brain like it does this
it feels like it condenses down to like I've had to do this before where I'm like okay what is happening here
my brain is just equipped for like character analysis
and the way I engage with media just privately is like when I'm watching something I'm not really thinking about the plot
I'm very rarely like well I'm not like watching shutter island and I'm like where is this going
I wonder what's going to happen next
my brain just like accepts whatever's going to happen but what I'm thinking about is like wow what is that character feeling right now
I wonder how like whatever is going to happen to them is going to change their worldview
like that's more where my mind is focused
and I kind of just accept the plot whatever it is
it doesn't matter that much to me
the sequence of things happening
unless it is so egregious that I'm like this doesn't make any sense
what if it was lena
well I refuse to accept that
lena is too kind hard and good - natured for her to be involved in that
it's funny therapists often seem to struggle with things like predicting stuff or telling if someone is lying