hello and welcome to my therapist plays disco elicio and analysis series
so on today's episode I'm very excited because we are finally getting to use one of my absolute favorite frameworks for analyzing characters
this is something that I use in therapy from time to time and it's an incredible way to explore patterns of psychology and patterns of behavior and sort of really uncover what is driving a lot of the complexes that we see play out in harry's thoughts and his actions
and the reason we were doing that now is because we are starting to learn more about ourselves and our past
we're going to take another look at that ledger and see what do we actually think about the person that we used to be before
we became a sorry cop
all that's coming up so let's jump back in
oh there it is
we are back
we are so back
I'm so excited
okay so we are back in the game now
I just wanted to say the community that has arrived around like this game and specifically this playthrough continues to amaze me especially after last episode was like a lot of politics talk and I was very like anxious avoidant of talking about politics
I have been very encouraged by the response to that last episode to like not be so anxious about it
I still don't know if I'm going to like start getting full political but I will try not to like avoid it in the game because of my personal issues with getting political
I'll just say that
I won't let it divert the game because at the end of the day I want to talk about like mental health and there's probably some interesting avenues in the narrative of the game that will miss out on if I just totally ignore it
however I will say this game is so wonderfully designed that you have a main character who has a real backstory
he's not like a blank slate like I thought that he was going to be from the beginning
he has his own backstory and at the same time it allows you to have your own beliefs and to and the character will like have the same behavioral patterns
like genuinely imagine if like literally brady was the detective
imagine it what you know about me so far
how I would go about solving a murder would be exactly like you've seen it like I would spend crazy amounts of time on things that you just wouldn't like do