hello and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
so on today's episode we are delving even deeper into the psychology of our main character
is this case gets more complicated so does our relationship with ourselves because we're also going to start discovering more about who we were and finding that we are not so happy with that person before we had our amnesia and woke up as the person we are today
and so what does it mean to be faced with some of those challenges
do we avoid them and try to shut them out or do we look for healthy ways to integrate them and move forward
but we also do get into major confrontation
we're going to face what it is like when we go up against an individual named measurehead who stands between us and our next objective in solving the case
so all that is coming up in today's episode
and perhaps our first moments of genuine trust is starting to build between ourselves and our partner kip
I'm excited to continue this journey with all of you
so let's jump in
hey there's a big gentleman
we have right to
maybe this is the gentleman who was asking about our case
he's a large lad
what's going on here
hold up and stay front
the broad shoulder to alpha male turns to you
he's a full head taller than everybody else here
you here to fuck with us
beat the honest worker down
why should I
I hear the fight for a cause
stripes usually have problems with people who have causes
okay then I think I think no
I want to be on your team friend
good
we're fighting for a cause here
right to work
besides we're not that different
it helps if people see us talking cops and strikebreakers together
shows with our days around our side
builds confidence
I like his perspective
I agree
I agree with that
I think it's also kind of a power play that I'm like grinding the flashlight and everybody's face because it makes them feel like I'm really targeting them which is good for my interrogation
what kind of cause are we talking about
rights of workers to have gainful employment to make a salary and feed their families
well I don't want to politically align with him but I want to be on his team