okay hello and also welcome
it's great to be back on stream and continuing our disco elicium playthrough
if you're just joining us which is a good chance that you are this is kind of still at the beginning of our little playthrough here
and what we're doing is we're kind of playing through it like mix of roleplay mix of psychoanalysis
I'm brady
I'm a therapist
and I'm going to be doing like different kinds of psychoanalysis on the characters and kind of linking that to the game design and like how it represents mental health
this game is just in another leak when it comes to that sort of thing so far
like I already did a video kind of talking about the skill system and how it represents this like very fascinating way to perceive like motivation and psychological priority
so yeah we're like we're going to get pretty deep with this
the last two playthroughs or last two streams
I'm sort of just been figuring out the game and now that I've like had some time to collect some thoughts on it I'll be talking a little bit more about the characters and their dynamics and like I guess why my character specifically is showing a lot of avoidance and confrontation and like is not maybe making some of the best decisions
I'm doing like a mix of my own head can in roleplay
like I'm not trying to play the game the best way
honestly I'm just trying to make this a fun fun playthrough like just kind of doing wild shit
we're not going to see every single part of the game or every dialogue tree and that's okay you know
but it has been great to get some recommendations for things that like I just straight out missed because of like so far my character has just fallen into like he's just failing upwards basically
like passing some of the early skill checks some of the comments on the last video were telling me that like missing or succeeding in some of these early skill checks has like made me skip over a lot of tutorials which makes sense because I kind of feel lost on some of the systems
but that's okay
we're discovering it as we go and I think that just makes for interesting playthrough dynamics
what I have been fascinated by is how well the game has responded to my like weird way of approaching this
like it's completely fine that I skipped certain things
it's completely fine that I don't know how to play it very well
it's not like I've not reached a roadblock where the game is like hey slow down friend
I need to teach you this before you move on and it's happy to just let me move on and try to fail my way through everything which is kind of life isn't it
so with that said