okay hello and welcome back to our playthrough of disco elisium
we just finished the first little chunk of the game kind of starting our character
and yeah just figuring out who he is in this wild disgusting world and how wild and disgusting are we going to be to kind of meet the world where it's at
so I've sort of decided that the the character profile we're going with is like x or failed therapist turned dirty cop
kind of the idea like I tried to be a therapist but I found it was too easy to manipulate people or the more I learned about people the more
I could not help the urge to exploit that stuff
so I became a cop instead where I can hide behind a moral or duty justification for getting information from people
and I can sort of code that as this is a good thing for me and them
I'm actually protecting them by figuring out their dark secrets
so that's kind of where we're at
let's continue
and keep working on the scrim here
literally just came back at the perfect time
hell yeah let's let's look and go
okay let's check out the crime scene a little bit more here
get some cash lying around
never going to let that go to waste
some more magnesium
I think if we're going to need to stock up on magnesium this winch mechanism has been oxidating for some years
the kid's ladder is climbable
okay not too much interesting going on around here
let's check out the body
with bulging white eyes the face around them does not look human
it's swollen and ready to burst
his lips are fish like and his tongue like a ball gag in his mouth
okay it's pretty gruesome
you seem to be holding your breath
a cargo belt twists his neck at an unnatural angle
the body below appears stiff
it's letting out an ungodly rot
the smell seeps in even through your clenched nostrils
legendary let's go of your nose without throwing up
that's 17 % and has not steered me wrong yet