hello and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elicium analysis series
in today's episode we are going to be taking a very thorough look at how disco elicium portrays intrusive thinking when electrochemistry starts giving us thoughts and they are very much opposed to the thoughts of volition and how this actually very accurately represents some of our very real thinking patterns
so we are going to be using actual theory to break this down using the cognitive model how actual cognitive behavioral therapy works and how we might apply it to a situation that our detective finds himself in with his own intrusive thinking
this one is going to be quite in depth so I am excited to get into it instead of it
alright
so what we need to do now is figure out where to go this door he wants me to bust down
oh there is an end of day debrief
kim can answer any lingering questions you may have about the case in the rcm
join him in the whirling and rags balcony after 10
so what time is it
it's almost 10 so we have got a little bit of time before we can do that
do we have enough money to pay back
mr guards
do we have enough do we have oh it's got a ton of trash
let's go turn in the trash
let's pay a visit to the best character in this entire game
ritter girl
let's see what she's up to and let's get some money
yeah we're not accepting that bribe fuck that guy
I don't care we'll solve our many problems through rigorous environmentalism
I believe I am supposed to talk to this gentleman first though let's see what he's got to say
so how'd you like our harbor
that was nice enough