okay hello
and welcome back to our therapist plays disco elysium
let's play series
if you are new here then hello welcome
my name is brady
I'm a therapist
and we are doing like kind of a long form psychoanalysis of the main character and his companions and all the people that we meet on our journey through revisual
so in today's episode we're going to talk a lot about like our main characters reflections on his own self identity as we sort of start to unpack and discover things that he is remembering about his past
and psychologically what does it mean to integrate a past version of yourself who you may not have a lot of positive feelings about into the identity that you're building today
and also we're going to see if we can take another shot this whole thing with guna
so let's dive in
now one thing that is kind of a hanging thread is I want to return to my bedroom while I'm here
we're playing the game like reading some psychological class material
yeah if you're new to the euro brady experience this is one part entertainment one part master's level psychology lecture one part my own self therapy life or your enjoyment
read the problem part let's do that
let's rewind
let's trace your drunken steps back home jump across the raised channel bridge southwest of here fall over get up get off the asphalt in 20 minutes shuffle your feet through court yards scaring little children that checks out
go under the great raised motor tract the 881 until you reach the domain a mineral in north jamrock
the streets are frozen this time of year caked with ice walked down main to perdition
there's a side alley there in your footprints in the mud
okay there's something there
there is a past for me
okay what is this
kim also tries not to look at the pile of take viscera on the carpet or the weird suitcase on the hat rack or the pocket plant dying in the corner but it's all just too morbid to ignore
oh that's true
this is the first time I've brought kim into the environment
maybe in a subconscious way I'm trying to understand again how much can I destroy my own image to him before I come to the conclusion that he's not going to abandon me
maybe if I show him something intimate and disgusting