hello and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elisium analysis series
okay I'm really excited about today's episode
we're finally getting into our first encounter with the union boss everart claire and kind of breaking down lots of different psychological angles on power dynamics and have a lot to share today on real techniques that I actually use in my practice as a therapist to navigate sort of like difficult conversations with people who either don't want to talk to you or are in some sort of power struggle and how do you sort of get that person opening up about things we're going to use some of this techniques on mr claire
and by the end of this episode we're going to learn a little bit more about ourselves and what kind of comp we are
yes we're finally getting our copo type
I'm sure a very few of you will be surprised at what I end up with
so I'm excited to share this one
let's dive in
okay so I have an objective
I have the objective to progress this game's storyline
like I do want to just like mention why I am going about playing this game this way because I do think it's relevant when you see my character do things like just totally give up on pursuing the narrative to try to find like cigarettes for example
this is a roleplay right
so sometimes I'm going to be speaking as like brady the therapist
sometimes I'm going to be speaking as like brady the degenerate who is using this as a kind of escapism from my very serious real life that I like this is where I get to give me a goofball
and sometimes I'm going to like speak from the voice of my character right
and just like say random nonsense garbage that I think he would say or think right
and one of the things that is really important about this character specifically because he is someone representing the struggle of addiction is how like we have all kinds of priority structures in our mind right
like there's the whole just basic needs hierarchy of like you need food you need water you need rest
and only once those things are satisfied
can you really focus on like higher order things like you know your self - esteem and your self - worth and the balance of health and your relationships and those sorts of things right
the problem with addiction is that your body has become dependent on a chemical one that's harmful to you