okay hello and welcome to the beginning of a special playthrough of a game that I have been kind of like talking about with my community to play for a very long time
it is disco elisium
if you are just discovering the channel based on this which is a good likelihood that you are my name is brady I'm a therapist and we are going to be doing like kind of a long form
analysis of the game that we are going to play we will probably play other games in the future as well
and we tend to ask a lot of questions kind of in the space of like okay so let's imagine this character was my client
like what sort of things do I think that they would be dealing with
what sort of approach would I use to help them
right so that's kind of what we are going to be getting into and I also myself am interested in creative writing
I would say like I'm an aspiring writer
I have a bit of an imposter syndrome around like I don't know if I'd call myself an author or not
I did write a science fiction novel a couple years ago
it's finished
I didn't publish it and I don't know if I will at this point
it's just so old now that it would need like a full rewrite and you know I still keep telling myself to go back and rewrite it or write something new
and I know that that kind of parallels just go elysium as like this is not your average game writing
there's a big focus on pros from what I can tell
I don't know anything about the story
I actually don't even really know anything about the setting
the only things I really know about it is that it has a lot of a claim a lot of for its like creative aspects for its like prosaic dialogue and narration
and that it's kind of a crpg
I like crpgs
I'm a fan of baldur's gate and divinity series
I played original sin too a couple years ago
fantastic game
I'm currently playing through baldur's gate 3
really enjoyed pillars of eternity as well
so those kinds of games I'm really into and we have tried to play games on stream before but just by the nature of like
you know discussing things from a therapeutic perspective
they can go quite long
so I'm going to be trying to keep my thoughts a little more focused and concise
but yeah I hope you enjoy what you see here today
we're going to be uploading this kind of periodically
and if you want to come check out the stream
see it live
we're welcome to do so as well
so yeah
let's do it
let's get into it
let's go
I'm ready
oh there it is
got my little brady box in the corner there
hey brady haven't seen you live in quite a while looking forward to you playing this