Okay, let's talk about why we make bad decisions.
So if you're like me, then you've probably been
in that situation where it's the end of the day
or it's the morning and you're thinking like,
okay, I'm gonna make a solid plan for myself.
Today, I'm gonna be disciplined.
I'm gonna come home from work
and I'm gonna get all these errands done
and I'm gonna treat myself really well.
I'm gonna make a nice healthy, proper meal.
I'm gonna go to the gym afterwards.
I'm gonna exercise and then maybe when I come home,
I'll like start reading a book or something.
I'll do something a little different,
something that makes me feel like I'm gonna advance my life
in a new positive direction.
And this is our real life volition
and it's there to lead you on your way
to making good life decisions.
But this doesn't always work out that way.
Sometimes you get to the end of the day
and you realize that you haven't been very disciplined.
At all, a lot of those errands are still
incomplete or like half-started.
We didn't end up going to the gym
and instead of making a proper meal,
we've ordered some definitely not healthy takeout food.
And instead of reading that book,
maybe you end up watching a show you've already seen
and we've not advanced our life
in a positive meaningful direction in any way at all.
What is happening here?
Why would we ignore the voice of volition
that's telling us to do all of these
beneficial positive things?
Well, it could be a lot of things honestly
and definitely having like a mental health diagnosis
is going to amplify this problem a lot more.
But even for the average person,
this happens like pretty often.
I mean, it certainly happens to me.
So what I wanted to share with you today
is a framework for understanding why this problem happens
and what we can actually do about it.
This is a real problem that actually comes up
in my work as a therapist kind of often.
And I have really enjoyed seeing it demonstrated
so clearly and given such a unique role
within the structure of a game like Disco Elysium has.
So okay, there is a reason that we do not always follow
the voice of volition and go through
with our good intentions.
And it has to do with something called psychological friction.
So in this context, friction is any force
either internal or external,
which opposes a behavioral change.
So what do we know about like regular friction, right?
If I am standing on an ice rink
and I move my body weight around a little bit,
I'm gonna start sliding around on the ice.
There's not a lot of friction between me
and the surface that's under me.
When I step off the ice and now I'm standing on concrete,