okay
hello
and welcome to
kind of like a special little interlude episode that
I wanted to put out before
the next Disco Elysium stream goes live
so this is something I may do from time to time
kind of like taking
a chunk of the analysis and putting it in its own video
sometimes because it takes me a while
to sort of collect my thoughts on things
and it doesn't always happen
like while we're live on stream
but also because
I can kind of already foresee that this
playthrough of Disco Elysium is going to be
quite long going at our usual pace
and I know it can be pretty hard to get into
a let's play
when it's like episode 30
or something and so if you weren't really
there for the beginning of it
it's kinda hard to hop in
that far down the line so
I thought it would be cool to kind of like do
like little chunks of our
character studies and
like analysis of the games
systems like how they represent different
parts of mental health like
just as their own separate videos
basically for the people who can't commit the time to watch
all of the let's play videos or
can't make it to the streams or that sort of thing
they can still enjoy
kind of the psychological breakdown parts of it so
that's what we're gonna be doing today
there's something that
I have to talk about basically like
I just couldn't really wait until
the next time I get on stream to talk about it
so that's what we're gonna do now
okay so there is something that Disco Elysium does
in its portrayal of a very specific aspect of mental health
that I have never seen portrayed this way
anywhere else
so one of the biggest challenges when talking about
anything related to mental health
whether depression mental illness addiction
is it can sometimes be really hard to explain
how can you want something
you could desperately want to not be depressed
you can desperately want to be sober
and yet sometimes our behaviors really don't agree with that desire
and how you explain that to someone that
you sitting there wondering like
all I want in the world is to stop using
but I just can't
and this is kind of
you know a mentality that I imagine like our
lead detective
having been in at some point
before he lost his memory
and at least in my playthrough
it's something he's still struggling with right
as he does whatever he can find a pack of cigarettes
and for me it comes down to this
we tend to have a very limited
way of talking about the subject of motivation
like why you actually do things why you want things
and this is where Disco Elysium comes into the picture
with these different aspects of the main character psyche who
seem to have different
motivations for him
and they influence you as the player to sort of
follow different paths
one motivation in terms of the authority voice will tell you like
you need to smack that kid right