hello
and welcome to another episode
in my therapist plays disco elysium analysis serie
so this time I wanted to share something
that I learned about particular character in the game and
also some things that I learned about myself
in the course of uploading this series
so just for context if you're just come into this now
the way I'm kind of playing through the game
is from like the perspective of being a therapist
and trying to provide as much commentary as I can on
different angles of mental health that are depicted in the game
there's a lot more going on than just that at the disco elysium
but I'm really just I'm not the person
to comment on like complicated political stuff
and one of the most important dynamics in the game
is the one that you have with your partner Kim Kitsuragi
and I recognize that like as the player
we're going to be a lot more aware of
Kim's qualities than my character the detective well
and so in my role play of him
I've sort of been exploring the subject of
someone who is coming from a background of trauma
which we still don't know a lot
about Raphael from where I'm at in the game
but a lot of his issues with the way he views authority and relationships
and his struggles with substance abuse
kind of indicate that
there may be some of that background present
so I've been kind of approaching a lot of the dialogue
with Kim from this perspective
that like we tend to have an initial first impression about someone
that we may want to trust them
but if we're someone who has a lot of trust issues
we may sort of like test that relationship over time
we may kind of see where the real boundaries are
and from my character's perspective
he's kind of been trying to see like this
this Kim's sticking around with me
because he needs me to complete this case
or are the qualities that we immediately picked up on that
he is earnest and trustworthy
and a very honest character at hearts
are those things going to last
when we make ourselves very difficult to be around basically
I'm definitely going to ask him
I really want to impress him
and I want him to think that I'm cool
and that I'm not a fucking ass
I've been kind of trying to demonstrate that
like some of the closest relationships you can have
are ones that have really been put through that test
and have outlasted that period of
like if I push this person far enough
are they still gonna stick with me
a sigh the lieutenant buries his nose in his notebook
see there's another thing that that I'm not sure about Kim
the way that she spoke to me just now
she's giving an honest reflection
and she's empathizing with me
whereas Kim is showing me disappointment
and he's showing me mistrust