okay
hello
and welcome back to our playthrough of disco elysium
we just finished kind of like the first little chunk of the game
kind of starting our character
and yeah just figuring out who he is
in this wild disgusting world
and how wild and disgusting are we going to be to
kind of meet the world where it's at
so I've sort of decided that the character profile
we're going with is like
ex or failed therapist turned dirty cop
kind of the idea like
I tried to be a therapist
but I found it was too easy to manipulate people
or the more I learned about people
the more I could not help the urge to exploit that stuff
so I became a cop instead
where I can hide behind a moral or duty justification
for getting information from people
and I can sort of code that as
this is a good thing for me and them
I'm actually protecting them by figuring out their dark secrets
so that's kind of where we're at
let's continue
keep working on this crime here
literally just came back at the perfect time hell yeah
let's fucking go
okay let's check out the crime scene a little bit more here
get some cash lying around
never gonna let that go to waste
some more magnesium
I'm thinking we're gonna need to stock up on magnesium
this winch mechanism has been oxidating for some years
the kids ladder is climbable
okay not too much interesting going on around here
let's check out the body
...with bulging white eyes
the face around them does not look human
it's swollen and ready to burst
his lips are fish like
and his tongue like a bull gag in his mouth
pretty gruesome
you seem to be holding your breath
a cargo belt twists his neck at an unnatural angle
the body below appears stiff
it's letting out an ungodly rot
the smell seeps in even through your clenched nostrils
legendary let go of your nose without throwing up
that 17 percent
has not steered me wrong yet