okay
hello
and welcome to the beginning of
a special playthrough of
a game that I have been
kind of like talking about with my community
to play for a very long time
it is Disco Elysium
if you are just discovering the channel
based on this which is a good likelihood that you are
my name is Brady
I'm a therapist
and we are gonna be doing like kind of a long form
analysis of the game that we're gonna play
we'll probably play out the games in the future as well
and we tend to ask a lot of
questions kind of in the space of
okay so
let's imagine this character was my client
like what sort of things
do I think that they would be dealing with
what sort of approach would I use to help them
so that's kind of what we're gonna be getting into and
I also myself am interested in creative writing
I would say like
I'm an aspiring writer
I have a bit of an imposture syndrome around like
I don't know if I'd call myself an author or not
I did write a science fiction novel a couple years ago
it's finished
I didn't publish it
and I don't know if I will at this point
it's just so old
now that it would need like a full rewrite and
I still keep telling myself
to go back and rewrite it or write something new
and I know that that kind of parallels Disco Elysium as like
this is not your average game writing like
there's a big focus on prose from what I can tell
I don't know anything about the story
I actually don't even really know anything about the setting
the only things I really know about it is that it has
a lot of acclaim a lot of for its like creative
aspects for its like prosaic dialogue and narration
and that it's kind of a CRPG
I like CRPGs I'm a fan of Baldurs Gate and
Divinity series
I played original sin 2 a couple years ago
fantastic game
I'm currently playing through Boulders Gate 3
really enjoyed pillars of eternity as well
so
those kinds of games I'm really into and
we have tried to play games on stream before but
just by the nature of like
discussing things from a therapeutic perspective
they can go quite long
so I'm gonna be trying to keep my thoughts a little more
focused and concise
but yeah I hope you enjoy what you see here today
we're gonna be uploading this
kind of periodically and if you want to come
check out the stream
see it live you're welcome to do so as well
so yeah let's do it
let's get into it
let's go I'm ready
oh there it is
got my little Brady box in the corner there
hey Brady I haven't seen you live in quite a while