hello
and welcome to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
on today's episode we are meeting what has become
another one of my absolute favorite characters that we've met so far
so we're gonna be talking a lot with Annette and her mother today
learning more about the economic reality
of being a child who has to work out in the cold all day
and in that dialogue we're also gonna be continuing to build our own character profile
sort of continuing the analysis using the JaharI window that we started in the last episode
there's a lot of emotions to dig into and discuss in today's episode
including some that may come up when we finally face ourselves
so that's where we're at I'm excited to continue so
let's jump back in
okay
what shall we do next
I guess we can go enter the green the door behind the greenhouse
let's go do that
it's in the yard basement door is that back there
yeah it's more useful in counseling
what's this girl up to it's been a while since we've checked in
every snowflake is like a little gift from the sky
she is way too positive
oh it's snowing
what is this crime business
crime fiction is about murders or burglaries or things like that
and the work of a policeman or a private detective
who's trying to solve a crime and catch the criminals
I need to know what *crime* is
it's that bad (point to your head)
crime is what we were solving before this conversation began
why would anyone want to *read* about crime
it's exciting to people I guess
they get to imagine dangerous things
and it's kind of like a puzzle where you can guess who the criminal is
or how the good guys are going to catch him
i'm a policeman myself by the way
you don't look much like a policeman
I know
well what does a cop look like then
didn't mean to offend sir sorry sir
it's just that you don't look like Dick Mullen
she points to a book cover on which you can see strapping Vespertine officer
he stands grimly over the body of a dead woman
you know nobody actually looks like the guy in the picture
it's not your body that's important in police work
it's your head