okay
hello
and welcome back to our uh
therapist plays Disco Elysium let's play series
if you are new here then hello welcome
my name is Brady I'm a therapist
and we are doing like kind of a long form
psychoanalysis of the main character
and his companions and all the people
that we meet on our journey through Revachol
so in today's episode
we're going to talk a lot about
like our main characters reflections on his own self identity
as we sort of start to unpack and discover
things that he is remembering about his past and
psychologically what does it mean to
integrate a past version of yourself who you may not
have a lot of positive feelings about
into the identity that you're building today
and also we're gonna see if we could take
another shot this whole thing with Cuno
so
let's dive in
now one thing that is a kind of a hanging thread is
I want to return to my bedroom while I'm here
we're playing the game like reading some
psychological class material
yeah if you're new to the eurobrady experience
this is one part entertainment
one part Masters level psychology lecture
one part my own
self therapy life
for your enjoyment
read the problem part let's do that
let's rewind let's trace your drunken steps back home
jump across the raised channel bridge southwest of here
fall over get up
get off the asphalt in 20 minutes
shuffle your feet through courtyards
scaring little children
that checks out
go under the great raised motor tract the 8/81
until you reach Le Domaine Aminol in north Jamrock
the streets are frozen this time of year caked with ice
walk down Main to Perdition
there's a side alley there
and your footprints in the mud
okay
there's something there
there is a past for me
okay
this
Kim also tries not to look at the pile of tape viscera on the carpet
or the weird suitcase on the hat rack
or the pottic plant dying in the corner
but it's all just too morbid to ignore
oh that's true
this is the first time I've brought Kim into the environment
maybe in a subconscious way I'm trying to understand again
how much can I destroy my own image to him
before I come to the conclusion that he's not going to abandon me
maybe if I show him