hello
and welcome back to my therapist plays
Disco Elysium analysis series
so on today's episode
we are delving even deeper into the psychology of
our main character
as this case gets more complicated
so does our relationship with ourselves
because we're also going to start
discovering more about who we were and
finding that we are not so happy with that person
before we had amnesia
and woke up as the person we are today
and so what does it mean
to be faced with some of those challenges
do we avoid them and try to shut them out
or do we look for
healthy ways to integrate them and move forward
but we also do get into a major confrontation
we're going to face
what it is like when we go up
against an individual named Measurehead
who stands between us and
our next objective in solving the case
so all that is coming up in today's episode and
perhaps our first moments of
genuine trust starting to build between ourselves and our partner Kim
I'm excited to continue this journey with all of you so
let's jump in
hey there's a big gentleman
bastards
we have a right to work
maybe this is the gentleman who
was asking about our case is a large lad
what's going on here
hold up and stay frosty everyone
cops are here
the broad shouldered alpha male turns to you
he's a full head taller than everybody else here
you here to fuck with us
beat the honest worker down
why should I
we're here to fight for a cause
stripes usually have problems with people who have causes
okay then I think I
I think no I want to be on your team friend
good
we're fighting for a cause here
right to work
besides
we're not that different
it helps if people see us talking
cops and strikebringers together
shows authorities around our side
builds confidence
I like his perspective I agree
I agree with that
I think it's also kind of a power play that
I'm like grinding the flashlight in everybody's face
because it makes them feel like I'm really targeting them
which is good for my interrogation
what kind of problems are we talking about
rights of workers to have gainful employment
to make a salary
and feed their families
well I don't want to politically align with him