hello
and welcome to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
so on today's episode I'm very excited
because we are finally getting to use one of my absolute
favorite frameworks for analyzing characters
this is something that I use in therapy from time to time
and it's an incredible way to explore patterns of psychology and patterns of behavior
and sort of really uncover what is driving a lot of the complexes
that we see play out in Harry's thoughts and his actions
and the reason we are doing that now is
because we are starting to learn more about ourselves and our past
and take another look at that Ledger
and see what do we actually think about the person that we used to be
before we became a sorry cop
all that's coming up
so let's jump back in
oh there it is there it is we are back
we're so back
and I'm so excited
okay so we are back in the game now
I just wanted to say
the community that has arrived around this game and specifically
this playthrough continues to amaze me
especially after last episode was like a lot of politics talk
and I was very like anxious avoidant of talking about politics
I have been very encouraged by the response to that last episode to like
not be so anxious about it
I don't I still don't know
if I'm gonna like start getting full political
but I will try not to to like avoid it in the game because of my personal
issues with getting political
I'll just say that
I won't let it divert the game
because at the end of the day I want to talk about like mental health
and there's probably some interesting avenues in the narrative of the game
that will miss out on if I just totally ignore it
however I will say this game is
so wonderfully designed that you
you have a main character who has a real backstory
he's not like a blank slate
like I thought that he was gonna be from the beginning
he has his own backstory and at the same time
it allows you to have your own beliefs
and the character will like have the same behavioral patterns
like genuinely imagine
if like literally Brady was the detective
imagine
what you know about me so far
I would go about solving a murder
would be exactly like you've seen it
like I would spend crazy amounts of time
on things that you just wouldn't like you