hello
and welcome back to my
therapist plays Disco Elysium analysis series
okay I'm really excited about today's episode
we're finally getting into our first
encounter with the union boss Evrart Claire
and kind of breaking down lots of different
psychological angles on power dynamics and
have a lot to share today on real techniques that
I actually use in my practice as a therapist
to navigate sort of like difficult conversations with people who
either don't want to talk to you
or are in some sort of power struggle
and how do you sort of get that person opening up about things
we're gonna use some of these techniques on Mister Claire
and by the end of this episode
we're going to learn a little bit more about
ourselves and what kind of cop we are
yes we're finally getting our cop type
I'm sure very few of you will be surprised at what I end up with
so I'm excited to share this one
let's dive in
okay so
I have an objective
I have the objective to progress this game storyline like
I do want to
just like
mention why I am going about playing this game this way
because I do think it's relevant
when you see my character
do things like just totally give up on pursuing the narrative
to try to find like cigarettes for example
this is a role play right
so sometimes I'm gonna be speaking as like Brady the therapist
sometimes I'm gonna be speaking as like
Brady the degenerate who is using this as a kind of
escapism from my very serious real life
that I
like this is where I get to give be a goofball
and sometimes I'm gonna like
speak from the voice of my character right
and just like
say random nonsense garbage that I think he would
say or think right
and one of the things that
it is really important about
this character specifically because he is
someone representing the struggle of addiction is how like
we have all kinds of priority structures in our mind
right like
there's the whole just basic needs hierarchy of
like you need food you need water you need rest
and only once those things are satisfied
can you really focus on like higher order things like
you know your self esteem and your self worth and
the balance of health and your relationships
and those sorts of things right
the problem with addiction is that
your body has become dependent on on a chemical
one that is harmful to you
and so it completely hijacks what should be a normal