okay
hello and also welcome
it's great to be back on stream
and continuing our Disco Elysium play through
if you're just joining us
which is a good chance that you are
this is kind of still at the beginning of our little play through here
and what we're doing is we're kind of playing through it like
mix of role play mix of psychoanalysis
I'm Brady I'm a therapist
and I'm going to be doing different kinds of
psychoanalysis on the characters
and kind of linking that to the game design
and like how it represents mental health
this game is just in another league
when it comes to that sort of thing so far like
I already did a video
kind of talking about the skill system and how it represents this like
very fascinating way to perceive like
motivation and psychological priority
so yeah we're like
we're gonna get pretty deep with this
the last two playthroughs or last two streams
I'm sort of just been figuring out the game and
now that I've like had some time to collect some thoughts on it
I'll be talking a little bit more about the
the characters and their dynamics and
like I guess why my character specifically is
showing a lot of avoidance and confrontation and like
is not maybe making some of the best decisions
I'm doing like a mix of my own headcanon role play like
I'm not trying to play the game the best way
honestly I'm just trying to make this fun
a fun play through like just kind of doing wild shit
we're not going to see every single part of the game
or every dialogue tree
and that's okay you know
but it has been great to get some recommendations
for things that like I just straight out missed
because of like
so far my character has just fallen into like
he's just failing upwards basically
like passing some of the early skill checks
some of the comments on the last video were telling me that like
missing or succeeding in some of these early skill checks has like
made me skip over a lot of tutorials
which makes sense
because I kind of feel lost on some of the systems
but that's okay
we're discovering it as we go
and I think that just makes for interesting play through dynamics
what I have been fascinated by is how well
the game has responded to my
weird way of approaching
it's completely fine that I skipped certain things
it's completely fine
that I don't know how to play it very well
it's not like
I've not reached a roadblock
where the game is like hey slow down friend
I need to teach you this before you move on
and it's happy to just let me move on and
try to fail my way through everything which
is kind of life
isn't it