hello
and welcome back to our therapist plays Disco Elysium
let's play if you're new here
hello my name is Brady
I'm a therapist
and we're doing kind of like a long forum
psychoanalysis of our main character
and all of the people that we meet in
our twisted weird journey through Revachol in Disco Elysium
so on today's episode we're kind of getting
deeper into the analysis
and actually kind of targeting our companion Kim
who at least in my play through
and the way I'm sort of role playing this character
we don't have like the most trusting relationship with yet and
kind of getting into the psychology of like
what does it mean to
want to trust someone
but not be sure if you can yet
and how does
someone who has a lot of like prior trauma
like our main character does
actually evaluate whether or not someone
who promises to be there on your side
is actually trustworthy in what they say
so today I'm going to give you
kind of a mix of psychological theory behind this idea
and also
how I would actually address something like this
in practice as a therapist
so with that is
let's continue
so
what do I need to do
I need to ask okay I need to solve this murder
I gotta be honest like the
the murder is like the lowest priority thing
to my character right now
I genuinely believe that if I'm this character
the murder is just a vehicle
to discover more about who I was
and in that process
reckoning with the idea that I may have done something
to myself to try to forget that person
and here I'm spending a lot of time
trying to figure that out
I could go do
I can go do the autopsy
I have the gloves and I have the form
maybe I should do that
the size of it to do list
I know I'm just collecting tasks
jam mystery
I kind of want to go see the body
let's do the autopsy real quick
I have all the ingredients I need
let's see what happens
maybe it will tell us something provide us information
the rotting man lies on his side
with his eyes looking straight through you
the belt is still around his neck
his body is supplying and open to intrusion by autopsy