hello
and welcome to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
so on today's episode
the plot signed we are going to
see if we can establish our authority with Titus the union boss
we're gonna see if we can get a little closer to a confession from him on
who exactly was involved with the murder in Martinez
and over on the analysis side
we're gonna be taking a deep dive into the rigorous self critique thought
now that we've finally internalized this one
it opens the door for a lot of discussion on
Harry's sense of self
and kind of digging into the question of
is he actually a good person
and if he's not
does  he think that it's possible to become one
this one's a little bit heavier on the analysis
这一点在分析中占比会更大
but it's pretty exciting to finally peel back more layers of our character
so let's jump in
any predictions on where the story will go or who's the killer
I kind of had the idea
that we would be somewhat involved in the killing like
because we are so uninitiated to our own past
I don't think that we did it like would have hung him up like that
but I sort of have the suspicion that
the dock workers are kind of like a red herring
I just don't buy it
that's that's what we're leading
but I could be wrong
I am notoriously bad at predicting the plot
of anything ever like
when you have already probably noticed this
but like when politics or the plot are part of the dialogue
my brain like
it does this it feels like
it condenses down to like
I have to I've had to do this before
where I’m like  okay what is happening here
my brain is just equipped for like character or an analysis
and the way I engage with media just privately
is like when I’m watching something
I’m not really thinking about the plot
I’m very rarely like what
I’m not like watching shutter island
and I’m like where is this going
I wonder what's gonna happen next
my brain just like accepts whatever's going to happen
but what I’m thinking about
is like wow what is that character feeling right now
you know
I wonder how like
whatever is going to happen to them
is going to change their worldview
like it's that's more where my mind is focused
and I kind of just accept the plot
whatever it is it doesn't that matter that much to me
the sequence of things happening
unless it is so egregious that I’m like this doesn't make any sense
what if it was Lena well
I refuse to accept that
Lena is too kind hearted and good natured
for her to be involved in that
（读chat）“有趣的是 心理治疗师们似乎很抗拒做这种事
it's funny therapists often seem to struggle with things like
predicting stuff or telling if someone is lying well