hello
and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
so on today's episode
we're getting deeper into our different character studies
and kind of breaking down like the psychological dynamics
in their dialogue and their relationships
and everything that represents terms of mental health
this time I give a lot of focus to two characters in particular
that we meet on our journey through Revachol
and one of them that
I give kind of like my deepest
psychoanalytical impressions yet
maybe also my
most unhinged character analysis thus far as well
but it is in service of
actually kind of discussing like some important things about
how the game depicts its world building and
what characters do we need to look at
and in terms of like if we look at the shape of their mental health
this will tell us a lot about
what it is like to live in this environment
with these political systems with these social tensions
like what is the result of that on the people
who are actually being brought up in this world
so emm there's a lot to get into
I'm excited to share so
let's jump back in
okay let's continue
so I think the last thing we were doing
is kind of investigating our relationship with kim here
I guess if it's a section of this that I missed
ah "cool for" I see what you mean
I thought it was something I had to click on
so let's check out Inland Empire
because that's our main skill and
I'm finding it very interesting that this was the
primary skill that I chose
especially because in the last stream
I found myself kind of disagreeing with its intrusions a little more
it says it's cool for dreamers paranatural investigators and mental creators
I don't know if i'd call myself paranatural
but I am an investigator
and I am a mental creator meaning that
I tend to make stuff in my brain
that's better than I can make it in reality
empathy is cool for judges of character interviewers interrogators
that's me as well
volition is cool for sane people
well-adjusted cops
the non-suicidal
that's kind of half of us right
authority is cool for leaders
experts of psychologIical warfare
and respect junkies
yes yes and yes
this one is cool for cops
cop aficionados
and pretend cops
I feel like that last one is us the pretend cop