hello
and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elysium analysis series
on today's episode
we're going to address something kind of unavoidable in a game like this
which is what are some of the crossovers between politics and mental health
and kind of some personal struggles I have about integrating those two subjects
i'm sure there will be a lot of discussion about this in the comments
just note that this is all recorded previously
I think I'm gonna probably make a dedicated video
it's some point kind of like compiling my thoughts a little more
but yeah we get an early look at kind of where my mind is coming from on this
aside from that
we have a very special moment in this episode
which is finally we're going to reach the end of our first day as a detective
it's taken us a while
and we're going to take another look at how
Kim and I's relationship has been developing
over this very challenging day
and see if there's actually some things we've become quite close on
so all that's coming up I'm excited to get into it
let's do it
all right we
are gonna talk to Kim
we should think about calling it a day maybe
the nights are still miserably cold this time of year
I haven't paid the cafeteria manager for the damages yet
you should take care of that then
but I don't have the money
(let's) talk to him anyway
an officer of the RCM shouldn't be sleeping in the street
we'll figure something out
though he finds this situation frustrating
he is doing his best to not make you feel any worse than you already do
I respect that Kim
yeah his Kim has won a lot of points with me this
these chapters of our stream
okay let's see if we can reason with this gentleman
can I help you
but I don't have another option here
yes have you got it
can we come to some sort of arrangement
that arrangement include you pay me
what we already agreed
you owe me
Kim is about to say something
let him lets do that
I understand your predicament as the manager however
I feel I must remind you
that we are here to conduct an important investigation
that also affects your business
that's a good point put the squeeze on
forgive me for saying this
but your colleague seems more committed to drinking and
establishment sentence
he shrinks back a bit under the lieutenant severe gaze
I mean no offense it's really nothing personal
I just have to protect the interests of this establishment
kitty