hello
and welcome back to my
therapist plays Disco Elysium Analysis series
in today's episode
we are going to be taking a very thorough look at
how Disco Elysium portrays intrusive thinking
when electrochemistry starts giving us thoughts
and they are very much opposed to the thoughts of volition
and how this actually very accurately represents
some of our very real thinking patterns
so we're gonna be using actual theory to break this down
using the cognitive model
how actual cognitive behavioral therapy works
and how we might apply it to a situation that
our detective finds himself in with his own intrusive thinking
this one's gonna be quite in depth
so I'm excited to get into it
let's dive it
all right
so what we need to do now is figure out
where to go
this door he wants me to bust down
oh there's a end-of-day debrief
Kim can answer any lingering questions
you may have about the case and the RCM
join him in the Whirling-in-Rags' balcony after 10
so what time is it
it's almost 10
so we've got a little bit of time before we can do that
do we have enough money to pay back Mr Garte
do we have enough
do we have it's got a ton of trash
let's go turn in the trash
let's pay a visit to the best character in this entire game
Frittte girl
let's see what she's up to
and let's get some money
yeah we're not accepting that bribe fuck that guy
I don't care I'll
we'll solve our many problems
through rigorous environmentalism
I believe I'm supposed to talk to this gentleman first though
see what he's got to say
so how'd you like our harbor