Okay, let's talk about why we make bad decisions.
So if you're like me, then you've probably been in that situation where it's the end
of the day or it's the morning and you're thinking like, okay, I'm going to make a solid
plan for myself.
Today I'm going to be disciplined.
I'm going to come home from work and I'm going to get all these errands done and I'm going
to treat myself really well. I'm going to make a nice, healthy, proper meal. I'm going
to go to the gym afterwards. I'm going to exercise. And then maybe when I come home, I'll
like start reading a book or something. I'll do something a little different, something
that makes me feel like I'm going to advance my life in a new, positive direction.
This is our real life volition and it's there to lead you on your way to making good life
decisions.
But this doesn't always work out that way. Sometimes you get to the end of the day and you
realize that you haven't been very disciplined at all. A lot of those errands are still
incomplete or like half-started. We didn't end up going to the gym and instead of making
a proper meal, we've ordered some definitely not healthy takeout food.
And instead of reading that book, maybe you end up watching a show you've already seen
and we've not advanced our life in a positive meaningful direction in any way at all.
What is happening here? Why would we ignore the voice of volition that's telling us to
do all of these beneficial positive things?
Well, it could be a lot of things, honestly. And definitely having like a mental health
diagnosis is going to amplify this problem a lot more. But even for the average person,
this happens pretty often. It certainly happens to me.
So what I wanted to share with you today is a framework for understanding why this problem
happens and what we can actually do about it. This is a real problem that actually comes
up in my work as a therapist kind of often. And I have really enjoyed seeing it demonstrated
so clearly. And given such a unique role within the structure of a game, like Disco
Felicium has, so okay, there is a reason that we do not always follow the voice of volition
and go through with our good intentions. And it has to do with something called psychological
friction. So in this context, friction is any force either internal or external, which
opposes a behavioral change. So what do we know about like regular friction, right?
If I am standing on an ice rink and I move my body weight around a little bit, I'm going
to start sliding around on the ice. There's not a lot of friction between me and the surface
that's under me. When I step off the ice and now I'm standing on concrete, when I shift
myself around, I'm...