Okay, hello, and welcome to kind of like a special little interlude episode that I wanted to put out before the next Disco Elysium stream goes live.
So this is something I may do from time to time, kind of like taking a chunk of the analysis and putting it in its own video.
Sometimes because it takes me a while to sort of collect my thoughts on things and it doesn't always happen like while we're live on stream.
But also because I can kind of already foresee that this playthrough of Disco Elysium is going to be quite long going at our usual pace.
And I know it can be pretty hard to get into a let's play when it's like episode 30 or something.
And so if you weren't really there for the beginning of it, it's kind of hard to hop in that far down the line.
So I thought it'd be cool to kind of like do like little chunks of our character studies and like analysis of the games systems and like how they represent different parts of mental health, like just as their own separate videos.
Basically for the people who can't commit the time to watch all of the let's play videos or can't make it to the streams or that sort of thing, they can still enjoy kind of this psychological breakdown parts of it.
So that's what we're going to be doing today. There is something that I have to talk about basically like I just couldn't really wait until the next time I get on stream to talk about it.
So that's what we're going to do now.
Okay, so there is something that Disco Elysium does in its portrayal of a very specific aspect of mental health that I have never seen portrayed this way anywhere else.
So one of the biggest challenges when talking about anything related to mental health, whether it's depression, mental illness, addiction is it can sometimes be really hard to explain like how can you want something you could desperately want to not be depressed.
You can desperately want to be sober and yet sometimes our behaviors really don't agree with that desire. And how do you explain that to someone that is sitting there wondering like all I want in the world is to stop using but I just can't.
And this is kind of a mentality that I imagine like our lead detective having been in at some point before he lost his memory and at least in my playthrough with something he's still struggling with.
As he does whatever he can to find the pack of cigarettes. And for me it comes down to this. We tend to have a very limited way of talking about the subject of motivation, like why you actually do things, why you want things.
And this is where disco elisium comes into the picture with these different aspects of the main character psyche who seem to have different motivations for him and they influence you as the player to sort of like follow different paths.
Right, one motivation in terms of the authority voice will tell you like you need to smack that kid right don't let kuno get one over you like that.