Hello, and welcome to another episode in my therapist plays Disco Elysium analysis series.
So this time I wanted to share something that I learned about particular character in the game
and also some things that I learned about myself in the course of uploading this series.
So just for context, if you're just coming into this now.
The way I'm kind of playing through the game is from like the perspective of being a therapist
and trying to provide as much commentary as I can on different angles of mental health that are depicted in the game.
There's a lot more going on than just that at Disco Elysium, but I'm really just...
I'm not the person to comment on complicated political stuff.
And one of the most important dynamics in the game is the one that you have with your partner, Kim Kitsuragi.
And I recognize that like as the player, we're going to be a lot more aware of Kim's qualities than my character, the detective will.
And so in my roleplay of him, I've sort of been exploring the subject of someone who is coming from a background of trauma,
which we still don't know a lot about Rafael from where I'm at in the game.
But a lot of his issues with the way he views authority and relationships and his struggles with substance abuse kind of indicate that there may be some of that background present.
So I've been kind of approaching a lot of the dialogue with Kim from this perspective that like we tend to have an initial first impression about someone that we may want to trust them.
But if we're someone who has a lot of trust issues, we may sort of like test that relationship over time.
We may kind of see where the real boundaries are.
And from my character's perspective, he's kind of been trying to see like...
Does Kim stick around with me because he needs me to complete this case?
Or are the qualities that we immediately picked up on that he is earnest and trustworthy and a very honest character at heart?
Are those things going to last when we make ourselves very difficult to be around basically?
I'm definitely going to ask him, I really want to impress him and I want him to think that I'm cool and that I'm not a f***ing miss.
I've been kind of trying to demonstrate that like some of the closest relationships you can have are ones that have really been put through that test and have outlasted that period of like...
If I push this person far enough, are they still going to stick with me?
A sigh. The lieutenant bears his nose in his notebook.
See, there's another thing that I'm not sure about Kim.
The way that she spoke to me just now, she's giving an honest reflection and she's empathizing with me,
whereas Kim is showing me disappointment and he's showing me mistrust like...