Hello and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elisium analysis series.
On today's episode we're going to address something kind of unavoidable in a game like this,
which is what are some of the crossovers between politics and mental health and kind of
some personal struggles I have about integrating those two subjects.
I'm sure there will be a lot of discussion about this in the comments, just know that this
is all recorded previously. I think I'm going to probably make a dedicated video at some
point kind of like compiling my thoughts a little more, but yeah, to get an early look
at kind of where my, my, my, my stomach's going to be problemless.
Aside from that, we have a very special moment in this episode, which is finally we're
going to reach the end of our first day as a detective. It's taken us a while and we're
going to take another look at how Kim and I's relationship has been developing over this
very challenging day and see if there's actually some things that we've become like close
on. So, all that's coming up, I'm excited to get into it.
Let's do it.
Alrighty, we are going to talk to Kim.
We should think about calling it today maybe. The nights are still miserably cold this
time of year. I haven't paid the cafeteria manager for the damages yet.
Should take care of that then.
I don't have the money.
I'm stuck to him anyway. An office of the RCM shouldn't be sleeping in the street. We'll
figure something out.
Though he finds this situation frustrating, he is doing his best to not make you feel
any worse than you already do.
I respect that, Kim. He's, he's, Kim is one of a lot of points with me this, in these
chapters of our stream.
Okay, let's see if we can reason with this gentleman.
Can I help you?
But I don't have another option here.
Yes, have you got it?
Can we come to some sort of arrangement?
Does that arrangement include you paying me what we already agreed you owe me?
Kim is about to say something. Let him. Let's do that.
I understand your predicament as the manager. However, I feel I must remind you that we are
here to conduct an important investigation that also affects your business.
That's a good point. Put the squeeze on him.
Give me for saying this, but your colleagues seems more committed to drinking and...
He stops me in sentence.
He shrinks back a bit under the Lieutenant-Severge's.
I mean no effects. It's really nothing personal. I just have to protect the interests of this
establishment.
No, kiddie.
Kiddie.