Hello and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elisium analysis series.
Okay, I'm really excited about today's episode.
We're finally getting into our first encounter with the union boss Everart Claire
and kind of breaking down lots of different psychological angles on power dynamics
and have a lot to share today on real techniques that I actually use in my practice as a therapist
to navigate sort of like difficult conversations with people who either don't want to talk to you
or are in some sort of power struggle and how do you sort of get that person opening up about
things. We're going to use some of those techniques on Mr. Claire and by the end of this episode
we're going to learn a little bit more about ourselves and what kind of comp we are.
Yes, we're finally getting our copo type. I'm sure very few of you will be surprised at
what I end up with. So I'm excited to share this one. Let's dive in.
Okay, so I have an objective. I have the objective to progress this game's storyline. Like
I do want to just like mention why I am going about playing this game this way because I do
think it's relevant when you see my character do things like just totally give up on
pursuing the narrative to try to find like cigarettes for example.
This is a roleplay, right? So sometimes I'm going to be speaking as like Brady the therapist.
Sometimes I'm going to be speaking as like Brady the degenerate who is using this as a kind of
escapism from my very serious real life that I like this is where I get to give me a goofball.
And sometimes I'm going to like speak from the voice of my character, right? And just like say
random nonsense garbage that I think he would say or think, right? And one of the things that
is really important about this character specifically because he is someone representing the struggle
of addiction is how like we have all kinds of priority structures in our mind, right? Like
there's the whole just basic needs hierarchy of like you need food, you need water, you need rest.
And only once those things are satisfied can you really focus on like higher order things like,
you know, your self-esteem and your self-worth and the balance of health and your relationships
and those sorts of things, right? The problem with addiction is that your body has become dependent
on a chemical one that's harmful to you and so it completely hijacks what should be a normal
set of priorities.