Hello and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elicium analysis series. So on
today's episode we're getting deeper into our different character studies and
kind of breaking down like the psychological dynamics in their dialogue and
their relationships and everything that represents in terms of mental health.
This time I give a lot of focus to two characters in particular that we meet on
our journey through Revisho and one of them that I give kind of like my
deepest psychoanalytical impressions yet maybe also my most unhinged character
analysis as far as well but it is in service of actually kind of discussing
like some important things about how the game depicts its world building and
what characters do we need to look at and in terms of like if we look at the
shape of their mental health this will tell us a lot about what it is like to
live in this environment with these political systems with these social
tensions like what is the result of that on the people who are actually being
brought up in this world so there's a lot to get into I'm excited to share
so let's jump back in. Okay let's continue so I think the last thing we were
doing is kind of investigating our relationship with Kim here I guess
there's a section of this that I missed. Ah cool four I see what you mean I
thought it was something I had to click on so let's check out Inland Empire
because that's our main skill and I'm finding it very interesting that this
was the primary skill that I chose especially because in the last stream I
found myself kind of disagreeing with its intrusions a little more. It says
it's cool for dreamers, paranatural investigators and mental creators. I don't
know if I'd call myself paranatural but I am an investigator and I am a
mental creator meaning that I tend to make stuff in my brain that's better
than I can make it in reality. Empathy is cool for judges of character
interviewers and interrogators yeah that's me as well. This is a
volition is cool for sane people well-adjusted cops the non-suicidal it's
kind of half of us right. Authority is cool for leaders experts of psychological
warfare and respect junkies okay yes yes and yes this one is cool for cops
cop-efficient autos and pretend cops I feel like that last one is us the
pretend cop.