Hello and welcome to my therapist plays disco elicium analysis series. On today's
episode we are meeting what has become another one of my absolute favorite
characters that we've met so far. So we're gonna be talking a lot with a net and
her mother today learning more about the economic reality of being a child who
has to work out in the cold all day. And in that dialogue we're also gonna be
continuing to build our own character profile sort of continuing the analysis
using the jahari window that we started in the last episode. There's a lot of
emotions to dig into and discuss in today's episode including some that may
come up when we finally face ourselves. So that's where we're at. I'm excited to
continue so let's jump back in. Okay. What shall we do next? I guess we can go
enter the green the door behind the green house. Let's go do that. It's in the yard
basement door. Is that back there? Yeah it's more useful on counseling.
What is this girl up to? It's been a while since we've checked in. She is way too
positive. Oh it's snowing. What is this crime? It's about murders or burglaries
or things like that and the work of a policeman or a private detective who's
trying to solve a crime and catch the criminals. I need to know what crime is. It's
that bad. Pointy red. Crime is what we were solving before this conversation began.
Why would anyone want to read a crime? They get to imagine dangerous things and
it's kind of like a puzzle where you can guess who the criminal is or how the
good guys are going to catch him. I'm a policeman myself by the way. I don't
look much like a policeman. I know. Well what does a cop look like that?
She points to a book cover on which you can see strapping
Vesparteen officer. He stems grinly over the body of a dead woman. You know
nobody actually looks like the guy in the picture. It's not your body that's
important in police work. It's your head.