Okay, hello and welcome back to our therapist plays disco elicium lets play series. If you are new
here then hello welcome my name is Brady I'm a therapist and we are doing like kind of a long
form psychoanalysis of the main character and his companions and all the people that we meet on
our journey through Revigel. So in today's episode we're going to talk a lot about like our main
characters reflections on his own self identity as we sort of start to unpack and discover
things that he is remembering about his past and psychologically what does it mean to
integrate a past version of yourself who you may not have a lot of positive feelings about
into the identity that you're building today and also we're going to see if we could take
another shot this whole thing with Guna. So let's dive in. Now one thing that is kind of a hanging
thread is I want to return to my bedroom while I'm here. We're playing the game like reading
some psychological class material. Yeah if you're new to the Euro Brady experience this is one part
entertainment one part master's level psychology lecture one part my own self therapy life
or your enjoyment. Read the problem part let's do that. Let's rewind let's trace your drunken
steps back home jump across the raised channel bridge southwest of here fall over get up get off
the asphalt in 20 minutes shuffle your feet through court yards scaring little children that
checks out go under the great raised motor tract the 881 until you reach the domain eminol
in north jamrock the streets are frozen this time of year caked with ice walk down main to
tradition there's a side alley there in your footprints in the mud okay there's something there
there is a past for me okay
what is this
Kim also tries not to look at the pile of take viscera on the carpet or the weird suitcase on the
hat rack or the pot it planned dying in the corner but it's all just too morbid to ignore oh that's
true this is the first time I've brought Kim into the environment maybe in a subconscious way
I'm trying to understand again how how much can I destroy my own image to him before I before
I come to the conclusion that he's not going to abandon me maybe if I show him something intimate and