Okay, hello and welcome back to our playthrough of disco elisium
We just finished kind of like the first little chunk of the game kind of starting our character and
Yeah, just figuring out who he is in this wild disgusting world and how wild and disgusting are we going to be to
Kind of meet the world where it's at
So I've sort of decided that the the character profile we're going with is like
X or failed therapist turned dirty cop
Kind of the idea like
I tried to be a therapist, but I found it was too easy to manipulate people or
The more I learned about people the more I could not help the urge to
exploit that stuff so I became a cop instead where I can hide behind a moral or duty justification for
Getting information from people and I can sort of code that as this is a good thing for me and them
I'm actually protecting them by figuring out their dark secrets. So that's kind of where we're at
Let's continue and
and
Keep working on this crime here
Literally just came back at the perfect time hell yeah, let's let's let's look and go
Okay, let's check out the crime scene a little bit more here
Get some cash lying around never gonna let that go to waste some more magnesium
I think we're gonna need to stock up on magnesium
This one mechanism has been oxidating for some years
The kids ladder is climbable
Okay, not too much interesting going on around here. Let's check out the body
With bulging white eyes the face around them does not look human
It's swollen and ready to burst his lips are fish like and his tongue like a ball gag in his mouth
Okay, it's pretty pretty gruesome you seem to be holding your breath
They cargo belt twist his neck at an unnatural angle the body below appears stiff
It's letting out an ungodly rot the smell seeps in even through your clenched nostrils
Legendary let's go of your nose without throwing up
That's 17%
Has not steered me wrong yet. Oh, it looks like my camera is frozen