Okay. Hello. And also welcome. It's great to be back on stream and continuing our disco
elicium playthrough. If you're just joining us, which is a good chance that you are, this
is kind of still at the beginning of our little playthrough here. And what we're doing
is we're kind of playing through it like mix of roleplay, mix of psychoanalysis. I'm
Brady, I'm a therapist. And I'm going to be doing like different kinds of psychoanalysis
on the characters and kind of linking that to the game design and like how it represents
mental health. This game is just in another league when it comes to that sort of thing so
far. Like I already did a video kind of talking about the skill system and how it represents
this like very fascinating way to perceive like motivation and psychological priority.
So yeah, we're like, we're going to get pretty deep with this. The last two playthroughs
or last two streams. I'm sort of just been figuring out the game. And now that I've
like had some time to collect some thoughts on it, I'll be talking a little bit more about
the characters and their dynamics. And like I guess why my character specifically is
showing a lot of avoidance and confrontation and like is not maybe making some of the
best decisions. I'm doing like a mix of my own head can in roleplay. Like I'm not trying
to play the game the best way. Honestly, I'm just trying to make this a fun play through
like just kind of doing wild shit. We're not going to see every single part of the game
or every dialogue tree. And that's okay. But it has been great to get some recommendations
for things that like I just straight out missed because of like so far my character has
just fallen into like he's just failing upwards basically like passing some of the early
skill checks. Some of the comments on the last video were telling me that like missing
or succeeding in some of these early skill checks has like made me skip over a lot of tutorials
which makes sense because I kind of feel lost on some of the systems. But that's okay.
We're discovering it as we go. And I think that just makes for interesting playthrough
dynamics. What I have been fascinated by is how well the game has responded to my like
weird way of approaching this like it's completely fine that I skipped certain things.
It's completely fine that I don't know how to play it very well. It's not like I've
not reached a roadblock where the game is like hey slow down friend. I need to teach you
this before you move on. It's happy to just let me move on and try to fail my way through
everything which is kind of life isn't it. So with that said...