Hello and welcome to my therapist plays disco elicium analysis series. So on
today's episode I'm very excited because we are finally getting to use one of my
absolute favorite frameworks for analyzing characters. This is something that I
use in therapy from time to time and it's an incredible way to explore patterns
of psychology and patterns of behavior and sort of really uncover what is
driving a lot of the complexes that we see play out in Harry's thoughts and his
actions. And the reason we were doing that now is because we are starting to
learn more about ourselves and our past. We're going to take another look at
that ledger and see what do we actually think about the person that we used to
be before we became a sorry cop. All that's coming up so let's jump back in.
Oh there it is. There it is. We are back. We are so back. I'm so excited. Okay so we
are back in the game now. I just wanted to say the community that has arrived
around like this game and specifically this playthrough continues to
amaze me especially after last episode was like a lot of politics talk and I was
very like anxious avoidant of talking about politics. I have been very encouraged
by the response to that last episode to like not be so anxious about it. I
don't I still don't know if I'm gonna like start getting full political but I
will try not to like avoid it in the game because of my personal issues with
with getting political. I'll just say that I I won't let it divert the game
because at the end of the day I want to talk about like mental health and
there's probably some interesting avenues in the narrative of the game that
will miss out on if I just totally ignore it. However I will say this game is
so wonderfully designed that it you have a main character who has a real back
story. He's not like a blank slate like I thought that he was gonna be from
the beginning. He has his own back story and at the same time it allows you to
have your own beliefs and and to and the character will like have the same
behavioral patterns. Like genuinely imagine if like literally Brady was the
detective. Imagine it what you know about me so far. How I would go about
solving a murder would be exactly like you've seen it like I would spend
crazy amounts of time on things that you just wouldn't like you.