Hello and welcome to my therapist plays disco lesium analysis series. So on
today's episode the plot sign we are going to see if we can establish our
authority with Tidus the Union boss. We're gonna see if we can get a little
closer to a confession from him on who exactly was involved with the murder in
Marche Nays. And over on the analysis side we're gonna be taking a deep dive
into the rigorous self critique thought. Now that we finally internalize this one
it opens the door for a lot of discussion on Harry's sense of self and kind of
digging into the question of is he actually a good person? And if he's not
does he think that it's possible to become one? This one's a little bit
heavier on the analysis but it's pretty exciting to finally peel back more
layers of our character. Let's jump in. Any predictions on where the story will
go or who's the killer? I kind of had the idea that we would be somewhat
involved in the killing like because we are so uninitiated to our own past.
I don't think that we did it like would have hung him up like that but I sort of
have the suspicion that the dock workers are kind of like a red hairing. I just
don't buy it. I just don't buy it that's that's what we're leading but I could be
wrong. I am notoriously bad at predicting the plot of anything ever like when
you have already probably noticed this but like when politics or the plot are
part of the dialogue my brain like it does this it feels like it condenses
down to like I've had to do this before where I'm like okay what is happening
here? My brain is just equipped for like character and analysis and the way I
engage with media just privately is like when I'm watching something I'm not
really thinking about the plot. I'm very rarely like well I'm not like
watching shutter island and I'm like where's this going? I wonder what's
gonna happen next? My brain just like accepts whatever's going to happen but
what I'm thinking about is like wow what is that character feeling right now?
You know I wonder how like whatever is going to happen to them is going to
change their worldview like it's that's that's more where my mind is focused
and I kind of just accept the plot whatever it is it doesn't matter that much to
me the sequence of things happening unless it is so egregious that I'm like this
doesn't make any sense what if it was Lena well I refuse to accept that
Lena is too kindhearted and good-natured for her to be involved in that it's
funny therapists often seem to struggle with things like predicting stuff
or telling if someone is lying well that's true because like