Hello, and welcome back to our therapist plays disco elicium. Let's play if you're new here
Hello, my name is Brady. I'm a therapist and we're doing kind of like a long-form psycho analysis of our
main character and all the people that we meet in our
twisted weird journey through
Revishol in disco elicium. So on today's episode we're kind of getting
deeper into the analysis and
actually kind of targeting our companion Kim who at least in my playthrough and the way I'm sort of roleplaying this character
We don't have like the most
trusting relationship with yet and kind of getting into the psychology of like what does it mean to
want to trust someone
But not be sure if you can yet and how does someone who has a lot of like prior trauma like our main character does
actually evaluate whether or not someone who
Promises to be there on your side is actually trustworthy in what they say so today
I'm gonna give you kind of a mix of psychological theory behind this idea and also how I would actually address something like this in
Practice as a therapist so that said let's continue
Okay, so
What do I need to do?
I need to ask I need to solve this murder
Like I gotta be honest like the the murder is like the lowest priority thing to my character right now
I genuinely believe that if I'm this character
The murder is just a vehicle to discover more about who I was and in that process
Reckoning with the idea that I may have done something to myself to try to forget that person and here
I'm spending a lot of time trying to figure that out
I could go do oh
I can go do the autopsy I have the gloves and I have the form
Maybe I should do that
I'm just collecting tasks
Jam mystery I kind of want to go see the body let's do the notch-ops zero quick I have all the ingredients I need
See what happens
If you don't tell us something provide us information
The rotting man lies on his side with his eyes looking straight through you
The belt is still around his neck his body is supine and open to intrusion by autopsy. Let's do that turn it