Hello and welcome back to my therapist plays disco elicium analysis series. So on
today's episode we are delving even deeper into the psychology of our main
character. Is this case gets more complicated so does our relationship with
ourselves because we're also going to start discovering more about who we were
and finding that we are not so happy with that person before we had our
amnesia and woke up as the person we are today and so what does it mean to be
faced with some of those challenges do we avoid them and try to shut them out
or do we look for healthy ways to integrate them and move forward but we also
do get into major confrontation we're going to face what it is like when we go
up against an individual named measurehead who stands between us and our next
objective in solving the case so all that is coming up in today's episode and
perhaps our first moments of genuine trust starting to build between ourselves
and our partner Kip. I'm excited to continue this journey with all of you so
let's jump in. Hey there's a big gentleman.
Scared. Maybe this is the gentleman who was asking about our case is a large
lead what's going on here. The broad shoulder alpha male turns to you he's a
full head taller than everybody else here. You hear to fuck with us beat the
honest worker down. Why should I hear the fight for a cause? Stripes usually have
problems with people who have causes. Okay then I think I think no I want to be on
your team friend.
Good. We're fighting for a cause here. Right to work. Right to work. Besides we're not that
different. It helps if people see us talking cops and strikebreakers together.
Shows with our days are on our side. Builds confidence. I like his perspective I
agree. I agree with that. I think it's also kind of a power play that I'm like
grinding the flashlight and everybody's face because it makes them feel like I'm
really targeting them which is good for my interrogation. What kind of trials are
we talking about? Well I don't want to politically align with him but I want to
be on his team.