hello
and welcome to another episode
in my therapist plays disco elysium analysis serie
so this time I wanted to share something
that I learned about particular character in the game and
also some things that I learned about myself
in the course of uploading this series
so just for context if you're just come into this now
the way I'm kind of playing through the game
is from like the perspective of being a therapist
and trying to provide as much commentary as I can on
different angles of mental health that are depicted in the game
there's a lot more going on than just that at the disco elysium
but I'm really just I'm not the person
to comment on like complicated political stuff
and one of the most important dynamics in the game
is the one that you have with your partner Kim Kitsuragi
and I recognize that like as the player
we're going to be a lot more aware of
Kim's qualities than my character the detective well
and so in my role play of him
I've sort of been exploring the subject of
someone who is coming from a background of trauma
which we still don't know a lot
about Raphael from where I'm at in the game
but a lot of his issues with the way he views authority and relationships
and his struggles with substance abuse
kind of indicate that
there may be some of that background present
so I've been kind of approaching a lot of the dialogue
with Kim from this perspective
that like we tend to have an initial first impression about someone
that we may want to trust them
but if we're someone who has a lot of trust issues
we may sort of like test that relationship over time
we may kind of see where the real boundaries are
and from my character's perspective
he's kind of been trying to see like this
this Kim's sticking around with me
because he needs me to complete this case
or are the qualities that we immediately picked up on that
he is earnest and trustworthy
and a very honest character at hearts
are those things going to last
when we make ourselves very difficult to be around basically
I'm definitely going to ask him
I really want to impress him
and I want him to think that I'm cool
and that I'm not a fucking ass
I've been kind of trying to demonstrate that
like some of the closest relationships you can have
are ones that have really been put through that test
and have outlasted that period of
like if I push this person far enough
are they still gonna stick with me
a sigh the lieutenant buries his nose in his notebook
see there's another thing that that I'm not sure about Kim
the way that she spoke to me just now
she's giving an honest reflection
and she's empathizing with me
whereas Kim is showing me disappointment
and he's showing me mistrust
like maybe I am too brain damaged
to be useful to him
and so as Brady the player
I can see that um you know these are genuine qualities in Kim
but from the perspective of my character
there's still some distance there
and still some things
that we're trying to kind of put through that test
so that's been kind of one of my goals with the play through
but in the last episode
we had one of our first like real one on one exchanges with Kim
and in that conversation
I was actually hoping to like
instigate some tension between these two characters
to sort of like kind of push that conversation about
like what does it look like to push through
you know a barrier of trust between two people
and I was doing so by trying to
also use an approach that is sometimes useful in therapy
for kind of like getting someone to talk more openly about
subjects that may be uncomfortable to them
as kind of a way to like
push the boundaries of our relationship with Kim
to a point where we are openly challenging some of the ideas
that may present tension between us
and actually start to work through them
and build some of that trust between us
so this is kind of what that looks like
the idea here is that
we often try to deal with our emotions
in a very sort of like intellectual way
meaning that we're talking about them
but the emotions that are attached to a difficult subject
are not present with us
we're discussing something like that
we went through a breakup or something
but we're sort of giving more of like
a historical analytical account of it
more so than getting in touch with the emotions
that might actually be present there
and the reason that we intellectualize things is
because it keeps our anxiety low
right
I'm talking about something
and I'm sort of trying to avoid really
the uncomfortable feelings that might be present there
and yet some of the best processing work that we can do
is going to take place in this like zone
where the psychological work actually happens
when there's a little bit of that anxiety present right
when we sort of break through the like layers and layers
of defense mechanisms and avoidance
that we're having to not actually get in touch
with those uncomfortable feelings
if I see someone intellectualizing
I might try to you know push a little bit into that subject
kind of try to raise the anxiety a little bit
and it's very common for people to kind of retreat back into intellectualizing
and sort of avoid that
and so you may need to push a little harder right
and you're trying to get that person to a point where
they are feeling enough of the emotion to talk about it
without going too far right
and then we end up sort of in a crisis situation
It's a tricky thing to manage
and this is kind of what I was trying to show in the dialogue with Kim
but it was in the pursuit of trying to demonstrate this
and kind of analyze the dynamics I play
that I sort of get things very wrong about Kim
and really what the whole conversation we were having was actually about
the conversation that we were having was about Kim's cultural heritage
and he's explaining to me that
he has no attachments to Seol
he calls himself a regular garden variety Revacholiere
and it's pretty evident that this conversation makes him feel uncomfortable
Kim is tired of people assuming that
he has some sort of connection to his Seolite ancestry
when really that's never been a part of his history
and it's frustratingly common for him
to feel like people don't consider him a genuine Revacholiere
because he doesn't necessarily look like the other people in the country
and so while we were in this dialogue
I was sort of looking for ways to raise the tensions
so that I could sort of like talk about
what this dynamic can look like
when someone really gets in touch with an uncomfortable emotion
but I got the wrong read on why he was becoming uncomfortable
and some of the assumptions
that not just from my character's point of view
but also in my own thinking
had some prejudices
and at the time
a lot of my focus was on just trying to sort of like increase the tensions
so that I could you know talk about this therapeutic technique
but I think that's really where the problem actually starts for me
which is that I wasn't thinking as much about how
people who relate to Kim in real life
feel when questions like this come up
and so I carried on with that conversation and continued the play through
and then it was after I published that episode
that I started to get a lot of comments that pointed this out to me
people share their perspectives of how they relate to Kim
and how it is very common for people to assume
that they must have an inherent attachment to their heritage's culture
and that they must feel conflicted about this
which is kind of you know where
my line of questioning towards Kim was coming from
It may come from a place of genuine curiosity
but there are prejudices inlaid in that assumption that go overlooked
and so I'm sorry to anyone for whom this
brought up these kinds of hurtful feelings
and uh even though it wasn't intentional
I know that I'm responsible for
what I say and for the way it makes other people feel
I am so appreciative of this community
and for the people who shared their experiences
in the commons of that video
because it was done in such a respectful and truly informative way
this was something that I needed some education on
and so I'm also very thankful for that as well
the other part that I wanted to talk about in this video
is actually just how I reflected on this whole situation
and kind of discovered some things
that actually make me uncomfortable about myself
so after I published the video
I started to get some comments
that were you know strongly disagreeing with everything
and I had to say about Kim
and they were right about every single one
but looking back on it now I can see that
like some of my first replies were rather defensive
and that's just the honest truth
I thought that I was being criticized for having a misunderstanding
and that this would be sort of mistaken for genuine bigotry
and so my first couple of replies were sort of focused on
like trying to explained that I didn't mean that
and you know I was not going at it from that angle
and here's what I really meant to talk about
and I just it wasn't the right way to go about that either
I shouldn't have been trying to like explain that I meant no offence
and really just should have started listening and
accepting what people had to say
so I was being defensive and like I hate this about myself
like I don't like that's my first reaction to being uncomfortable
which is really
it's kind of exactly what I'm demonstrating in my whole little chart here
like honestly
it's it's kind of amusing I guess
to see that like what I experience
is a better demonstration of this principle
than whatever I was trying to say in the video
and just totally blew it
here I am
like trying to come at a very intellectual angle with
like no I didn't mean that here's what I really meant
I was actually trying to explain this thing
no like what I was doing is avoiding my own anxiety you know
and the more that people started to comment
and share their experiences
and I just kind of realized
not only was my take on like Kim's character just totally wrong
but it was also upsetting and hurtful to people who relate to him
and have to deal with similar things all the time
I never wanted to like confront people's real issues that way
but like I said intention or not like that's what happens
and realizing that like my mistake could have upset someone to that degree
like my anxiety started going up like a lot
and um I was going to stream that evening and I decided not to
because like I was just I was probably a little bit higher up here
like I really felt this just wouldn't be a good idea you know
I I'm not feeling good about myself
and I um have some like self reflection to do here
and it was actually when
I went back and started to read some of the comments
and reread them
and realized that
like no one there was attacking me
like they were just sharing their experiences
trying to inform me
that my anxiety started to come down
and legitimately it's there that I started to think a lot more clearly
on why I actually had that reaction to begin with
so I realized that I not only need to apologize for you know what was said
but I also just needed to reflect a lot on myself here
I needed to see that the reason I became so defensive
at first and then anxious after that
was that I actually do have some
biases and prejudices and assumptions
that II didn't even know I had right
and it was only after being sort of like very uncomfortably confronted by that
did I start to detect
like okay this this avoidance you're having
is because there are some misinformed
and overlooked assumptions that you have
that make you feel uncomfortable
and you don't like realizing that
you know not every thought that crosses your mind
is gonna be formed in absolute perfection before you say it
and that scares me
but it's also like just natural
and you know I'm trying to learn as much as I can from this experience
and I understand that even some of
what I'm doing right here is a little bit of intellectualizing
but like what is true and honest is that the other day
I felt like just really beside myself with disappointment
but that's okay you know
it it's okay to feel that way sometimes
because what it has brought to me
is you know a little bit more awareness
and um helped me just see a little bit more
where people were coming from
for that I'm also sorry
but I'm also very thankful to those of you
who helped me learn something new about myself and
just reminding me that you know there's
there's definitely some areas that I have to do some work on too
you know this whole process is not something I'm unfamiliar with
and it's really why I want to bring it up in the first place
because I do really believe that
there's some things that are a little too below the surface
that you don't even really know they are there
and it takes a certain kind of confrontation to actually
put them in front of you
and like make you a little uncomfortable
like oh wow I didn't even really know
that I had that kind of assumption
like that makes me really uncomfortable
so like what do I need to do to start working on it
and like I know how to manage that
when it comes to like doing therapy with someone else
and how to sort of like safely bring them to that point
and you know make sure that like we're developing inside around this
and not going down a path of like major self criticism
which is something I tend to do
but it's just it's really hard to do sometimes
when it's yourself and uh it's your own issues that need attention
so that's just something that I really wanted to say about all of this
and um you know the fact that a game like Disco Elycium exists
and has so many complicated layers to it
and can be the cause of the genuine self discovery
good and bad
just continues to amaze me and makes me you know
even more excited too keep playing it
so my understanding of Kim
has definitely changed as a result of this
but that's like speaking for myself
for my character
you know I do think that there is something worth exploring
on the subject of like the two of them not immediately starting to get along
I do expect that between my detective and Kim
there are still some things to sort of work on
and that you know it's still going to take some time before
we warm up to each other
so for the sake of the role play
you know there may still be times where we confront each other
but I will definitely be in a better perspective with myself
as we explore those subjects and talk about them
you know that's been one of the most interesting parts
of the play through so far
is just how much discussion this stimulates
including this one
so I'm really curious to see where we go from
so thank you again for everyone who shared their perspective with me
I just appreciate the way that everyone is engaging with this series
it's been more impactful to me than I think I'm even really able to show here
and look I know that I'm also just like generally trashed at playing the game
like our play through is a total mess
I'm missing all kinds of important things
and um you know that's something that I'll uh try to work on as well
so with that said
I'll see you all on the next one Goodbye