Okay, let's talk about why we make bad decisions.
So if you're like me, then you've probably been
in that situation where it's the end of the day
or it's the morning and you're thinking like,
okay, I'm gonna make a solid plan for myself.
Today, I'm gonna be disciplined.
I'm gonna come home from work
and I'm gonna get all these errands done
and I'm gonna treat myself really well.
I'm gonna make a nice healthy, proper meal.
I'm gonna go to the gym afterwards.
I'm gonna exercise and then maybe when I come home,
I'll like start reading a book or something.
I'll do something a little different,
something that makes me feel like I'm gonna advance my life
in a new positive direction.
And this is our real life volition
and it's there to lead you on your way
to making good life decisions.
But this doesn't always work out that way.
Sometimes you get to the end of the day
and you realize that you haven't been very disciplined.
At all, a lot of those errands are still
incomplete or like half-started.
We didn't end up going to the gym
and instead of making a proper meal,
we've ordered some definitely not healthy takeout food.
And instead of reading that book,
maybe you end up watching a show you've already seen
and we've not advanced our life
in a positive meaningful direction in any way at all.
What is happening here?
Why would we ignore the voice of volition
that's telling us to do all of these
beneficial positive things?
Well, it could be a lot of things honestly
and definitely having like a mental health diagnosis
is going to amplify this problem a lot more.
But even for the average person,
this happens like pretty often.
I mean, it certainly happens to me.
So what I wanted to share with you today
is a framework for understanding why this problem happens
and what we can actually do about it.
This is a real problem that actually comes up
in my work as a therapist kind of often.
And I have really enjoyed seeing it demonstrated
so clearly and given such a unique role
within the structure of a game like Disco Elysium has.
So okay, there is a reason that we do not always follow
the voice of volition and go through
with our good intentions.
And it has to do with something called psychological friction.
So in this context, friction is any force
either internal or external,
which opposes a behavioral change.
So what do we know about like regular friction, right?
If I am standing on an ice rink
and I move my body weight around a little bit,
I'm gonna start sliding around on the ice.
There's not a lot of friction between me
and the surface that's under me.
When I step off the ice and now I'm standing on concrete,
when I shift myself around, I don't move, right?
There is a lot more friction between me and the ground.
And psychologically, this principle
is basically the same thing.
If you imagine you're trying to do something,
it's going to be much harder
if there is more friction between you and the process
and it's going to be much easier
if there is less friction.
When friction is introduced
and we'll talk about what kinds of friction are very common,
the process tends to slow down.
We tend to have a harder time
actually completing the thing we're trying to do.
And it's much more likely that we're going to give up.
When there is less friction
or we find a way to reduce the friction that's there,
the process can start to speed up again
and we'll find more motivation
to actually keep working on it.
And really we can kind of think of this
how like habits work, right?
When you're trying to do something new,
it can be hard to stay motivated and be consistent
and be very disciplined in it.
We have to be very rigorous and consistent with things
before they start to get easier
and we have to do less work to get ourselves
in the mindset to do it.
Like if we're trying to start, you know,
an exercise, regimen or something.
So there's a lot of friction between us
and this new behavioral change.
Things start to get easier when we learn more about that process
and we start developing sort of like the mental tricks
to get ourselves into that kind of mode
where we want to do it.
We don't have to convince ourselves anymore
and our stamina to like do the thing that's difficult
starts to go up and there's a lot less friction here.
We start to develop that habit
when the process becomes streamlined and simplified
and we have to do less of the psychological work
to get ourselves moving on it.
So basically the things that we tend to do the most
and the patterns of behavior that we tend to repeat
are those where the amount of friction between us
and the process is very minimal.
So this is part of why when we tell ourselves
we're going to do all of these nice things,
a lot of friction tends to get introduced in that process
because thinking about doing all of those things
isn't really that hard, but when it comes down to it,
it takes an extra layer of scheduling and timing
and trying to balance your energy throughout the day.
You better make sure that you slept enough,
ate well enough to that you're hydrated,
that you actually have the motivation at the time
you're trying to do that thing to actually start it.
And honestly, at the end of a long day,
we're not typically still in the high motivation state
that we were at the beginning of the day
when volition was telling us how awesome
we're gonna be sometime later.
We are not always interested or capable sometimes
of fighting against all of the friction
that has found us along the way.
So we choose things that are less difficult, right?
The kinds of habits that we've already formed
that we know work that don't require a lot
of mental fortitude to carry out.
Volition asks us to do things which are good for us
but that they are difficult to accomplish.
And so it's often the voices of half light
or electrochemistry that give us other options
and don't ask us to fight against a bunch of friction.
They just want us to chase whatever impulse
makes sense in the moment.
You should tell people to f*** off more often.
I should, I should do that.
You shouldn't.
You're an officer of the law.
Maybe I shouldn't.
So this has been really fascinating to see portrayed
in disco-alecium because in my playthrough,
I've been kind of role-playing and demonstrating
this whole problem, right?
And so sometimes volition will chime in with a thought
and I just ignore it.
And I go do something that for a lot of people,
it looks like it's not really within my character's best interest
and they're right.
But that's how people are.
We are kind of walking contradictions.
We just don't always act in our own best interests.
Like I said, even though the thought
to do something good is available to us,
that doesn't mean we're actually going to do it.
In fact, we're very keenly aware,
a lot of the times, that we are doing something
that's not in our best interest.
And we're pulling the ice cream out of the fridge
and telling ourselves along the way,
I really shouldn't.
But I'm gonna anyway.
So this is a real problem, right?
And the game is so good at demonstrating this.
So what do you do about this, right?
I like the word friction because it gives us
a very easy framework to understand.
And so when I'm working with someone
who is struggling with motivation
or a lot of times we're sort of questioning,
like I'm very passionate about this thing,
but I don't find myself doing it a lot.
Like I don't know what's wrong with me.
Maybe I've lost interest in it.
That's where we may start to ask the question, okay,
well, what kind of friction is in this process for you
and how might we start to work to reduce it?
And the best place to start is actually trying to understand
whether this friction is even real or not,
because that's the thing.
There is real psychological friction
and perceived psychological friction.
Now, that is not to say that friction by itself
is a bad thing.
In fact, there are some cases where introducing friction
to some sort of behavioral process is actually a good thing.
Think about an addiction, for example, right?
Which is a big part of dysgoelisium,
where the habit to seek and use a substance
has become very normalized for us,
and we're always looking to have the least amount of friction
between us and continuing that substance use.
And so actually, when you're trying to work on breaking a habit
or lower the chances that an addiction develops,
you actually want to introduce friction to the process.
Essentially, making things harder is going to slow down
and make completely interrupt the process
that we are trying to change.
This is why when people are trying to quit a substance,
they typically go to a detox center
and then they go into full rehabilitation.
And that's to completely separate themselves
from the environment and all of the social and psychological
issues which made repeating that pattern of behavior very easy.
We want to introduce a ton of friction
to this person's life temporarily,
so that we can learn to develop better strategies
to cope with the issues that resulted in some sort of addiction.
So this was all pretty well demonstrated in my own playthrough
in which we spent a lot of time trying to find a way
to buy a pack of cigarettes.
And I was explaining how when we have a chemical dependence
on something, we're often going to prioritize that
over most other things, higher order things,
like solving a crime or strengthening our relationships.
And so the thought pattern may have been something like,
okay, well, our character wants to smoke.
How do I do that?
What's the simplest path here?
I want to find the way with the least amount of friction
like I need this now.
So we go into Frita and Frita Girl is there, okay?
And she tells us that we don't have the money for cigarettes.
There's a way that we can get the money for cigarettes.
What we can do is we can collect tear.
And tear is trash.
And so what we can do is try to find a bag
so that we can pick up all the tear and revisher
and we'll spend as much time as we need to collecting this
so that we can go and buy the cigarettes.
And that sounds like kind of a difficult drawn out process.
And it was, however, there was less friction in doing that
than there would be if I tried to solve this murder
without the stimulant that my body is craving.
I may have been telling myself, like, look,
this whole detective thing is just way too hard
without a buzz, right?
There's too much friction.
I can't talk to people.
I can't think straight, right?
I'm gonna do this other thing that's still difficult,
but maybe it will help reduce the amount of friction
in this other bigger, more difficult task.
And then we'll go do it.
And that is an example of totally made up
perceived fake friction, right?
Like, smoking cigarettes doesn't actually make us
a better detective.
Like, it gives us maybe a false sense
of like plus one to our intellect.
But we may have convinced ourselves as, you know,
many people who are struggling with substances do
that we are inadequate or unable to perform a certain task
without this thing.
And so like, we look at that and say,
no, there's too much friction.
I can't do that.
It's too hard.
Having this substance will make it easier.
When really what we have done is just choose something
that's equally hard and we're reinforcing a bad pattern
of behavior.
And one that's pretty bad for us.
So that was a demonstration of the perceived kind of friction,
right?
Then this happened again,
nearing the end of our first day in Revishal,
in which my character had also been searching for ways
to drink alcohol.
And so we come to the end of the day
and we hadn't really found any opportunities
to do that besides like licking some alcohol
off of a table.
But so we're standing there at the end of the day
and we're talking to Gart, who is the manager
of the whirling and rags.
And we're asking him, like, can I buy a drink?
Look, I've had a long day, OK?
I spent most of it looking for cigarettes
and then I did a little bit of detective work
and it has tired me out, OK?
Now I need the other substance that I'm
depended on to sleep all of this off.
And that's when Gart tells us like, dude,
I'm not the bartender, OK?
I don't actually serve drinks here.
Find another way to get drunk.
You know what?
The impact of rejection is stronger
than the impulse to drink from my guy right now,
as a sorry cop.
I abandon, I'm going to abandon the desire to drink
because I am too ashamed to ask further.
He effectively made it more difficult for us to do this.
And in my mind, in simulating the character's perspective,
we decided that this was just too much work, right?
Like, we're already tired enough.
Who knows how much more time and effort and money
this was going to take to get some alcohol, right?
And so we gave up.
There was too much friction introduced to the process.
It would involve talking to people.
It would have involved budgeting.
It would have involved embarrassing ourselves even more.
And so with a lot of friction introduced to the process,
this slowed down and has the potential
to completely interrupt the problem behavior.
So I just find this whole thing fascinating
that the voice of a listen represents what is in real life,
which is just our good intentions to make healthy,
balanced decisions for ourselves.
And yet, typically the things that it wants us to do
require a lot of effort, a lot of deep behavioral changes.
And there are often a lot of barriers in between us
and doing them.
And here you have like other voices, which
have not so great intentions for us in competition
with volition.
And there's way less friction involved in those.
And so we chase those impulses even though we know we shouldn't.
That is just real life.
And I love disco elicin for this.
It's been one of my favorite parts of the game so far.
So what can you take away from this?
Well, consider a change that you've
been trying to make recently or a habit
that you're trying to break.
And ask yourself, what is the friction involved
in this process?
What is making it hard for me to make this good change?
And is that a real source of friction
or is it one that I'm kind of like perceiving?
Because at the end of the day, we
choose to ignore a volition even though we know it's there
and that it actually wants something better for us.
I genuinely think that making a change
is not always about working harder at something.
In fact, a lot of times I think
it's about making the process easier, right?
Simpler, streamlined, with the least amount of friction.
And you may find that over time, just like any other habit,
the more you train yourself to detect and resolve
the sources of friction in your life,
you actually find it a little easier
to listen to volition when it talks to you.
So that is why we ignore volition in real life.
I am very curious to hear what all of you think about this.
And if there's anything that you can think of that
is a source of friction in your life
that you may not even even really know is there.
So far, disco-alecium has been amazing at bringing
together real mental health with practical game mechanics.
And I find that really fun to talk about.
So I'm also curious if there's other games and other systems
in them that you think would be worthy of this kind of analysis
as well.
I don't know.
Maybe this could be like a series or something
where we talk about the crossover between game design
and mental health and how mechanics
can represent real cognitive structures
that we use and deal with every day.
So thank you for watching my video.
I hope you enjoyed it.
Yeah, let me know if you'd like to hear more of this kind
of discussion with other game mechanics.
And if you want to see more of where these ideas
are kind of taking shape and the discussions
we're having about them, we're currently
uploading a full Let's Play of disco-alecium
with lots of psychological analysis intermixed in that.
So subscribe if you want to catch those
as they release or other standalone analyses like this one.
Right now, these two are the friction between me
and finishing this video.
It's OK.
I love them.
So with that said, I will see you guys next time.
I'm going to go try to make some of my own good decisions
right now.