okay
hello
and welcome to
kind of like a special little interlude episode that
I wanted to put out before
the next Disco Elysium stream goes live
so this is something I may do from time to time
kind of like taking
a chunk of the analysis and putting it in its own video
sometimes because it takes me a while
to sort of collect my thoughts on things
and it doesn't always happen
like while we're live on stream
but also because
I can kind of already foresee that this
playthrough of Disco Elysium is going to be
quite long going at our usual pace
and I know it can be pretty hard to get into
a let's play
when it's like episode 30
or something and so if you weren't really
there for the beginning of it
it's kinda hard to hop in
that far down the line so
I thought it would be cool to kind of like do
like little chunks of our
character studies and
like analysis of the games
systems like how they represent different
parts of mental health like
just as their own separate videos
basically for the people who can't commit the time to watch
all of the let's play videos or
can't make it to the streams or that sort of thing
they can still enjoy
kind of the psychological breakdown parts of it so
that's what we're gonna be doing today
there's something that
I have to talk about basically like
I just couldn't really wait until
the next time I get on stream to talk about it
so that's what we're gonna do now
okay so there is something that Disco Elysium does
in its portrayal of a very specific aspect of mental health
that I have never seen portrayed this way
anywhere else
so one of the biggest challenges when talking about
anything related to mental health
whether depression mental illness addiction
is it can sometimes be really hard to explain
how can you want something
you could desperately want to not be depressed
you can desperately want to be sober
and yet sometimes our behaviors really don't agree with that desire
and how you explain that to someone that
you sitting there wondering like
all I want in the world is to stop using
but I just can't
and this is kind of
you know a mentality that I imagine like our
lead detective
having been in at some point
before he lost his memory
and at least in my playthrough
it's something he's still struggling with right
as he does whatever he can find a pack of cigarettes
and for me it comes down to this
we tend to have a very limited
way of talking about the subject of motivation
like why you actually do things why you want things
and this is where Disco Elysium comes into the picture
with these different aspects of the main character psyche who
seem to have different
motivations for him
and they influence you as the player to sort of
follow different paths
one motivation in terms of the authority voice will tell you like
you need to smack that kid right
don't let Cuno get one over you like that
and then at the same time
the voice coming from place of empathy might tell you
you know Cuno probably doesn't really have
anyone to look after him either
and one of the only ways that he has to express himself
because he doesn't have a sense of control at home
is to be vulgar
and he gets a reaction from people
may go home and find that
no one really pays attention to him
and this is how he gets that
this is his outlet
and so my character can have these two
very different perspectives
offering him a different kind of motivation
one that says slap the shit out of this
and the other that says actually
the two of you are probably not too dissimilar
you both feel this absence of connection to the world around you
and you're both trying to express
that longing for connection in different ways
so this is complicated right
it's not always easy to explain to people
why you can have two thoughts that don't necessarily agree
one that says I want to be sober
one that says
go get as high as you can right now right
so I'm going to pull this up here
I've got the skill system
these are all the different like voices
that you tend to hear in the characters dialogue
and this is the part
where Disco Elysium really gets something very right
about how to explain these
different sources of motivation
that don't always agree
and what it comes down to is that
we have this word
motivation
but I always come back to this idea that like
motivation by itself this word it doesn't really explain
what I just talked about
like the fact that you can have different sources of desires
that are not always in harmony with one another
to use this word is to say oh I didn't
do it because I wasn't motivated right
I didn't get up early enough
because I didn't have enough motivation to do it
I didn't go to the gym today
because I just didn't have the motivation for it
like it tries to explain
desire and action potential as like
a one to one relationship
my problem with this word is that it is very
one dimensional
so if we just think of like the start of the game right
at the very beginning the character wakes up and
like where is his center of motivation at
the first thing that we kind of learn about him
is that he is like not really aware of what's going on
like his primary motivation
as the player being the character is to like
figure out where you are and like
get a grasp on the world right
my first instinct when I loaded up the character
was like
look around at the things that you can find to like
wear his clothes like defend yourself right
and so like one of my motivations is safety
at the same time
he starts getting pulled into like
even more complicated motivations
like he tries to get the tie down from the fan
and here we have Inland Empire
telling us that like the tie is
not just your tie but it's also potentially your
long lost cosmic best friend right
and so
his motivation
shifts from safety to a sense of belonging
you reach up for the tie and your body is like
actually you can't reach for it
like that hurts too much right
and so it's kind of winding back to safety
me as the character
I was like all right
well this is a higher priority to me right now
than belonging
so I left the tie there
this does not mean that I'm not motivated to
have a sense of belonging
it just means that there is a priority structure that
interferes with itself sometimes
so I really don't think that the word itself motivation
really explains the psychodynamic issue at play here right
the better way that I try to explain this to my clients
is that we can be in different
mental states that are in competition with one another
so instead of talking about like
your lack of action potential as
you just didn't want to do something
like you didn't really want to be sober so you relapsed
instead we try to formulate it in terms of
we have different mental states
that are in competition with one another
so we have competing mental states
and this is where Disco Elysium really nails that idea
because here you have a mental state
called empathy that is telling you
you need to make this your priority
you need to connect to something
as you awake from the void of nothingness
and the only thing active in your brain is the reptilian side of you
like you need emotional grounding
you need to find something that anchors you to
not just like who you were
but who you are and what you feel right now
at the same time
there are parts of his body right his electrochemistry
all that stuff I talked about with like the
sympathetic and parasympathetic nervous system
that are rejecting what empathy commands of you
and so electrochemistry is like in competition with
empathy for your priority structure
then we have things like logic enter the picture right
the logical side of his brain is like okay
well search for things that
are a compromise to this
go find your shoe
you don't have to like reach up and grab the tie right
you can still satisfy safety by finding your shoes
perception comes into play and is like hey
why don't you check out the window right
and then the more you are sort of exerting yourself
like your endurance and your pain threshold
like they start vying for
territory over your decision making to say like
actually you don't really need that much Protection
like you're good enough with one shoe right
and so like your decision making
is not just a one track
sort of line of like are you motivated to do this
do you want to do it then you do it
instead the way disco elysium kind of
depicts this and this is like a very accurate way of trying to explain
the discord that happens in someone's mind
especially when they're
intoxicated or recovering from being intoxicated
is that you have all these different mental states that
are sort of vying for your attention
and are not always
in agreement with one another on what you should do
and so that causes a lot of inner tention
like I don't know about you
but when I feel overwhelmed by something
the main feeling that I have is one of avoidance
I don't want to feel like I
am not in control of myself for my own decision making
so I'm going to listen to the ones that are basically
like the most impulsive right
electrochemistry is basically like threatening me
that if I don't do what it wants
if I don't get the out of this environment
or if I don't like get a cigarette right now
that I'm going to die
right it's like convincing my body that
not smoking right now is the equivalent of like
being eaten alive by a predator
like that's what it's able to do because it's tapped
directly into my like spinal cord and
my entire like fighter flight response
and so you can imagine like
even for someone who is completely sober
and is just afflicted with the disease
of anxiety which we all are
this is a mess like we're all a total mess
and it's really hard to like sort out
what our priorities should be at any given moment
just when we're stressed
a lot of people
don't want to have to spend the time to reflect
and sort this out and like
learn how to develop like healthy communication
between these two systems and many systems
and so like what we often do is we resort to avoidance
like I'm just not gonna
participate in any of this
I'm just gonna go get fucked up instead right
I'm gonna listen to this one that tells me
if you don't
get on something to alleviate this stress right now
then the whole thing shuts down
so like right from the beginning
Disco elysium targets this
very complicated subject of motivation
and gives us a framework for understanding like
as you go throughout the world
as you start talking to people
and as you start making decisions as a player like
you are also going to be
in contention with what these different systems ask of you
for like my character
his very much built in
this category
and these have different names as well in the game
so these ones are intellect these are psyche
physique
and Motorics
and so these are like
we can even just explain it that way to say that
these are kind of like the four main categories of mental states
that are often vying for territory over your decision making
there's an intellectual side of you
that is telling you to make logical
clear decisions based on deduction and reasoning
but intellects
doesn't always agree with your psyche because
your psyche is the realm where your emotions live
like Inland Empire empathy authority volition
these are all like very emotional machines
that aren't always interested in solving problems
based on deduction and reasoning and observation
they are not as concerned
with the ideas
that perception might have in Motorix
about like how to solve a problem
they're going to rely more on emotional virtues
and so like they're gonna compete with each other
and
both of those systems are going to be competing with
physique because physique is basically managing like
the resources that the body has to
send off to these different corners right
physique is like
look you don't actually have the energy to go
get that tie down
even if it is your best friend
and Motorix
may be interfering with aspects of intellect
by saying like hey you
may perceive
lots of details you can tell there is something here
but you can't necessarily deduce
the best way to deal with it
that's kind of my character right like
he's he's able to like pass these really hard
perception rolls
but there's really not a lot of follow through with it
so as I was playing the game I just found this skill system amazing
not only as like a parallel to real discussions
that I have with people all the time about
like the complicated nature of motivation
and that motivation is not
really even the subject that we're talking about
we're talking about competition between
several mental states that you can occupy all at the same time
and that want different things from you
but this also works extremely well as a narrative device
as a storytelling device
and as a game mechanic
because these are the things that
as the player you're interfacing with
when I'm like yeah well I'm specked into psyche
and so I'm probably gonna be more biased to follow what
Inland Empire is telling me I should focus on
versus like something that my physique side is telling me
and really like using this system to
explain character motivations
doesn't just apply to the detective
think about Kim for a second all right Kim
he's our best boy right now
Kim
from the moment we meet him
has a complicated array of motivations as we do
and he is way more stable than we are presumably
so I can imagine for Kim
that he's got a lot of different mental states
that are in competition with one another as well
something that we learn
this might actually be in the second recording
I can't remember
but something we learn about him is that like
he does care about his work
like he cares a lot about being a good detective like doing things the right way
he has a lot of dignity and integrity and respect for himself
but at the same time
还请略作宽容，观察主播对金的认知变化。
I think he also presents as someone willing to bend his morals
if he knows he can accomplish
还请略作宽容，观察主播对金的认知变化。
something he is trying to do right
because he also has this like
还请略作宽容，观察主播对金的认知变化。
cultural side to him right
when we meet the racist lorry driver
right like we see
Kim himself
get in touch with some of these more like
commanding mental states that
sort of break him from the facade of someone who is always
cool and calm and collected
and he confronts this gentleman and like we see that
you know I think Kim would be
willing to compromise on some things
if he knew that it would satisfy like his cultural desires right
so he's got two competing mental states there
just being around us is a competition between
his structured world and the
complete chaos that our character presents right
at the same time I think he also finds us useful
as someone he can wield to accomplish this
it's not just about competition between mental states
it's also about like
where do you start justifying what you compromise
and somewhere along the way I really think that
he does compromise logic and maybe his empathy and some of his volition
like he compromises those things
to allow us to do our thing
in some ways maybe because he
he can relate to us
I think there's maybe a part of him that
is a little bit like
shackled by his structured way of being
and being around the detective vicariously he gets to experience
his own inner chaos
we are the conduit for him exploring
what would happen if I don't compete
and I don't try to win out
and I don't try to learn to communicate healthily
between any of these systems
what if I just embrace chaos and
follow whatever impulse comes to me right like
I don't think he can let himself do that and so
he allows the detective to do that right
that's what makes Detective Costeau and
Kim great foils for each other right
foil is
not necessarily a character who is
the opposite of another character
but it's someone whose qualities like
when we see how structured and mannered
and let's say by the book that Kim is
we see him express those qualities
it creates a major contrast
with our own character
and amplifies our awareness of these qualities
like if you put two people who are like Kim next to each other
we don't necessarily notice
how important these things are
for keeping his whole worldview intact
but the second you put him next to the detective
or someone like * Cuno
that's where the contrast really comes through
and we start to see where those compromises happen
because at least in my play through
I got Kim to try to shoot down the body right
this is not something that fits with this worldview that we
normally might associate with him with
I think somewhere in the mix we got to see what it was like
when Kim wasn't able to stifle the competition between
some of his own more pressing mental states
and right down here this mental state lost to
any number of these that sort of represent pride
and that's what makes them as a dynamic
no matter what kind of play through I imagine you're having
so fun and so unique to watch is because like
you are the character
who is not really trying to stop these
mental states from having fierce competition
and you are literally just letting whichever one is strongest  drive view
especially because as the player
like you want to explore and exhaust as many
options as you can to get the best outcome
like in trying to play optimally as a character
we end up allowing our
character that we're playing to be totally
disregulated and unpredictable
we can't play as someone necessarily like Kim
and get the most optimal result
because it very rarely takes sort of like
allowing this competition between the mental states to
resolve itself in a neat and structured and orderly way
so that's one of the
ideas that I was having as I was playing through
just like the first couple hours of disco elysium
like I said this is something that is not super easy to explain to people
in clinical practice sometimes
other than to say that like
first we're gonna try to demonstrate that motivation is not  really
it's not sufficient enough of an idea to explain
why behaviors that we don't want continue
if this is like my 20th time trying to get sober and I'm still relapsing
it's something that her(his) main character is probably still dealing with
like he doesn't want to have headaches
he doesn't want to feel like he hates himself
he doesn't want to be confused about who he is
or maybe he does
right I guess we're gonna find out but
if we assume good intentions
if we even just assume that getting what he wants
even if it's like really simple and primal the things that he wants
if that requires being in
good health and having good perception reaction speed
in you know having a healthy physical instrument
a healthy body
if that requires it then you
you should be invested in
you know not killing yourself
moment to moment by like
desperately hounding everyone you see for a pack of sigis right
but that's what he does anyways
that's what my character is doing
because this is not as simple as well
if you just want it bad enough
you would work harder on it
I think that that's the big myth in any sort of mental health
it's like if you just wanted to be happy enough
you just you would find a way to do it
it's not that simple right
that is a very one dimensional way of thinking about things
wanting something is not enough
to resolve the inner sort of turmoil that happens when
you have different priority structures all vying for
your attention and for your decision making power
so that brings me to like
this is a problem
how do you actually work on it
what would I do with
let's say myself the detective or someone like Kim
maybe even more appropriately because
feel like he just is more ready to be in therapy than the detective
I think that guy needs like serious detoxing before
like any level of talk therapy would even be effective with him
but one of the approaches that I find very useful
in working on situations like this
is an approach called internal family systems it's also called IFS
so internal family systems is a type of therapy in which
the framework you're using is that
we consider the inner parts of ourselves to be like
a close family of individuals right and so
we would use the terminology of parts to describe
a part of you that's angry
a part of you that wants to still use a part of you that wants to be sober
a part of you that wants to smack Cuno in the face
and a part of you that wants to give him
a healthy home to return to right
like there are disparate parts of ourselves that in
the same way that I was talking about here
may not always agree with each other and
so the goal of IFS therapy is to learn how to like
develop lines of communication between these things
and so now I would imagine like the character
saying something like well
you know
that part of me
feels like it's never quite in control right there's a
there's a sense of authority that's missing right
the the part of me that's angry struggles the most with authority
and you could attach those two
you know ideas to each other
you could say okay well what about the part of you that
can sort of understand
where Cuno is coming from and that
his expression of vulgarity is his way of
like controlling his own competing mental states
and you may be able to connect that part of yourself with
you know a source of empathy
and so we might actually engage in that
process by saying like okay well
what would a conversation
between these two parts look like
where do you think there is some common ground
between these two parts that that don't agree right
so IFS is something I can imagine being pretty useful here
it's not something I'm super specialized in
but I do find the framework of discussing the self as different parts
that actually all have the potential to want the same thing
and sort of
being the pursuit of like finding what that thing is
and working to make this a common shared goal within yourself
and so it's something that I think could really benefit
these two gentlemen in particular
so that's a little bit of a breakdown on
kind of my thoughts so far on
one of the very interesting ways that Disco Elysium portrays mental health
I genuinely think that like the way
it has integrated these ideas as a
like narrative dialogue skill system is
absolutely ingenious and
really gives us like a framework for discussing something that
is not always easy to grasp by the person
who isn't necessarily sure about why
they feel like they're being pulled in these different directions
and like I said
this is a subject that is relevant to not just addiction
but is relevant to depression any kind of mental illness
or even just like a normal healthy person who
can have competition between two mental states
one that tells you it's time to get up for work
and the other that's like actually go back to bed
I have that competition every single day of my life
and boy is it a struggle
so I hope you enjoyed this little vignette analysis
like I said
I think this would be a cool way to sort of engage
with people who may not be able to commit to
watching all of the let's plays either live or in the vods
because you know they can be quite long uploads after all
so let me know what you think about this format
if you enjoyed it
it's great to see so many new people
kind of join in the community
and getting interested in this stuff
I'm really happy to have you here
and I'm excited to do more of this kind of thing
very soon
so that said next episode is coming
shortly after this one and
we'll see you there bye
do you have any competing mental state
that you want to share with the class
no
she's perfect as she is
bye