okay let's talk about bad decisions
so if you're like me you've been there
it's the end of the day or the morning
you plan a solid day for yourself
you'll be disciplined
you'll come home from work
you'll run errands
you'll treat yourself well
you'll make a healthy meal
you'll go to the gym
you'll exercise
then you'll read a book
you'll advance your life
this is your volition
it leads to good decisions
but this doesn't always work
sometimes you're undisciplined
errands are incomplete
you skip the gym
you order unhealthy takeout
you watch a show instead
you haven't advanced your life
what is happening
why ignore your volition
it could be many things
a mental health diagnosis amplifies it
this happens often
it happens to me
I'll share a framework
it explains why this happens
it shows what to do
this problem arises in my work
I've seen it clearly demonstrated
it has a unique role in games
there's a reason we don't follow volition
it's psychological friction
friction opposes behavioral change
regular friction is like this
on ice there's little friction
on concrete there's more friction