hello and welcome to another episode
it's my therapist plays disco elysium analysis
this time I wanted to share something
I learned about a character in the game
I also learned about myself
this is during the uploading of this series
just for context if you're just joining
I'm playing through the game
it's from a therapist's perspective
I provide commentary on mental health
it's depicted in the game
there's a lot more going on
but I'm not the person to comment
I can't comment on complicated political stuff
one important dynamic is with your partner
that's kim kitsuragi
as the player we're more aware of kim's qualities
my character the detective is not
I've been exploring the subject
it's someone coming from a background of trauma
we still don't know a lot about rafael
his issues with authority and relationships
his struggles with substance abuse indicate trauma
I've been approaching dialogue with kim
we have an initial impression of someone
we may want to trust them
if we have trust issues we may test it
we may see where the real boundaries are
my character's trying to see
does kim stick around because he needs me
or are his qualities earnest and trustworthy
are those things going to last
we make ourselves very difficult to be around
I'm going to ask him
I want to impress him
I want him to think I'm cool
I'm not a f * * * ing mess
I've been demonstrating
some close relationships are tested
they outlast the period of testing
if I push this person will they stick with me
the lieutenant bears his nose in his notebook
there's another thing I'm unsure about kim
she gave an honest reflection
she empathized with me
kim showed me disappointment and mistrust