okay hello and welcome
it's a special interlude episode
I wanted to put it out before the next stream
so this I may do from time to time
taking a chunk of the analysis
putting it in its own video
sometimes it takes a while
to collect my thoughts on things
it doesn't always happen live
but also I foresee this playthrough
being quite long at our usual pace
it can be hard to get into a let's play
especially at episode 30 or something
it's hard to hop in that far down
so I thought it'd be cool
to do little chunks of character studies
analysis of the game's systems
how they represent mental health
as separate videos
basically for people who can't commit
the time to watch all the let's play videos
they can still enjoy this breakdown
so that's what we're doing today
I have to talk about something
I couldn't wait until the next stream
so that's what we're doing now
disco elysium portrays a specific aspect
of mental health I've never seen portrayed this way
one of the biggest challenges is explaining
how you can want something
you could desperately want to not be depressed
you can desperately want to be sober
our behaviors don't agree with that desire
how do you explain that to someone
they want to stop using but can't
this is a mentality our lead detective had
before he lost his memory
he's still struggling with it
as he finds cigarettes
it comes down to this
we have a limited way of talking about motivation
why you do things why you want things
disco elysium comes into the picture
with different aspects of the main character's psyche
they have different motivations
they influence you to follow different paths
one motivation will tell you to smack that kid