hello and welcome back to my therapist plays
disco elisium analysis series
okay I'm really excited about today's episode
we're finally getting into our first encounter
with the union boss everart claire
and kind of breaking down lots of different
psychological angles on power dynamics
we have a lot to share today
on real techniques that I actually use
in my practice as a therapist
to navigate difficult conversations
with people who don't want to talk to you
or are in some sort of power struggle
how do you get that person opening up
about things
we're going to use some of those techniques
on mr claire
by the end of this episode we're going to learn
a little bit more about ourselves
and what kind of comp we are
yes we're finally getting our copo type
I'm sure very few of you will be surprised
so I'm excited to share this one
let's dive in
okay so I have an objective
I have the objective to progress this game's storyline
like I do want to mention why I am going
about playing this game this way
because I do think it's relevant
when you see my character do things
like just totally give up on pursuing
the narrative to try to find cigarettes
for example
this is a roleplay
so sometimes I'm going to be speaking
as like brady the therapist
sometimes I'm going to be speaking
as like brady the degenerate
who is using this as a kind of escapism
from my very serious real life
this is where I get to give me a goofball
and sometimes I'm going to like speak
from the voice of my character
and just like say random nonsense garbage
that I think he would say or think
and one of the things that is really important
about this character specifically
because he is someone representing the struggle
of addiction is how like we have all kinds
of priority structures in our mind
like there's the whole just basic needs
hierarchy of like you need food
you need water
you need rest
and only once those things are satisfied
can you really focus on like higher order things
like you know your self - esteem
and your self - worth and the balance of health
and your relationships and those sorts of things
the problem with addiction is that your body
has become dependent on a chemical
one that's harmful to you
so it completely hijacks what should be
a normal set of priorities