hello and welcome back to our therapist plays disco elicium
let's play if you're new here
hello my name is brady
I'm a therapist
we're doing a long - form psychoanalysis
of our main character and all the people
that we meet in our twisted weird journey
through revishol in disco elicium
so on today's episode we're getting deeper
into the analysis and targeting our companion kim
who in my playthrough we don't have a trusting relationship with yet
and kind of getting into the psychology of trust
what does it mean to want to trust someone
but not be sure if you can yet
how does someone with prior trauma evaluate trust
whether someone who promises to be there is trustworthy
so today I'm giving you psychological theory
and how I'd address this in practice as a therapist
so that said let's continue
okay so what do I need to do
I need to ask
I need to solve this murder
the murder is the lowest priority
I genuinely believe that as this character the murder is a vehicle
to discover more about who I was
in that process reckoning with the idea
that I may have done something to myself
to try to forget that person
I'm spending a lot of time trying to figure that out
I could go do the autopsy
I have the gloves and the form
maybe I should do that
I'm just collecting tasks
I kind of want to go see the body
let's do the notch - ops zero quick
I have all the ingredients
see what happens
if you don't tell us something provide us information
the rotting man lies on his side
his eyes look straight through you
the belt is still around his neck
his body is supine and open to intrusion
let's do that
turn it