hello and welcome back to my therapist
plays disco elisium analysis series
on today's episode we're going to address something
it's unavoidable in a game like this
which is what are some crossovers
between politics and mental health
and some personal struggles I have
integrating those two subjects
I'm sure there will be discussion
in the comments this is all recorded previously
I think I'm going to make a dedicated video
compiling my thoughts a little more
to get an early look at where my stomach's going
aside from that we have a special moment
we're going to reach the end of our first day
as a detective it's taken us a while
we're going to take another look
at how kim and i's relationship has been developing
over this very challenging day
see if there's some things we've become close on
so all that's coming up
I'm excited to get into it
let's do it
alrighty we are going to talk to kim
we should think about calling it today maybe
the nights are still miserably cold
this time of year
I haven't paid the cafeteria manager for the damages yet
should take care of that then
I don't have the money
I'm stuck to him anyway
an office of the rcm shouldn't be sleeping in the street
we'll figure something out
though he finds this situation frustrating
he is doing his best to not make you feel worse
than you already do
I respect that kim
he's kim is one of a lot of points with me
in these chapters of our stream
okay let's see if we can reason with this gentleman
can I help you
but I don't have another option here
yes have you got it
can we come to some sort of arrangement
does that arrangement include you paying me
what we already agreed you owe me
kim is about to say something
let him
let's do that
I understand your predicament as the manager
however I feel I must remind you
that we are here to conduct an important investigation
that also affects your business
that's a good point
put the squeeze on him
give me for saying this but your colleagues
seem more committed to drinking and
he stops me in sentence
he shrinks back a bit
under the lieutenant - severge's
I mean no effects
it's really nothing personal
I just have to protect the interests
of this establishment
no kiddie kiddie