okay hello and welcome to the beginning
of a special playthrough of a game
that I have been talking about
with my community to play
for a very long time
it is disco elysium
if you are discovering the channel
based on this which is likely
my name is brady
I'm a therapist
we are going to be doing a long form analysis
of the game that we're going to play
we'll probably play out the games
in the future as well
and we tend to ask questions
like okay so
let's imagine this character was my client
what sort of things do I think
that they would be dealing with
what sort of approach would I use
to help them
that's kind of what we're getting into
and I also myself am interested
in creative writing
I'm an aspiring writer
I have imposter syndrome
I don't know if I'd call myself an author
I did write a science fiction novel
a couple years ago
it's finished I didn't publish it
I don't know if I will
it's so old
it would need a full rewrite
I still keep telling myself to rewrite it
or write something new
that kind of parallels disco elysium
this is not your average game writing
there's a big focus on prose
from what I can tell
I don't know anything about the story
I don't know anything about the setting
it has a lot of acclaim
for its creative aspects
for its prosaic dialogue and narration
and that it's a crpg
I like crpgs
I'm a fan of baldur's gate
and divinity series
I played original sin a couple years ago
fantastic game
I'm currently playing through baldur's gate 3
I really enjoyed pillars of eternity
so those kinds of games I'm really into
and we have tried to play games on stream
but discussing things from a therapeutic perspective
they can go quite long
so I'm going to keep my thoughts focused
and concise
but yeah I hope you enjoy what you see
we're going to be uploading this periodically
and if you want to check out the stream
see it live
we're welcome to do so as well
so yeah let's do it
let's get into it
let's go I'm ready
oh there it is
got my little brady box
hey brady I haven't seen you live
in quite a while
looking forward to you playing