hello and welcome to my therapist plays disco elicium analysis series
so on today's episode I'm very excited
we are finally getting to use one of my favorite frameworks
this is something I use in therapy
it's an incredible way to explore patterns of psychology
it's also a way to explore patterns of behavior
we uncover what drives the complexes we see
these complexes play out in harry's thoughts and actions
the reason we're doing that now is this:
we are starting to learn more about ourselves
we're learning more about our past
we'll take another look at that ledger
what do we think about the person we used to be
all that's coming up so let's jump back in
oh there it is
we are back
I'm so excited
we are back in the game now
I wanted to say this:
the community around this game amazes me
this playthrough continues to amaze me
last episode was a lot of politics talk
I was anxious about talking about politics
I have been encouraged by the response
I don't know if I'll get fully political
I will try not to avoid it in the game
I won't let it divert the game
I want to talk about mental health
there are interesting avenues in the narrative
I will say this:
this game is wonderfully designed
the main character has a real backstory
he's not a blank slate
he has his own backstory
it allows you to have your own beliefs
the character will have the same behavioral patterns
imagine brady as the detective
imagine what you know about me
how I'd solve a murder would be exactly like this
I'd spend crazy amounts of time on things
you just wouldn't like you