hello and welcome back to my therapist
plays disco elicium analysis series
so on today's episode we are delving deeper
into the psychology of our main character
this case gets more complicated
so does our relationship with ourselves
we're also going to start discovering more
about who we were and finding that
we are not so happy with that person
before we had our amnesia
and woke up as the person we are today
so what does it mean to be faced
with some of those challenges
do we avoid them and try to shut them out
or do we look for healthy ways
to integrate them and move forward
but we also do get into major confrontation
we're going to face what it is like
when we go up against an individual
named measurehead who stands between us
and our next objective in solving the case
so all that is coming up in today's episode
and perhaps our first moments of genuine trust
starting to build between ourselves and our partner kip
I'm excited to continue this journey with all of you
so let's jump in
hey there's a big gentleman
scared
maybe this is the gentleman who was asking
about our case is a large lead
what's going on here
the broad shoulder alpha male turns to you
he's a full head taller than everybody else here
you hear to fuck with us
beat the honest worker down
why should I hear the fight for a cause
stripes usually have problems with people
who have causes
okay then I think I think no
I want to be on your team friend
good
we're fighting for a cause here
right to work
besides we're not that different
it helps if people see us talking
cops and strikebreakers together
shows our days are on our side
builds confidence
I like his perspective
I agree
I think it's also kind of a power play
that I'm like grinding the flashlight
and everybody's face because it makes them feel
like I'm really targeting them
which is good for my interrogation
what kind of trials are we talking about
well I don't want to politically align with him
but I want to be on his team