okay hello and welcome back
to our playthrough of disco elysium
we just finished the first chunk
of the game starting our character
yeah just figuring out who he is
in this wild disgusting world
and how wild and disgusting are we
going to be to meet the world
so I've decided that the character profile
we're going with is like x
or failed therapist turned dirty cop
I tried to be a therapist
but I found it too easy to manipulate people
the more I learned about people
the more I couldn't help exploiting that
so I became a cop instead
where I can hide behind a moral justification
for getting information from people
I can code that as a good thing
for me and them; I'm protecting them
by figuring out their dark secrets
so that's kind of where we're at
let's continue and keep working
on this crime
literally just came back at the perfect time
hell yeah let's look and go
okay let's check out the crime scene
get some cash lying around
never gonna let that go to waste
some more magnesium
we're gonna need to stock up
this mechanism has been oxidating for years
the kids ' ladder is climbable
not too much interesting going on
let's check out the body
with bulging white eyes
the face does not look human
it's swollen and ready to burst
his lips are fish - like
and his tongue like a ball gag
okay it's pretty gruesome
you seem to be holding your breath
the cargo belt twists his neck
at an unnatural angle
the body below appears stiff
it's letting out an ungodly rot
the smell seeps in
even through your clenched nostrils
legendary let go of your nose
without throwing up
that's 17 %
has not steered me wrong yet
oh it looks like my camera is frozen