hello and welcome back to my therapist plays disco
elicium analysis series
so on today's episode we're getting deeper
into our different character studies
we're breaking down the psychological dynamics
in their dialogue and their relationships
this represents mental health
I focus on two characters
that we meet on our journey
through revisho
I give my deepest psychoanalytical impressions
maybe my most unhinged character analysis
it discusses important things
about how the game depicts its world building
what characters do we need to look at
if we look at the shape of their mental health
this will tell us a lot
about living in this environment
with these political systems and social tensions
what is the result on the people
there's a lot to get into
I'm excited to share
let's jump back in
okay let's continue
we were investigating our relationship with kim
I guess there's a section I missed
ah cool
I see what you mean
let's check out inland empire
that's our main skill
I find it very interesting
this was the primary skill I chose
in the last stream I disagreed with its intrusions
it's cool for dreamers paranatural investigators
and mental creators
I am an investigator and a mental creator
I make stuff in my brain
it's better than reality
empathy is cool for judges
interviewers and interrogators
that's me as well
volition is cool for sane people
well - adjusted cops the non - suicidal
authority is cool for leaders
experts of psychological warfare and respect junkies
this is cool for cops
cop - efficient autos and pretend cops
that last one is us the pretend cop