okay hello and welcome back
to our therapist plays disco elicium
let's play series
if you are new here hello
welcome my name is brady
I'm a therapist
we are doing a long - form psychoanalysis
of the main character and his companions
and all the people we meet
on our journey through revigel
so in today's episode we're going to talk
about our main character's reflections
on his own self - identity
as we start to unpack things
that he is remembering about his past
psychologically what does it mean
to integrate a past version of yourself
who you may not have positive feelings about
into the identity you're building today
also we're going to see
if we could take another shot
with guna
so let's dive in
now one thing is a hanging thread
I want to return to my bedroom
while I'm here
we're playing the game like reading
some psychological class material
yeah if you're new to the euro brady experience
this is one part entertainment
one part master's level psychology lecture
one part my own self - therapy
read the problem part
let's do that
let's rewind
let's trace your drunken steps back home
jump across the raised channel bridge
southwest of here
fall over get up
get off the asphalt in 20 minutes
shuffle your feet through courtyards
scaring little children
that checks out
go under the great raised motor tract
the 881 until you reach the domain
eminol in north jamrock
the streets are frozen this time of year
caked with ice
walk down main to tradition
there's a side alley there
in your footprints in the mud
okay there's something there
there is a past for me
okay what is this
kim also tries not to look
at the pile of viscera on the carpet
or the weird suitcase on the hat rack
or the pot plant dying in the corner
but it's all too morbid to ignore
oh that's true
this is the first time
I've brought kim into the environment
maybe in a subconscious way
I'm trying to understand
how much can I destroy my own image
to him before I come to the conclusion
that he's not going to abandon me
maybe if I show him something intimate