okay hello and also welcome
it's great to be back on stream
continuing our disco elicium playthrough
if you're just joining us which is a good chance that you are this is still at the beginning
it's the beginning of our little playthrough
what we're doing is playing through it
it's a mix of roleplay a mix of psychoanalysis
I'm brady I'm a therapist
I'm doing psychoanalysis on the characters
I'm linking that to the game design
it represents mental health
this game is in another league
I already did a video about the skill system
it represents motivation and psychological priority
we're going to get pretty deep with this
the last two streams I've been figuring out the game
I've had some time to collect thoughts
I'll be talking about the characters and their dynamics
my character shows avoidance and confrontation
he's not making the best decisions
I'm doing a mix of my own head canon in roleplay
I'm not trying to play the game the best way
I'm trying to make this a fun playthrough
we're not going to see every part of the game
we're not going to see every dialogue tree
that's okay
it's been great to get recommendations
my character has just fallen into failing upwards
he's passing some of the early skill checks
some comments said I skipped tutorials
that makes sense because I kind of feel lost
but that's okay
we're discovering it as we go
that makes for interesting playthrough dynamics
I'm fascinated by how well the game responded
it's completely fine that I skipped certain things
it's fine that I don't know how to play it well
I haven't reached a roadblock
the game is happy to let me move on
it lets me fail my way through everything
that's kind of life isn't it
so with that said