hello and welcome to my therapist
plays disco elicium analysis series
on today's episode we are meeting
what has become another favorite character
that we've met so far
so we're gonna be talking
a lot with a net and her mother
today learning more about the economic reality
of being a child who has to work
out in the cold all day
and in that dialogue we're also gonna be
continuing to build our own character profile
sort of continuing the analysis
using the jahari window
that we started in the last episode
there's a lot of emotions to dig into
and discuss in today's episode
including some that may come up
when we finally face ourselves
so that's where we're at
I'm excited to continue
so let's jump back in
okay what shall we do next
I guess we can go enter the green
the door behind the green house
let's go do that
it's in the yard basement door
is that back there
yeah it's more useful on counseling
what is this girl up to
it's been a while since we've checked in
she is way too positive
oh it's snowing
what is this crime
it's about murders or burglaries
or things like that and the work
of a policeman or a private detective
who's trying to solve a crime
and catch the criminals
I need to know what crime is
it's that bad pointy red
crime is what we were solving
before this conversation began
why would anyone want to read a crime
they get to imagine dangerous things
and it's kind of like a puzzle
where you can guess who the criminal is
or how the good guys are going to catch him
I'm a policeman myself by the way
I don't look much like a policeman
I know
well what does a cop look like that
she points to a book cover
on which you can see strapping
vesparteen officer
he stems grinly over the body
of a dead woman
you know nobody actually looks
like the guy in the picture
it's not your body that's important
in police work
it's your head