hello and welcome back to my therapist
plays disco elicium analysis series
in today's episode we are going to be taking
a very thorough look at how disco elicium portrays
intrusive thinking when electrochemistry starts
giving us thoughts and they are very much opposed
to the thoughts of volition
and how this actually very accurately represents
some of our very real thinking patterns
so we are going to be using actual theory
to break this down using the cognitive model
how actual cognitive behavioral therapy works
and how we might apply it to a situation
that our detective finds himself in
with his own intrusive thinking
this one is going to be quite in depth
so I am excited to get into it and start it
alright so what we need to do now is figure out
where to go
this door he wants me to bust down
oh there is an end of day deep brief
kim can answer any lingering questions
you may have about the case in the rcm
join him in the whirling and rags balcony after 10
so what time is it
it is almost 10 so we have a little bit of time
before we can do that
do we have enough money to pay back mr guards
do we have enough
do we have
oh he has a ton of trash
let's go turn in the trash
let's pay a visit to the best character
in this entire game
ritter girl
let's see what she is up to
and let's get some money
yeah we are not accepting that bribe
fuck that guy
I don't care
we will solve our many problems
through rigorous environmentalism
I believe I am supposed to talk to this gentleman first
though
let's see what he has got to say
what is nice and not