hello and welcome to my therapist
plays disco lesium analysis series
so on today's episode the plot
we will see if we can establish authority
with tidus the union boss
we're gonna see if we can get closer
to a confession from him
on who was involved with the murder
in marche nays
and on the analysis side
we're taking a deep dive
into the rigorous self - critique thought
now that we finally internalize this
it opens the door for discussion
on harry's sense of self
is he actually a good person
does he think it's possible to become one
this is heavier on the analysis
but it's exciting to peel back layers
of our character
let's jump in
any predictions on where the story will go
or who's the killer
I had the idea that we would be involved
in the killing because we are uninitiated
to our own past
I don't think we did it
I have the suspicion that the dock workers
are a red herring
I just don't buy it
that's what we're leading
but I could be wrong
I am notoriously bad at predicting the plot
of anything as you've probably noticed
but when politics or the plot
are part of the dialogue
my brain condenses down
I've had to do this before
okay what is happening here
my brain is equipped for character analysis
when I'm watching something
I'm not thinking about the plot
I'm not like watching shutter island
and wondering what's gonna happen next
my brain accepts whatever happens
but I'm thinking about what the character feels
how whatever happens will change their worldview
that's where my mind is focused
I just accept the plot
it doesn't matter that much to me
the sequence of things happening
unless it's so egregious
what if it was lena
I refuse to accept that lena
is too kindhearted and good - natured
for her to be involved in that
it's funny therapists often struggle
with predicting stuff or telling if someone is lying
well that's true because